<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2015-04-29T21:24:57Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <subcommittees />
          <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <billNumber>1138</billNumber>
    <updateDate>2016-11-02T23:26:32Z</updateDate>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
    </policyArea>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2015-04-29T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Reclassification to Ensure Smarter and Equal Treatment Act of 2015 or the RESET Act</strong></p> <p> Amends the Controlled Substances Act (CSA) to reduce penalties (to not greater than a one-year term of imprisonment and/or a $1,000 fine) for simple possession of a controlled substance by a person who has one or more prior convictions for a controlled substance offense. </p> <p>Repeals a provision providing for up to three years' imprisonment for the possession of flunitrazepam. Revises penalties for possession of drugs classified as date rape drugs after a prior drug-related conviction.</p> <p>Reduces the maximum term of imprisonment (to one year) for the sale, use of the mails to transport, or importation or exportation of drug paraphernalia.</p> <p>Eliminates provisions of the CSA and the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act that apply the same penalties applicable to offenses involving a specified amount of a substance containing cocaine to offenses involving a lesser amount of a substance containing cocaine base.</p> <p>Amends the CSA to provide that in determining the weight of a controlled substance or mixture of controlled substances that is in a compound with a food product for purposes of provisions concerning controlled substance offenses, the weight of the food product shall not be included.</p> <p>Makes this Act applicable to any offense committed before its enactment, if a sentence for the offense has not been imposed as of such enactment date. Provides for the reduction of the term of imprisonment of a defendant who was convicted and sentenced before such date for an offense for which the penalty is amended by this Act.</p> <p>Directs the Sentencing Commission to review and, if appropriate, amend the federal sentencing guidelines and policy statements applicable to any person convicted of an offense affected by this Act.</p> <p>Establishes within the Department of Justice the Safe Neighborhoods and Schools Fund, which (subject to specified limitations) shall be disbursed as follows by August 15 of each fiscal year beginning in 2016:</p> <ul> <li>15% to the Department of Education to administer a grant program to public agencies aimed at improving outcomes for public school pupils in kindergarten and grades 1 to 12 by reducing truancy and supporting students who are at risk of dropping out or are victims of crime;</li> <li>10% to the Federal Crime Victim Assistance Fund to make grants to trauma recovery centers to provide services to victims of crime;</li> <li>25% to Federal Reentry/Drug Court programs to administer a grant program to public agencies aimed at supporting mental health treatment, substance abuse treatment, and diversion programs for people in the criminal justice system; and </li> <li>50% to the General Treasury in order to pay down the national debt. </li> </ul>]]></text>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-07-21T15:39:25Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2015-04-29</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <title>RESET Act</title>
    <laws />
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2173</lisID>
          <bioguideId>S001194</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
        <middleName />
        <fullName>Sen. Schatz, Brian [D-HI]</fullName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <firstName>Brian</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <state>HI</state>
        <bioguideId>S001194</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-04-29</sponsorshipDate>
        <party>D</party>
        <lastName>Schatz</lastName>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <recordedVotes />
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <type>HR</type>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <number>2153</number>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-11-16</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>RESET Act</latestTitle>
      </item>
      <item>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <type>HR</type>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <number>1255</number>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-03-31</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>Fairness in Cocaine Sentencing Act of 2015</latestTitle>
      </item>
      <item>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <type>S</type>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <number>1610</number>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-06-18</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. (Sponsor introductory remarks on measure: CR S4302)</text>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>BALTIMORE Act</latestTitle>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-04-29</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
          <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2015-04-29</actionDate>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <notes />
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2015-04-29</actionDate>
      <links />
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <introducedDate>2015-04-29</introducedDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Paul, Rand [R-KY]</fullName>
        <firstName>Rand</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>P000603</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8308</gpoId>
          <lisID>2082</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>P000603</bioguideId>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>KY</state>
        <lastName>Paul</lastName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Budget deficits and national debt</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Crime victims</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Criminal procedure and sentencing</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Drug trafficking and controlled substances</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Drug, alcohol, tobacco use</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Education programs funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Elementary and secondary education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health programs administration and funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Law enforcement administration and funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Mental health</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>U.S. Sentencing Commission</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <committeeReports />
    <amendments />
    <createDate>2015-04-30T09:17:48Z</createDate>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>RESET Act</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>Reclassification to Ensure Smarter and Equal Treatment Act of 2015</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>A bill to reclassify certain low-level felonies as misdemeanors, to eliminate the increased penalties for cocaine offenses where the cocaine involved is cocaine base, to reinvest in our communities, and for other purposes.</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>RESET Act</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
      </item>
    </titles>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

