<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. AMODEI:H.R. 2324.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:The constitutional authority of Congress to enact thislegislation is provided by Article I, Section 8 of the UnitedStates Constitution, specifically clause 1 (relating toproviding for the general welfare of the United States) andclause 18 (relating to the power to make all laws necessaryand proper for carrying out the powers vested in Congress),and Article IV, Section 3, Clause 2 (relating to the power ofCongress to dispose of and make all needful rules andregulations respecting the territory or other propertybelonging to the United States).[Page H3213]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>A000369</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2090</lisID>
          <gpoId>8366</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <district>2</district>
        <byRequestType />
        <fullName>Rep. Amodei, Mark E. [R-NV-2]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <state>NV</state>
        <bioguideId>A000369</bioguideId>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <party>R</party>
        <lastName>Amodei</lastName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <committeeReports />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Small Lands Tracts Conveyance Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>To provide for the conveyance of small parcels of National Forest System land and small parcels of public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management to private landowners, State, county, and local governments, or Indian tribes whose lands share a boundary with the National Forest System land or public lands, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Small Lands Tracts Conveyance Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <laws />
    <createDate>2015-05-15T12:51:45Z</createDate>
    <recordedVotes />
    <billNumber>2324</billNumber>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <name>Conservation and Forestry Subcommittee</name>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2015-06-08T15:32:25Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
              <systemCode>hsag15</systemCode>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Agriculture Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsag00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2015-05-14T14:01:10Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
        <item>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <name>Federal Lands Subcommittee</name>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2015-06-04T19:57:02Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
              <systemCode>hsii10</systemCode>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2015-05-14T14:01:05Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills />
    <updateDate>2016-11-02T22:07:14Z</updateDate>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2015-05-14</actionDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-07-23T16:52:47Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Small Lands Tracts Conveyance Act</b></p> <p> Requires the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) for a state (respecting certain public lands) or the Forest Service (respecting certain National Forest System lands) to select an eligible federal lands parcel for conveyance: (1) in response to a request by an adjacent landholder (any holder of non-federal land that shares one or more boundaries with such a parcel and who requests to purchase such a parcel), or (2) upon the recommendation of the BLM District Office or System unit that exercises administration over such parcel. </p> <p>Directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Department of the Interior to each create a process by which an adjacent landholder may request to purchase an eligible parcel. Instructs that such process be open to the public and available on the Internet.</p> <p>Bars a conveyed eligible parcel from exceeding 160 acres unless the BLM or the Forest Service approves a request for additional acreage. Permits acquisition by an adjacent landholder of only one eligible parcel a year, subject to an exception. </p> <p>Instructs the BLM or the Forest Service, as consideration for the sale of an eligible parcel, to require a cash payment in an amount equal to at least the fair market value of such parcel, including the mineral estate, being conveyed. </p> <p>Requires the proceeds collected from such conveyances to be deposited into a special fund established by this Act and distributed annually to each state in which the federal government owns more than 33% of the land area of such state.</p> <p>Requires, from amounts collected and deposited: (1) 50% of the amount collected from a conveyance to be distributed to the state in which the conveyance took place, and (2) the remaining 50% to be distributed equally between the remaining states identified pursuant to the preceding paragraph.</p> <p>Requires states receiving such funds to use them only for: (1) purchasing additional eligible parcels consistent with land use management under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act; and (2) complying with requirements under the Endangered Species Act of 1973, the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act), and the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA). </p> <p>Requires the purchaser of an eligible federal lands parcel under this Act to cover the costs to be incurred, or to reimburse the BLM or the Forest Service for the costs incurred, in carrying out the conveyance. </p> <p>Excludes categorically a conveyance of an eligible federal lands parcel under this Act from the requirement to prepare an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement under NEPA. </p> <p>(A categorical exclusion under NEPA is a category of actions which do not individually or cumulatively have a significant effect on the human environment and which have been found to have no such effect in procedures adopted by a federal agency in implementing environmental regulations and for which, therefore, neither an Environmental Assessment nor an Environmental Impact Statement is required.)</p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <updateDate>2015-05-14T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <title>Small Lands Tracts Conveyance Act</title>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>7</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-06-08</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Conservation and Forestry Subcommittee</name>
          <systemCode>hsag15</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-06-04</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Federal Lands Subcommittee</name>
          <systemCode>hsii10</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-05-14</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <committee>
          <name>Agriculture Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsag00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-05-14</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H11100-A</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-05-14</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <committee>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-05-14</actionDate>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-05-14</actionDate>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <billReferralsAggregate>1</billReferralsAggregate>
        <placeholderTextForH>2</placeholderTextForH>
        <billReferrals>2</billReferrals>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <amendments />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <introducedDate>2015-05-14</introducedDate>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
      <actionDate>2015-06-08</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative remedies</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of the Interior</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>General public lands matters</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government trust funds</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Intergovernmental relations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Land transfers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Land use and conservation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local finance</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <cosponsors />
    <notes />
    <billType>HR</billType>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

