<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <billType>HJRES</billType>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
    </policyArea>
    <recordedVotes />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>National Weather Service Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014 - Makes appropriations, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, and out of applicable corporate or other revenues, receipts, and funds, for the National Weather Service for FY2014, and for other purposes, such amounts as may be necessary, at a rate for operations as provided in the Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2013 (division B of P.L. 113-6), for continuing projects or activities of the Service that are not otherwise specifically provided for in this joint resolution, that were conducted in FY2013, and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were made available by such Act under the headings &quot;National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, Operations, Research, and Facilities&quot; and &quot;National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, Procurement, Acquisition and Construction.&quot; </p> <p>Requires the rate of operations to be calculated to reflect the full amount of any reduction required in FY2013 pursuant to: (1) the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013 (P.L. 113-6), and (2) the presidential sequestration order dated March 1, 2013, except as attributable to budget authority made available by the Disaster Relief Appropriations Act, 2013 (P.L. 113-2). </p> <p>Makes appropriations and funds made available and authority granted under this joint resolution available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) enactment into law of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this joint resolution, (2) enactment into law of the applicable appropriations Act for FY2014 without any provision for such project or activity, or (3) December 15, 2013. </p> <p>Requires implementation of this joint resolution so that only the most limited funding action be taken in order to provide for continuation of projects and activities. </p> <p>Authorizes amounts made available for personnel compensation and benefits to be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to avoid furloughs, consistent with the applicable appropriations Act for FY2013, except that such authority shall not be used until after the agency has taken all necessary actions to reduce or defer non-personnel-related administrative expenses. </p> <p>Expresses the sense of Congress that this joint resolution may also be referred to as the National Weather Monitoring Act. </p>]]></text>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-10-09T21:43:02Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <updateDate>2013-10-03T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDate>2013-10-03</actionDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>3</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <name>Appropriations Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsap00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-10-03</actionDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-10-03</actionDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-10-03</actionDate>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T15:56:26Z</updateDate>
    <amendments />
    <introducedDate>2013-10-03</introducedDate>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <billNumber>82</billNumber>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-10-04</actionDate>
          <actionTime>15:02:59</actionTime>
          <text>DEBATE - Mr. Cole asked unanimous consent to modify the text of H.Res. 371 with the amendment at the desk. Agreed to without objection.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <number>371</number>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <type>HRES</type>
        <latestTitle>Providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 75) making continuing appropriations for the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules; waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules; and for other purposes.</latestTitle>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <cosponsors />
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2013-10-03T14:01:50Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <subcommittees />
          <systemCode>hsap00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Appropriations Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Rep. Rogers, Harold [R-KY-5]</fullName>
        <lastName>ROGERS</lastName>
        <byRequestType />
        <party>R</party>
        <state>KY</state>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>HAROLD</firstName>
        <bioguideId>R000395</bioguideId>
        <district>5</district>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>977</lisID>
          <gpoId>7957</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>R000395</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
      <actionDate>2013-10-03</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Appropriations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Atmospheric science and weather</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Commerce</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. ROGERS of Kentucky:H.J. Res. 82.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:The principal constitutional authority for this legislationis clause 7 of section 9 of article I of the Constitution ofthe United States (the appropriation power), which states:``No Money shall be drawn from the Treasury, but inConsequence of Appropriations made by Law . . .'' Inaddition, clause 1 of section 8 of article I of theConstitution (the spending power) provides: ``The Congressshall have the Power . . . to pay the Debts and provide forthe common Defence and general Welfare of the United States .. .'' Together, these specific constitutional provisionsestablish the congressional power of the purse, grantingCongress the authority to appropriate funds, to determinetheir purpose, amount, and period of availability, and to setforth terms and conditions governing their use.[Page H6224]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <createDate>2013-10-04T09:13:09Z</createDate>
    <title>National Weather Service Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <laws />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType>Popular Title</parentTitleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <title>National weather monitoring bill</title>
        <titleType>Popular Titles</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>National Weather Service Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>Making continuing appropriations for the National Weather Service for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>National Weather Service Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <committeeReports />
    <notes />
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2013-10-04T14:40:00Z</pubDate>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/44642</url>
        <title>H.J. Res. 82, National Weather Service Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2013-10-04T14:40:00Z</pubDate>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/44642</url>
        <title>H.J. Res. 82, National Weather Service Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

