<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>6</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <billReferrals>3</billReferrals>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferralsAggregate>1</billReferralsAggregate>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2014-04-09</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to House Intelligence (Permanent)</text>
        <committee>
          <name>Intelligence (Permanent) Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hlig00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2014-04-09</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
        <committee>
          <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsas00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2014-04-09</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
        <committee>
          <name>Foreign Affairs Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsfa00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2014-04-09</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>H11100-A</actionCode>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2014-04-09</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2014-04-09</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <links />
      </item>
    </actions>
    <title>Forging Peace Through Strength in Ukraine and the Transatlantic Alliance Act</title>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-04-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Rogers</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Rogers, Mike D. [R-AL-3]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>Mike</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>R000575</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1704</lisID>
          <gpoId>7788</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>R000575</bioguideId>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-04-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>MCKEON</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. McKeon, Howard P. "Buck" [R-CA-25]</fullName>
        <middleName>P.</middleName>
        <firstName>HOWARD</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7830</gpoId>
          <lisID>778</lisID>
          <bioguideId>M000508</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>M000508</bioguideId>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-04-10</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Bridenstine</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Bridenstine, Jim [R-OK-1]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>Jim</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>B001283</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2155</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>B001283</bioguideId>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-05-01</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Stivers</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Stivers, Steve [R-OH-15]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>Steve</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>S001187</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2047</lisID>
          <gpoId>8105</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>S001187</bioguideId>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-05-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Enyart</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Enyart, William L. [D-IL-12]</fullName>
        <middleName>L.</middleName>
        <firstName>William</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2125</lisID>
          <bioguideId>E000292</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>E000292</bioguideId>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-07-31</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>McCaul</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. McCaul, Michael T. [R-TX-10]</fullName>
        <middleName>T.</middleName>
        <firstName>Michael</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>M001157</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1804</lisID>
          <gpoId>8166</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>M001157</bioguideId>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <firstName>Michael</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>T000463</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Turner, Michael R. [R-OH-10]</fullName>
        <lastName>Turner</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1741</lisID>
          <bioguideId>T000463</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8093</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>International Affairs</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Alliances</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Arms control and nonproliferation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Asia</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Bosnia and Herzegovina</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>China</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Computer security and identity theft</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Conflicts and wars</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Europe</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Georgia (Republic)</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Greece</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>International organizations and cooperation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Macedonia</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Middle East</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military assistance, sales, and agreements</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military education and training</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military facilities and property</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military operations and strategy</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military readiness</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Montenegro</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Nuclear weapons</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Poland</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Russia</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Sanctions</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Space flight and exploration</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Ukraine</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:12:23Z</updateDate>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <billNumber>4433</billNumber>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Forging Peace Through Strength in Ukraine and the Transatlantic Alliance Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To provide military assistance to Ukraine, to enhance the presence and capabilities of the United States military in Europe, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Forging Peace Through Strength in Ukraine and the Transatlantic Alliance Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <createDate>2014-04-10T07:11:38Z</createDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <introducedDate>2014-04-09</introducedDate>
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2014-04-09</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence (Permanent)</text>
    </latestAction>
    <laws />
    <relatedBills />
    <notes />
    <recordedVotes />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <policyArea>
      <name>International Affairs</name>
    </policyArea>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. TURNER:H.R. 4433.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:The constitutional authority on which this bill rests isthe power of Congress ``to provide for the common Defence'',``to raise and support Armies'', and ``to make Rules for theGovernment and Regulation of the land and naval Forces'' asenumerated in Article I, section 8 of the United StatesConstitution.[Page H3143]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2014-04-09T14:01:45Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>hlig00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
          <type>Select</type>
          <name>Intelligence (Permanent) Committee</name>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
        </item>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2014-04-09T14:01:40Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>hsas00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
        </item>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2014-04-09T14:01:35Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>hsfa00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Foreign Affairs Committee</name>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <amendments />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-04-29T20:32:01Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Forging Peace Through Strength in Ukraine and the Transatlantic Alliance Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the continuing practice by the Russian Federation of physical, diplomatic, and economic aggression toward neighboring countries is clearly intended to undermine regional security and stability; (2) the Russian military build-up and aggressive posture on the eastern border of Ukraine represents an intent to intimidate Ukraine and its citizens to submit to Russian control; (3) the Russian Federation should immediately cease all improper and illegal activities in Ukraine and President Putin should direct an immediate return of Russian forces; (4) the United States reaffirms its commitment to explicitly secure the independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity and borders of Ukraine; (5) the United States supports the expansion of security cooperation with states in Central and Eastern Europe, including NATO member states, NATO aspirants, and appropriate Eastern Partnership countries; (6) the United States reaffirms support of NATO efforts to resolve the conflict peacefully and diplomatically; and (7) the United States should take immediate steps to enhance its military presence and readiness posture in Europe to deter aggression and assure its allies and partners through forward presence and engagement.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) (Secretary) to develop and report on a strategic framework for U.S. security force assistance and cooperation in the European and Eurasian regions.</p> <p>Directs the President to submit a plan to: (1) increase U.S. intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance capabilities devoted to monitoring the situation in Ukraine; (2) increase U.S. intelligence information sharing and situational awareness to the maximum extent practicable with Ukraine utilizing appropriate bilateral channels and the NATO-Ukraine Commission; (3) provide military advice and technical assistance to the Ukrainian military to enhance their defensive preparations and posture; (4) convene NATO member states and Ukraine to review options and implement prudent steps to increase the defense of U.S., NATO, and Ukraine cyber networks; and (5) work with NATO member states and the Ukrainian military to counter Russian propaganda.</p> <p>Expresses the sense of Congress in support of the immediate augmentation of U.S. Armed Forces in the area of responsibility of the U.S. European Command in order to meet operational plan requirements for response in support of a NATO ally. Directs the Secretary to provide notification of such augmentation, as well as related information. Calls for the President to immediately correct deficiencies in the readiness of U.S. Armed Forces in such area and to provide appropriate additional resources to NATO as needed.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to ensure the operational availability of the Aegis Ashore system site in Poland. Authorizes the Secretary to relocate the necessary assets of the Aegis weapon system between and within the DDG-51 Class Destroyer program and the Aegis Ashore program to meet mission requirements.</p> <p>States that it is the policy of the United States that available short-range air and missile defense systems and terminal missile defense systems of the United States with operational missiles be rotationally deployed to central and eastern European allies to strengthen their air and missile defense capabilities. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary: (1) by December 31, 2014, and pursuant to an agreement between the United States and Poland, to deploy to Poland a system providing a short-range air and missile defense capability and/or terminal missile defense capability and the personnel required to operate and maintain such system; (2) to stop plans for the relocation and consolidation of U.S. dual-capable aircraft that are based in Europe and develop plans to temporarily base such aircraft in NATO member states that request to host such aircraft; (3) to conduct siting studies for the construction of weapon storage and security systems and protective aircraft shelters in NATO member states that notify the Secretary of an interest in hosting such systems and shelters and to provide for reasonable burden sharing of associated costs; and (4) to coordinate with NATO member states on the policy considerations of a decision to alter the posture of forward deployed nuclear weapons and related capabilities of the United States.</p> <p>Prohibits FY2015 DOD funds from being used for any bilateral military-to-military contact or cooperation between the United States and the Russian Federation until the Secretary makes certain certifications with respect to Russian recognition of the sovereignty of all Ukrainian territory and related matters. Allows a waiver in the U.S. national security interest.</p> <p>Prohibits FY2015 Department of Energy (DOE) National Nuclear Security Administration funds from being used for any contract, cooperation, or transfer of technology between the United States and the Russian Federation until the Secretary of Energy makes certain certifications with respect to Russia's respect of Ukrainian territory and compliance with the Treaty Between the United States of America and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on the Elimination of Their Intermediate-Range and Shorter-Range Missiles and the Treaty on Conventional Armed Forces in Europe. Allows a waiver in the national security interest.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to report annually on the current and future military power of the Russian Federation.</p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2014-04-09T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2014-04-09</actionDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <committeeReports />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

