<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <middleName>Alfred</middleName>
        <lastName>Perdue</lastName>
        <fullName>Sen. Perdue, David [R-GA]</fullName>
        <firstName>David</firstName>
        <bioguideId>P000612</bioguideId>
        <state>GA</state>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>P000612</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2286</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-03-10</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <laws />
    <congress>114</congress>
    <billNumber>2665</billNumber>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <amendments />
    <notes />
    <recordedVotes />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>State and Local Cyber Protection Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) national cybersecurity and communications integration center (NCCIC) to assist state and local governments with cybersecurity by:</p> <ul> <li>upon request,&nbsp;identifying system vulnerabilities and information security protections&nbsp;to address unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction of information collected or maintained by, or information systems used or operated by, state or local governments or other organizations or contractors on their behalf; </li> <li>providing via a web portal updated resources and guidelines related to information security; </li> <li>coordinating through national associations to implement information security tools and policies to ensure the resiliency of state and local information systems; </li> <li>providing training on cybersecurity, privacy, and civil liberties; </li> <li>providing requested technical assistance to deploy technology that continuously diagnoses and mitigates cyber threats and to conduct threat and vulnerability assessments; </li> <li>coordinating vulnerability disclosures under standards developed by the National Institute of Standards and Technology; and </li> <li>ensuring that state and local governments are aware of DHS resources and other federal tools to ensure the security and resiliency of federal civilian information systems.</li></ul> <p>The NCCIC's&nbsp;privacy and civil liberties training must include:&nbsp;(1) reasonable limits on the receipt, retention, use, and disclosure of information associated with specific persons that is not necessary for cybersecurity purposes; (2) data integrity standards requiring the prompt removal and destruction of obsolete or erroneous names and personal information that is unrelated to the risk or incident information; (3) safeguards and confidentiality protections for&nbsp;cyber threat indicators and defensive measures, including information that is proprietary or business-sensitive that may be used to identify specific persons from unauthorized access or acquisition; and (4) methods to ensure that information obtained from efforts to address cybersecurity risks and incidents is used only for such purposes or as specifically authorized by law.</p>]]></text>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-04-15T21:45:38Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2016-03-10T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <actionDate>2016-03-10</actionDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <updateDate>2017-01-11T14:36:34Z</updateDate>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-03-10</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <actionDate>2016-03-10</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <createDate>2016-03-11T05:19:33Z</createDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Computer security and identity theft</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Intergovernmental relations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Right of privacy</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local government operations</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <title>State and Local Cyber Protection Act of 2016</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require State and local coordination on cybersecurity with the national cybersecurity and communications integration center, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>State and Local Cyber Protection Act of 2016</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <number>3869</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestTitle>State and Local Cyber Protection Act of 2015</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-12-14</actionDate>
          <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>114</congress>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <title>State and Local Cyber Protection Act of 2016</title>
    <introducedDate>2016-03-10</introducedDate>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-03-10</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <committeeReports />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2016-03-10T18:11:30Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Peters, Gary C. [D-MI]</fullName>
        <firstName>Gary</firstName>
        <bioguideId>P000595</bioguideId>
        <party>D</party>
        <byRequestType />
        <middleName>C.</middleName>
        <state>MI</state>
        <lastName>Peters</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>P000595</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7994</gpoId>
          <lisID>1929</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

