<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:26:41Z</updateDate>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Read the second time and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <laws />
    <introducedDate>2013-08-01</introducedDate>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2013-08-01T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-11-18T20:25:24Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Congressional Health Care for Seniors Act of 2013 - Allows access to the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program (FEHBP) beginning in 2015 for persons who would have been entitled to, or could have enrolled in part A (Hospital Insurance) Medicare benefits, or who could have enrolled in part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) Medicare.</p> <p>States that a covered individual who elects to enroll in such program shall enroll as an individual and not as self and family.</p> <p>Bases monthly premiums on adjusted gross income.</p> <p>Requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to establish procedures to ensure that health benefits plans coordinate with state Medicaid programs regarding cost-sharing and other medical assistance for covered individuals enrolled in health benefit plans who are also eligible for medical assistance and enrolled in a state Medicaid program.</p> <p>Requires OPM, at the end of each contract year, to identify high risk individuals and pay to a carrier contracting to provide a health benefits plan to a high risk individual 90% of the benefits paid by the carrier for such individual.</p> <p>Defines &quot;high risk individual&quot; as an enrolled individual who, of all individuals enrolled in a health benefits plan for the contract year, is in the highest 5% in terms of benefits paid by a carrier for the contract year.</p> <p>Exempts health benefits plans from specified insurance requirements of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</p> <p>Amends the Social Security Act to incrementally increase the Medicare qualifying age from 65 years to 70 years, by 2034, plus the number of months in a specified age increase factor.</p> <p>Sunsets Medicare, on January 1, 2014, with a transition to FEHBP coverage. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make available to states recommendations with respect to specified requirements for health care entities and individuals under Medicare that will no longer apply but that should be considered on the state level.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <recordedVotes />
    <notes />
    <billNumber>1469</billNumber>
    <committeeReports />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <congress>113</congress>
    <amendments />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <createDate>2013-08-02T05:52:43Z</createDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Health</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Employment taxes</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government trust funds</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health care costs and insurance</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health care coverage and access</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Medicare</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>Paul</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>P000603</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2082</lisID>
          <gpoId>8308</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>Rand</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. Paul, Rand [R-KY]</fullName>
        <bioguideId>P000603</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors />
    <title>Congressional Health Care for Seniors Act of 2013</title>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
          <name>Finance Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read the second time and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Congressional Health Care for Seniors Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide higher-quality, lower-cost health care to seniors.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Congressional Health Care for Seniors Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <relatedBills />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2013-08-01T21:53:01Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Finance Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

