<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:26:25Z</updateDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>CARPER</lastName>
        <firstName>THOMAS</firstName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>C000174</bioguideId>
          <lisID>179</lisID>
          <gpoId>8283</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>C000174</bioguideId>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <fullName>Sen. Carper, Thomas R. [D-DE]</fullName>
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <createDate>2013-07-31T15:52:21Z</createDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government buildings, facilities, and property</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Homelessness and emergency shelter</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Housing and community development funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Performance measurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Postal service</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public-private cooperation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <introducedDate>2013-07-30</introducedDate>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 113-122</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Reported by</name>
              <date>2013-11-19T20:22:26Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Markup by</name>
              <date>2013-07-31T13:13:55Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2013-07-30T22:40:01Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <title>S. 1398, Federal Real Property Asset Management Reform Act of 2013</title>
        <pubDate>2013-11-01T20:21:00Z</pubDate>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/44682</url>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>S. 1398, Federal Real Property Asset Management Reform Act of 2013</title>
        <pubDate>2013-11-01T20:21:00Z</pubDate>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/44682</url>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <amendments />
    <title>Federal Real Property Asset Management Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <notes />
    <billNumber>1398</billNumber>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>TOM</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. Coburn, Tom [R-OK]</fullName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-30</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>C000560</bioguideId>
        <lastName>COBURN</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>C000560</bioguideId>
          <lisID>212</lisID>
          <gpoId>8293</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <middleName>Lunsford</middleName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. Pryor, Mark L. [D-AR]</fullName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-30</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>P000590</bioguideId>
        <lastName>Pryor</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1701</lisID>
          <bioguideId>P000590</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8241</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. Begich, Mark [D-AK]</fullName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-30</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>B001265</bioguideId>
        <lastName>Begich</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8301</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>B001265</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1898</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>ROB</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. Portman, Rob [R-OH]</fullName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-30</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>P000449</bioguideId>
        <lastName>PORTMAN</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>P000449</bioguideId>
          <lisID>924</lisID>
          <gpoId>8266</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>Jon</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. Tester, Jon [D-MT]</fullName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-30</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>T000464</bioguideId>
        <lastName>Tester</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1829</lisID>
          <bioguideId>T000464</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8258</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>Kelly</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. Ayotte, Kelly [R-NH]</fullName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-30</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>A000368</bioguideId>
        <lastName>Ayotte</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8315</gpoId>
          <lisID>2075</lisID>
          <bioguideId>A000368</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <number>0249</number>
        <calendar>Senate Calendar of Business</calendar>
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-09-20T18:47:17Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Federal Real Property Asset Management Reform Act of 2013 - States that the purpose of this Act is to increase the efficiency and effectiveness of the federal government in managing real property by: (1) requiring federal agencies to maintain an up-to-date inventory of real property, (2) establishing a Federal Real Property Council to develop guidance on and ensure the implementation of strategies for better managing federal real property, and (3) authorizing a pilot program to expedite the disposal of surplus real property. </p> <p>Requires each federal agency to: (1) maintain adequate inventory controls and accountability systems for real property under its control, (2) develop current and future workforce projections to assess the need of the federal workforce regarding the use of real property, (3) continuously survey real property under its control to identify excess and underutilized property and other real property suitable for colocation or consolidation with other agencies and facilities, (4) establish goals to reduce excess and underutilized federal property, (5) assess leased space to identify space that is not fully used or occupied, and (6) conduct an inventory and make an assessment of real property under its control.</p> <p>Requires the Postmaster General to annually identify a list of postal properties with space available for use by federal agencies. </p> <p>Establishes a Federal Real Property Council to: (1) develop guidance and ensure implementation of an efficient and effective real property management strategy, (2) identify opportunities to better manage real property assets, and (3) reduce the costs of managing real property. Requires agencies with independent leasing authority to submit to the Council a list of all their leases, including operating leases.</p> <p>Requires the Administrator of the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish and maintain a single, comprehensive, and descriptive database of real property under the custody and control of all federal agencies</p> <p>Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to establish a pilot program to dispose of, by sale, transfer, or other means of disposal, any surplus property. Requires the Comptroller General (GAO) to report on such pilot program.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to make grants to private nonprofit organizations to purchase real property to assist the homeless.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2013-07-30</actionDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2013-07-30T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-12-16T19:44:00Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Reported to Senate without amendment</name>
          <actionDesc>Reported to Senate without amendment</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</b></p> <p>Federal Real Property Asset Management Reform Act of 2013 - Defines for purposes of this Act:</p> <ul> <li>"excess property" as any real property under the control of a federal agency that the agency head determines is not required to meet the needs or responsibilities of the agency; </li> <li>"surplus property" as excess real property that is not required to meet the needs or responsibilities of any agency, other than: (1) any military installation; (2) property exempt under public building and property law, including the public domain, land reserved or dedicated for national forest or park purposes, minerals in land, naval vessels, and records of the government; (3) Indian and native Eskimo property held in trust by the federal government; (4) real property operated and maintained by the Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA); (5) any real property the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) excludes for reasons of national security; (6) public lands administered by the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior; and (7) any property operated and maintained by the U.S. Postal Service (USPS); and </li> <li>"underutilized property" as a portion or the entirety of any real property, including improvements, that is used irregularly or intermittently by the accountable agency for program purposes or that is used for program purposes that can be satisfied only with a portion of the property. </li></ul> <p>Requires each federal agency to: </p> <ul> <li>maintain adequate inventory controls and accountability systems for real property under agency control; </li> <li>develop current and future workforce projections to assess the needs of the federal workforce regarding the use of real property; </li> <li>continuously survey real property to identify excess property, underutilized property, and other real property suitable for colocation or consolidation with other federal agencies and facilities; </li> <li>promptly report excess property and underutilized property to the Administrator of the General Services Administration (GSA); </li> <li>establish goals to reduce excess property and underutilized property; </li> <li>submit to the Federal Real Property Council (Council), established by this Act, a report on all excess property and underutilized property in the agency inventory; </li> <li>adopt workplace practices, configurations, and management techniques to increase productivity and decrease the need for federal real property assets; </li> <li>identify leased space that is not fully used or occupied; </li> <li>conduct an annual inventory of real property under agency control and make an assessment of such property using specified criteria; and </li> <li>provide to the Council and the GSA Administrator information used to establish and maintain the database of federal real property assets established by this Act. </li></ul> <p>Authorizes the Postmaster General to identify annually a list of postal property with space available for use by federal agencies and submit such list to the Council. Requires the Council to provide such list to each federal agency.</p> <p>Establishes a Federal Real Property Council to: (1) develop guidance and ensure implementation of an efficient and effective real property management strategy, (2) identify opportunities to better manage real property assets, and (3) reduce the costs of managing real property. Requires the Council to: (1) establish a real property management plan template, updated annually, to reduce surplus property; (2) develop standard use rates and a strategy to reduce reliance of agencies on leased space; (3) provide guidance on eliminating inefficiencies in the leasing process; (4) compile a list of field offices that are suitable for colocation with other federal real property; and (5) report to the OMB Director on a list of remaining excess, surplus, and underutilized property in each agency and on the progress of the Council and agencies in meeting the objectives of this Act. </p> <p>Requires the GSA Administrator to establish and maintain a single, comprehensive, and descriptive database of real property under the custody and control of all federal agencies.</p> <p>Requires agencies with independent leasing authority to submit to the Council a list of all agency leases, including operating leases, with specified information including the expiration dates of such leases and the annual rental rates.</p> <p>Requires the OMB Director to establish a pilot program to dispose of, by sale, transfer, or other means of disposal, any surplus property. Authorizes the Director to authorize the disposal of not more than 200 surplus properties.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to make grants to private nonprofit organizations to purchase real property to assist the homeless.</p> <p>Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to submit a draft and a final report on the expedited disposal pilot program established by this Act.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2013-11-19</actionDate>
          <versionCode>80</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2013-11-19T12:37:18Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles Senate</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <title>Federal Real Property Asset Management Reform Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Federal Real Property Asset Management Reform Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>A bill to require the Federal Government to expedite the sale of underutilized Federal real property.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Federal Real Property Asset Management Reform Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 249.</text>
      <actionDate>2013-11-19</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <orderedReported>1</orderedReported>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>1</placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>
        <reportedToSenate>2</reportedToSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-11-19</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 249.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-11-19</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>report No. 113-122</name>
            <url>/congressional-report/113th-congress/senate-report/122</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Carper without amendment. With written report No. 113-122.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2013-11-19</actionDate>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>report No. 113-122</name>
            <url>/congressional-report/113th-congress/senate-report/122</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Carper without amendment. With written report No. 113-122.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-31</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-30</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2013-07-30</actionDate>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>6</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <laws />
    <recordedVotes />
    <billType>S</billType>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestTitle>Federal Real Property Asset Management Reform Act of 2013</latestTitle>
        <number>1382</number>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-07-29</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestTitle>Postal Reform Act of 2014</latestTitle>
        <number>1486</number>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-07-31</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 523.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

