<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <laws>
      <item>
        <type>Public Law</type>
        <number>114-226</number>
      </item>
    </laws>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <middleName />
        <state>FL</state>
        <lastName>Miller</lastName>
        <firstName>Jeff</firstName>
        <district>1</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Miller, Jeff [R-FL-1]</fullName>
        <party>R</party>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>M001144</bioguideId>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1685</lisID>
          <bioguideId>M001144</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7873</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <updateDate>2016-12-24T12:05:36Z</updateDate>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <systemCode>hsvr00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2016-09-06T18:01:10Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <introducedDate>2016-09-06</introducedDate>
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>4</senate>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>10</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <presentedToPresident>1</presentedToPresident>
        <passedAgreedToInHouse>1</passedAgreedToInHouse>
        <considerationByHouse>1</considerationByHouse>
        <sentToHouse>1</sentToHouse>
        <becamePublicLaw>2</becamePublicLaw>
        <placeholderTextForE>3</placeholderTextForE>
        <amendingTheTitleOfAnActWithoutObjection>1</amendingTheTitleOfAnActWithoutObjection>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <motionToReconsiderResults>1</motionToReconsiderResults>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>1</motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>
        <passedAgreedToInSenate>1</passedAgreedToInSenate>
        <finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>1</finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>
        <passedSenate>1</passedSenate>
        <generalDebate>1</generalDebate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Became Public Law No: 114-226.</text>
        <type>President</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-29</actionDate>
        <actionCode>E40000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Became Public Law No: 114-226.</text>
        <type>BecameLaw</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-29</actionDate>
        <actionCode>36000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Signed by President.</text>
        <type>President</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-29</actionDate>
        <actionCode>E30000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Signed by President.</text>
        <type>BecameLaw</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-29</actionDate>
        <actionCode>36000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Presented to President.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-21</actionDate>
        <actionCode>E20000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Presented to President.</text>
        <type>President</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-21</actionDate>
        <actionCode>28000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-20</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-19</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote. (consideration: CR S5888)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Passed/agreed to in Senate: Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-19</actionDate>
        <actionCode>17000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-13</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <actionTime>16:11:16</actionTime>
        <committee />
        <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-12</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H38800</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <actionTime>16:11:13</actionTime>
        <committee />
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-12</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <actionTime>16:11:10</actionTime>
        <committee />
        <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR H5274-5276)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-12</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H37300</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <actionTime>16:11:10</actionTime>
        <committee />
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-12</actionDate>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <actionTime>16:05:35</actionTime>
        <committee />
        <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5936.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-12</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <actionTime>16:05:32</actionTime>
        <committee />
        <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR H5274-5277)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-12</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <actionTime>16:05:10</actionTime>
        <committee />
        <text>Mr. Miller (FL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-12</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H30300</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsvr00</systemCode>
          <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-06</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-06</actionDate>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-09-06</actionDate>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <createDate>2016-09-07T05:23:29Z</createDate>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-09-12T20:19:11Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Veterans Care Agreement and West Los Angeles Leasing Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to enter into Veterans Care Agreements with certain eligible providers to furnish hospital care, medical services, or extended care to eligible veterans if: (1) furnishing such care and services at VA facilities or under otherwise authorized contracts or sharing agreements with non-VA facilities is impracticable or inadvisable because of the veteran's medical condition, the travel involved, or the nature of the care or services required; and (2) the VA determines that the hospital care or medical services to be furnished are not available from a non-VA health care provider under a contract or sharing agreement other than an agreement under this bill.</p> <p>The bill sets forth provider eligibility criteria and requires the VA to establish a process for provider certification. </p> <p>The VA may carry out leases at the VA West Los Angeles Campus in Los Angeles, California: </p> <ul> <li>for supportive housing for veterans and their families; </li> <li>for third party services to veterans and their families for health and wellness promotion, education, employment-related training, peer activities and physical recreation, legal and federal benefits assistance, family support services including child care, and transportation; and </li> <li> to The Regents of the University of California for additional services for veterans and their families. </li> </ul> <p>The VA shall establish a Community Veterans Engagement Board for the Campus to coordinate locally with the VA to identify community goals and advise the VA on improving services and outcomes for veterans, members of the Armed Forces, and their families. </p> <p>The bill amends provisions regarding the VA's enhanced-use lease authority, including to prohibit the VA from waiving or postponing the obligation of a lessee to pay any consideration, including rent, under an enhanced-use lease.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2016-09-06</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2016-09-06T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-11-03T18:38:31Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Passed House amended</name>
          <versionCode>36</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Passed House amended</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>West Los Angeles Leasing Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out the following leases at the VA's West Los Angeles Campus in Los Angeles, California: </p> <ul> <li>any enhanced-use lease of real property for supportive housing that principally benefits veterans and their families; </li> <li>any lease of real property for not to exceed 50 years to a third party for services that principally benefit veterans and their families and that are related to health and wellness, education, vocational training and employment, peer activities or recreation, legal and federal benefits assistance, volunteerism, family support services, and transportation; and </li> <li>a lease of real property for up to 10 years to the Regents of the University of California, on behalf of the University of California, Los Angeles, if the lease is consistent with the VA master plan, the provision of veterans services is the predominant focus, and the Regents agree to provide non-VA compensated additional services that principally benefit veterans and their families.</li> </ul> <p>The VA shall not enter into land-sharing agreements unless the agreements provide additional health care resources and benefit veterans and their families in ways other than generating additional revenue. </p> <p>Funds received by the VA from a lease shall be credited to the applicable VA medical facilities account and shall be available, without fiscal year limitation and without further appropriation, exclusively for campus renovation and maintenance. </p> <p>The VA may, notwithstanding any other provision of law other than federal laws relating to environmental and historic preservation, grant easements or rights-of-way on, above, or under campus lands to: (1) any local or regional public transportation authority to construct, operate, or maintain public mass transit facilities; and (2) California, the County of Los Angeles, the City of Los Angeles, any agency or political subdivision thereof, or any public utility company for the purpose of providing public utilities. </p> <p>The VA may not sell or convey to a third party fee simple title to any real property or related improvements made at the campus. </p> <p>The VA shall ensure that each lease is consistent with the draft master plan approved by the VA on January 28, 2016, or successor master plans. </p> <p>The VA shall establish, within 180 days, a Community Veterans Engagement Board to coordinate locally with the VA to: (1) identify community goals; and (2) provide advice to improve services for veterans, members of the Armed Forces, and their families. </p> <p>The VA shall submit, annually, an evaluation of all campus leases and land-sharing agreements.</p> <p>The VA Inspector General shall report on: (1) all campus leases; and (2) the VA's management of land use at the campus, including an assessment of efforts to implement the master plan. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The VA may not waive or postpone the obligation of a lessee to pay any consideration under an enhanced-use lease, including monthly rent. (The enhanced-use lease program is a program in which the VA leases under-utilized real estate to the private sector for developing supportive housing and other services for homeless and at-risk veterans and their families.) </p> <p>The bill provides that nothing in this bill shall be construed to: (1) authorize the VA to enter into an enhanced-use lease that authorizes the federal government to guarantee a third party loan to a lessee; and (2) abrogate or constitute a waiver of the sovereign immunity of the United States with respect to any financial agreement between a lessee and a third-party relating to an enhanced-use lease. </p> <p>The annual report on enhanced-use leases shall include: (1) identification of VA actions taken to implement and administer such leases, and (2) lease amounts deposited into the Medical Care Collection Fund account and the VA's use of such funds. </p> <p>Such report shall also include with respect to each enhanced-use lease: (1) an overview of the VA's use of consideration received to support veterans, (2) the amount of consideration received by the VA under or relating to the lease, and (3) the costs to the VA of carrying out the lease. </p> <p>The bill defines &quot;major enhanced-use lease&quot; as an enhanced-use lease that includes more than $10 million in average annual rent.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office shall submit an audit of the enhanced-use lease program within 270 days.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2016-09-12</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2016-09-12T15:34:34Z</updateDate>
        </item>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-11-07T16:20:51Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Passed Senate without amendment</name>
          <versionCode>82</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Passed Senate without amendment</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on September 12, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>West Los Angeles Leasing Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out the following leases at the VA's West Los Angeles Campus in Los Angeles, California: </p> <ul> <li>any enhanced-use lease of real property for supportive housing that principally benefits veterans and their families; </li> <li>any lease of real property for not to exceed 50 years to a third party for services that principally benefit veterans and their families and that are related to health and wellness, education, vocational training and employment, peer activities or recreation, legal and federal benefits assistance, volunteerism, family support services, and transportation; and </li> <li>a lease of real property for up to 10 years to the Regents of the University of California, on behalf of the University of California, Los Angeles, if the lease is consistent with the VA master plan, the provision of veterans services is the predominant focus, and the Regents agree to provide non-VA compensated additional services that principally benefit veterans and their families.</li> </ul> <p>The VA shall not enter into land-sharing agreements unless the agreements provide additional health care resources and benefit veterans and their families in ways other than generating additional revenue. </p> <p>Funds received by the VA from a lease shall be credited to the applicable VA medical facilities account and shall be available, without fiscal year limitation and without further appropriation, exclusively for campus renovation and maintenance. </p> <p>The VA may, notwithstanding any other provision of law other than federal laws relating to environmental and historic preservation, grant easements or rights-of-way on, above, or under campus lands to: (1) any local or regional public transportation authority to construct, operate, or maintain public mass transit facilities; and (2) California, the County of Los Angeles, the City of Los Angeles, any agency or political subdivision thereof, or any public utility company for the purpose of providing public utilities. </p> <p>The VA may not sell or convey to a third party fee simple title to any real property or related improvements made at the campus. </p> <p>The VA shall ensure that each lease is consistent with the draft master plan approved by the VA on January 28, 2016, or successor master plans. </p> <p>The VA shall establish, within 180 days, a Community Veterans Engagement Board to coordinate locally with the VA to: (1) identify community goals; and (2) provide advice to improve services for veterans, members of the Armed Forces, and their families. </p> <p>The VA shall submit, annually, an evaluation of all campus leases and land-sharing agreements.</p> <p>The VA Inspector General shall report on: (1) all campus leases; and (2) the VA's management of land use at the campus, including an assessment of efforts to implement the master plan. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The VA may not waive or postpone the obligation of a lessee to pay any consideration under an enhanced-use lease, including monthly rent. (The enhanced-use lease program is a program in which the VA leases under-utilized real estate to the private sector for developing supportive housing and other services for homeless and at-risk veterans and their families.) </p> <p>The bill provides that nothing in this bill shall be construed to: (1) authorize the VA to enter into an enhanced-use lease that authorizes the federal government to guarantee a third party loan to a lessee; and (2) abrogate or constitute a waiver of the sovereign immunity of the United States with respect to any financial agreement between a lessee and a third-party relating to an enhanced-use lease. </p> <p>The annual report on enhanced-use leases shall include: (1) identification of VA actions taken to implement and administer such leases, and (2) lease amounts deposited into the Medical Care Collection Fund account and the VA's use of such funds. </p> <p>Such report shall also include with respect to each enhanced-use lease: (1) an overview of the VA's use of consideration received to support veterans, (2) the amount of consideration received by the VA under or relating to the lease, and (3) the costs to the VA of carrying out the lease. </p> <p>The bill defines &quot;major enhanced-use lease&quot; as an enhanced-use lease that includes more than $10 million in average annual rent.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office shall submit an audit of the enhanced-use lease program within 270 days.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2016-09-19</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2016-09-19T13:14:17Z</updateDate>
        </item>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-11-07T16:21:05Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Public Law</name>
          <versionCode>49</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Public Law</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on September 12, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>West Los Angeles Leasing Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out the following leases at the VA's West Los Angeles Campus in Los Angeles, California: </p> <ul> <li>any enhanced-use lease of real property for supportive housing that principally benefits veterans and their families; </li> <li>any lease of real property for not to exceed 50 years to a third party for services that principally benefit veterans and their families and that are related to health and wellness, education, vocational training and employment, peer activities or recreation, legal and federal benefits assistance, volunteerism, family support services, and transportation; and </li> <li>a lease of real property for up to 10 years to the Regents of the University of California, on behalf of the University of California, Los Angeles, if the lease is consistent with the VA master plan, the provision of veterans services is the predominant focus, and the Regents agree to provide non-VA compensated additional services that principally benefit veterans and their families.</li> </ul> <p>The VA shall not enter into land-sharing agreements unless the agreements provide additional health care resources and benefit veterans and their families in ways other than generating additional revenue. </p> <p>Funds received by the VA from a lease shall be credited to the applicable VA medical facilities account and shall be available, without fiscal year limitation and without further appropriation, exclusively for campus renovation and maintenance. </p> <p>The VA may, notwithstanding any other provision of law other than federal laws relating to environmental and historic preservation, grant easements or rights-of-way on, above, or under campus lands to: (1) any local or regional public transportation authority to construct, operate, or maintain public mass transit facilities; and (2) California, the County of Los Angeles, the City of Los Angeles, any agency or political subdivision thereof, or any public utility company for the purpose of providing public utilities. </p> <p>The VA may not sell or convey to a third party fee simple title to any real property or related improvements made at the campus. </p> <p>The VA shall ensure that each lease is consistent with the draft master plan approved by the VA on January 28, 2016, or successor master plans. </p> <p>The VA shall establish, within 180 days, a Community Veterans Engagement Board to coordinate locally with the VA to: (1) identify community goals; and (2) provide advice to improve services for veterans, members of the Armed Forces, and their families. </p> <p>The VA shall submit, annually, an evaluation of all campus leases and land-sharing agreements.</p> <p>The VA Inspector General shall report on: (1) all campus leases; and (2) the VA's management of land use at the campus, including an assessment of efforts to implement the master plan. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The VA may not waive or postpone the obligation of a lessee to pay any consideration under an enhanced-use lease, including monthly rent. (The enhanced-use lease program is a program in which the VA leases under-utilized real estate to the private sector for developing supportive housing and other services for homeless and at-risk veterans and their families.) </p> <p>The bill provides that nothing in this bill shall be construed to: (1) authorize the VA to enter into an enhanced-use lease that authorizes the federal government to guarantee a third party loan to a lessee; and (2) abrogate or constitute a waiver of the sovereign immunity of the United States with respect to any financial agreement between a lessee and a third-party relating to an enhanced-use lease. </p> <p>The annual report on enhanced-use leases shall include: (1) identification of VA actions taken to implement and administer such leases, and (2) lease amounts deposited into the Medical Care Collection Fund account and the VA's use of such funds. </p> <p>Such report shall also include with respect to each enhanced-use lease: (1) an overview of the VA's use of consideration received to support veterans, (2) the amount of consideration received by the VA under or relating to the lease, and (3) the costs to the VA of carrying out the lease. </p> <p>The bill defines &quot;major enhanced-use lease&quot; as an enhanced-use lease that includes more than $10 million in average annual rent.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office shall submit an audit of the enhanced-use lease program within 270 days.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2016-09-29</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2016-09-30T03:59:58Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <district>33</district>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>L000582</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2230</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>L000582</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Lieu, Ted [D-CA-33]</fullName>
        <lastName>Lieu</lastName>
        <firstName>Ted</firstName>
        <party>D</party>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-09-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <state>CA</state>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <billNumber>5936</billNumber>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <recordedVotes />
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. MILLER of Florida:H.R. 5936.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article 1, Section 8 of the United States Constitution.[Page H5096]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committeeReports />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType>Short Title</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Enacted</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>West Los Angeles Leasing Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles Senate</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed Senate</titleType>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
        <title>West Los Angeles Leasing Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House</titleType>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <title>West Los Angeles Leasing Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>Veterans Care Agreement and West Los Angeles Leasing Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType>Official Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Official Titles as Amended by House</titleType>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <title>To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into certain leases at the Department of Veterans Affairs West Los Angeles Campus in Los Angeles, California, to make certain improvements to the enhanced-use lease authority of the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into agreements with certain health care providers to furnish health care to veterans, to authorize the Secretary to enter into certain leases at the Department of Veterans Affairs West Los Angeles Campus in Los Angeles, California, to make certain improvements to the enhanced-use lease authority of the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>West Los Angeles Leasing Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <amendments />
    <title>West Los Angeles Leasing Act of 2016</title>
    <notes />
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestTitle>Los Angeles Homeless Veterans Leasing Act of 2016</latestTitle>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <number>3484</number>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-05-17</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 442.</text>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Accounting and auditing</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>California</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Veterans Affairs</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government buildings, facilities, and property</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health facilities and institutions</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Land transfers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Land use and conservation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military personnel and dependents</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public transit</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public utilities and utility rates</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Veterans' medical care</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Vocational and technical education</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2016-09-29</actionDate>
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-226.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

