<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <notes />
    <billNumber>5487</billNumber>
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2016-09-19</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <introducedDate>2016-06-15</introducedDate>
    <amendments />
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <billReferralsAggregate>1</billReferralsAggregate>
        <billReferrals>3</billReferrals>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-19</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Higher Education and Workforce Training Subcommittee</name>
          <systemCode>hsed13</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2016-06-15</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2016-06-15</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2016-06-15</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H11100-A</actionCode>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2016-06-15</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <name>Education and the Workforce Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsed00</systemCode>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2016-06-15</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2016-06-15</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>7</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Education</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Consumer Financial Protection Bureau</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Education programs funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government lending and loan guarantees</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health care coverage and access</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health personnel</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Higher education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Income tax exclusion</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Interest, dividends, interest rates</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Medical education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Student aid and college costs</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>Bass</lastName>
        <firstName>Karen</firstName>
        <party>D</party>
        <fullName>Rep. Bass, Karen [D-CA-37]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <state>CA</state>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>B001270</bioguideId>
        <district>37</district>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1996</lisID>
          <bioguideId>B001270</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7838</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <recordedVotes />
    <committeeReports />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Education</name>
    </policyArea>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2017-01-17T17:30:23Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2016-06-15</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Student Loan Fairness Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to establish a 10/10 Loan Repayment Plan that allows borrowers of Federal Family Education Loans (FFELs) and Direct Loans (DLs) to limit their monthly payments on such loans to one-twelfth of 10% of the amount by which their adjusted gross incomes and that of their spouses (if applicable) exceed 150% of the federal poverty level.</p> <p>Additionally, it establishes a 10/10 Loan Forgiveness Program that provides FFEL and DL forgiveness to borrowers who, after the date that is 10 years before this bill's enactment, have made 120 monthly payments under the 10/10 Loan Repayment Plan or under another repayment plan that required them to make payments at least as large as those they would have made under the 10/10 Loan Repayment Plan. </p> <p>It credits the months during which an individual is in deferment due to an economic hardship as months for which payment was made for purposes of the 10/10 Loan Forgiveness Program.</p> <p>The bill caps the amount of loan forgiveness that the program will provide to individuals who become new borrowers after this bill's enactment.</p> <p>It caps the interest rate on new DLs at 3.4%.</p> <p>It amends the public service employee loan forgiveness program to forgive the DLs of participants who have made 60 (currently, 120) monthly payments on such loans pursuant to specified repayment plans.</p> <p>The bill includes primary care physicians in medically underserved areas in the public service employee loan forgiveness program.</p> <p>Certain borrowers may consolidate their private education loans as Direct Consolidation Loans, provided the private loans were made on or before this bill's enactment.</p> <p>The bill limits such borrowers to those who: (1) were students eligible for unsubsidized Stafford loans or PLUS loans under the FFEL or DL programs for their enrollment at an institution of higher education, or would have been had they been enrolled on at least a half-time basis; (2) borrowed at least one private education loan for such enrollment; and (3) have an average adjusted gross income that does not exceed their total education debt.</p> <p>It caps the interest rate on those Direct Consolidation Loans at 3.4%.</p> <p>Borrowers must apply for such loans within one year of this bill's enactment.</p> <p>It amends the Truth in Lending Act to direct the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau to issue regulations that require private education lenders to sell private education loans to the Department of Education (ED) for consolidation as Direct Consolidation Loans. </p> <p>It sets forth the data to be used in determining the price paid for such loans. </p> <p>ED must pay the interest that accrues on unsubsidized FFELs and DLs that are deferred due to a student borrower's lack of full-time employment. </p> <p>ED must pay the interest that accrues on Federal Consolidation Loans that are in deferment due to a borrower's lack of full-time employment, provided the application for such a loan is received on or after this bill's enactment.</p> <p>ED must pay the interest that accrues on FFELs and DLs that are subject to income-based repayment provisions and are in deferment due to a borrower's lack of full-time employment.</p> <p>The bill limits these interest-free deferment periods to those occurring on or after this bill's enactment and covering no more than three years of full-time unemployment.</p> <p>It excludes from a borrower's gross income for income tax purposes the principal and interest on FFELs and DLs that is forgiven pursuant to income-based repayment plans. </p>]]></text>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <updateDate>2016-06-15T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <createDate>2016-06-16T04:46:10Z</createDate>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2016-06-15T14:00:38Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2016-09-19T14:35:19Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
              <name>Higher Education and Workforce Training Subcommittee</name>
              <systemCode>hsed13</systemCode>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <systemCode>hsed00</systemCode>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <name>Education and the Workforce Committee</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2016-06-15T14:00:48Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <subcommittees />
          <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2016-06-15T14:00:43Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <subcommittees />
          <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills />
    <laws />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Student Loan Fairness Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>To increase purchasing power, strengthen economic recovery, and restore fairness in financing higher education in the United States through student loan forgiveness, caps on interest rates on Federal student loans, and refinancing opportunities for private borrowers, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Student Loan Fairness Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <cosponsors />
    <updateDate>2017-01-17T17:31:13Z</updateDate>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Ms. BASS:H.R. 5487.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article. I.Section 1.All legislative Powers herein granted shall be vested in aCongress of the United States, which shall consist of aSenate and House of Representatives.[Page H3914]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <title>Student Loan Fairness Act</title>
    <congress>114</congress>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

