<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <laws />
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>H. Rept. 114-807</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <recordedVotes />
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <title>PIPES Act of 2016</title>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-08-26T16:11:32Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protecting our Infrastructure of Pipelines and Enhancing Safety Act of 2016 or the PIPES Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill reauthorizes through FY2019 the gas and hazardous liquid pipeline and related programs of the Department of Transportation (DOT), including Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration (PHMSA) operational expenses, one-call notification programs, community pipeline safety information grants, and the pipeline integrity program.</p> <p> The DOT Inspector General shall report to DOT, PHMSA, and Congress a list of each statutory pipeline safety mandate contained in the Pipeline Safety, Regulatory Certainty, and Job Creation Act of 2011, as well as those pipeline safety statutory mandates contained in this Act and other prior Acts, that have not been implemented.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office (GAO) shall report to Congress on the natural gas integrity management and hazardous liquid integrity management programs.</p> <p>After completion of any PHMSA pipeline safety inspection, the PHMSA, or the certified state authority, shall:</p> <ul> <li>conduct a post-inspection briefing with the gas or hazardous liquid pipeline owner or operator outlining any concerns, and</li> <li>give the owner or operator written preliminary findings of the inspection.</li> </ul> <p> GAO shall study improving existing damage prevention programs through technological improvements in location and communications practices to prevent excavation damage to a pipe or its coating.</p> <p>DOT's Inspector General shall review PHMSA staff resource management.</p> <p>DOT shall convene a working group to consider development of a voluntary information sharing system to encourage collaborative efforts to improve inspection information feedback and information sharing regarding natural gas transmission and hazardous liquid pipeline integrity risk analysis.</p> <p>DOT shall:</p> <ul> <li>establish a national integrated pipeline safety regulatory inspection database to improve communication and collaboration between the PHMSA and state pipeline regulators, and </li> <li>issue minimum safety standards for underground natural gas storage facilities.</li> </ul> <p>The bill imposes a fee on the operator of an underground natural gas storage facility, and establishes the Underground Natural Gas Storage Facility Safety Account in the Pipeline Safety Fund to receive such fees.</p> <p>Each hazardous liquid pipeline owner or operator shall provide safety data sheets on any spilled oil to the designated federal On-Scene Coordinator and state officials within six hours of notice of a spill to the National Response Center.</p> <p>DOT may issue an emergency order, without prior notice or hearing, for violations of pipeline regulations, or an unsafe condition or practice, or combination thereof, constituting or causing an imminent hazard.</p> <p>Each hazardous liquid pipeline owner or operator required to prepare a response plan shall consider the impact of a discharge into or on navigable waters or adjoining shorelines, including those covered by ice.</p> <p>DOT shall revise certain regulations to state explicitly that the Great Lakes and any marine coastal waters (including coastal estuaries) are USA ecological resources for purposes of determining whether a pipeline is in a high consequence area.</p> <p>DOT's Inspector General shall report to Congress on the community pipeline safety technical assistance grants program.</p> <p>GAO shall study materials and corrosion prevention technologies used in pipeline transportation.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2016-04-14</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2016-04-14T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <versionCode>17</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-12-01T19:47:11Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Reported to House amended</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protecting our Infrastructure of Pipelines and Enhancing Safety Act of 2016 or the PIPES Act of 2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill reauthorizes through FY2019 the gas and hazardous liquid pipeline and related programs of the Department of Transportation (DOT), including Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration (PHMSA) operational expenses, one-call notification programs, community pipeline safety information grants, and the pipeline integrity program.</p> <p> (Sec. 3) The DOT Inspector General shall report to DOT, PHMSA, and Congress a list of each statutory pipeline safety mandate contained in the Pipeline Safety, Regulatory Certainty, and Job Creation Act of 2011, as well as those pipeline safety statutory mandates contained in this Act and other prior Acts, that have not been implemented.</p> <p>DOT shall periodically report to Congress on specific actions taken to implement such mandates and make such report publicly available on its website.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The Government Accountability Office (GAO) shall report to Congress on the natural gas integrity management and hazardous liquid integrity management programs.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) Two of the individuals selected for each Technical Pipeline Safety Standards Committee and each Technical Hazardous Liquid Pipeline Safety Standards Committee must be state officials (currently, state commissioners). DOT must consult with national organizations representing commissioners (as under current law) or governors before making such a selection.</p> <p>DOT shall fill all vacancies on technical safety standards committees within 90 days of enactment of this bill, and after that period, not later than 60 days after a vacancy occurs.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) After completion of any PHMSA pipeline safety inspection, the PHMSA, or the certified state authority, shall:</p> <ul> <li>conduct a post-inspection briefing with the gas or hazardous liquid pipeline owner or operator outlining any concerns, and</li> <li>give the owner or operator written preliminary findings of the inspection.</li> </ul> <p> (Sec. 8) The GAO shall study improving existing damage prevention programs through technological improvements in location and communications practices to prevent excavation damage to a pipe or its coating.</p> <p>(Sec. 9) The DOT Inspector General shall review PHMSA staff resource management, including any recommendations to address hiring challenges, training needs, and any other staff resource challenges.</p> <p>(Sec. 10) DOT shall convene a working group to consider development of a voluntary information sharing system to encourage collaborative efforts to improve inspection information feedback and information sharing regarding natural gas transmission and hazardous liquid pipeline integrity risk analysis.</p> <p>(Sec. 11) DOT shall establish a national integrated pipeline safety regulatory inspection database to improve communication and collaboration between the PHMSA and state pipeline regulators.</p> <p>(Sec. 12) DOT shall issue minimum safety standards for underground natural gas storage facilities.</p> <p>A state authority may adopt additional or more stringent safety standards for such facilities if they are compatible with the minimum standards.</p> <p>The bill imposes a fee on the operator of an underground natural gas storage facility, and establishes the Underground Natural Gas Storage Facility Safety Account in the Pipeline Safety Fund to receive such fees.</p> <p>(Sec. 13) DOT shall allow for a state authority with a pipeline safety program certification, at its request, to participate in the inspection of an interstate pipeline facility. </p> <p>(Sec. 14) Each hazardous liquid pipeline owner or operator shall provide safety data sheets on any spilled oil to the designated federal On-Scene Coordinator and state officials within six hours of notice of a spill to the National Response Center.</p> <p>(Sec. 15) DOT shall issue an advanced notice of proposed rulemaking to take public comment on the petition for rulemaking dated October 28, 2015, titled &quot;Corrections to title 49 CFR 172.336 identification numbers; special provisions&quot; (P-1667), regarding the display of hazardous materials identification numbers on transport vehicles or freight containers.</p> <p>(Sec. 16) DOT may issue an emergency order, without prior notice or hearing, for an unsafe condition or practice, or combination thereof, constituting or causing an imminent hazard.</p> <p>(Sec. 17) The bill revises DOT authority to withhold any part of a payment from a state authority under a state pipeline safety grant if the state authority is not maintaining a satisfactory effort to carry out a safety program or is not acting satisfactorily as an agent. </p> <p>DOT may, if a state certification is rejected or otherwise suspended or interrupted, use any unobligated or deobligated grant funds to carry out pipeline safety activities in that state.</p> <p>(Sec. 18) Each hazardous liquid pipeline owner or operator required to prepare a response plan shall consider the impact of a discharge into or on navigable waters or adjoining shorelines, including those covered by ice.</p> <p>(Sec. 19) DOT shall revise certain regulations to state explicitly that the Great Lakes and any marine coastal waters (including coastal estuaries) are USA ecological resources for purposes of determining whether a pipeline is in a high consequence area.</p> <p>(Sec. 20) The DOT Inspector General shall report to Congress on the community pipeline safety technical assistance grants program.</p> <p>(Sec. 21) The GAO shall study materials, training, and corrosion prevention technologies used in pipeline transportation.</p> <p>(Sec. 22) The GAO shall report to Congress on PHMSA's research and development program for pipeline facility integrity.</p> <p>Certain DOT biennial reporting requirements regarding gas and hazardous liquid pipeline safety are revised to require an analysis and evaluation of each R&amp;D pipeline facility integrity project using federal and non-federal entities as well as a review of how the project affects safety.</p> <p>The bill amends the Pipeline Safety Improvement Act of 2002 to revise requirements for the allocation of funding costs of pipeline transportation R&amp;D using non-federal sources.</p> <p>DOT shall implement processes and procedures to ensure that such projects produce results that are factual and peer-reviewed by independent experts.</p> <p>(Sec. 23) DOT shall issue formal guidance to gas or hazardous liquid pipeline facility owners and operators and state regulatory authorities regarding actions required to change the status of a pipeline facility from active to abandoned.</p> <p>(Sec. 24) The GAO shall complete a study on state pipeline safety agreements within two years of the enactment of this bill.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2016-11-14</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2016-11-14T15:02:55Z</updateDate>
          <name>Reported to House amended</name>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>2276</number>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-06-22</actionDate>
          <text>Became Public Law No: 114-183.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>PIPES Act of 2016</latestTitle>
        <type>S</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>4429</number>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-02-05</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>Natural Gas Leak Prevention Act of 2016</latestTitle>
        <type>HR</type>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <introducedDate>2016-04-14</introducedDate>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Discharged from</name>
              <date>2016-11-14T20:08:44Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2016-04-14T14:02:10Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <systemCode>hsif03</systemCode>
              <name>Energy and Power Subcommittee</name>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2016-04-15T18:11:48Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <type>Standing</type>
        </item>
        <item>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Reported by</name>
              <date>2016-11-14T20:08:38Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Markup by</name>
              <date>2016-04-20T18:57:07Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2016-04-14T14:02:05Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <systemCode>hspw14</systemCode>
              <name>Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials Subcommittee</name>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Discharged from</name>
                  <date>2016-04-20T18:56:14Z</date>
                </item>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2016-04-15T18:55:36Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <type>Standing</type>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <updateDate>2017-01-20T12:33:04Z</updateDate>
    <createDate>2016-04-15T06:54:20Z</createDate>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <notes />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to House</titleType>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <title>PIPES Act of 2016</title>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to House</titleType>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <title>Protecting our Infrastructure of Pipelines and Enhancing Safety Act of 2016</title>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <title>PIPES Act of 2016</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <title>Protecting our Infrastructure of Pipelines and Enhancing Safety Act of 2016</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <title>To amend title 49, United States Code, to reauthorize pipeline safety programs and enhance pipeline safety, and for other purposes.</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <title>PIPES Act of 2016</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <amendments />
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2016-05-27T18:31:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>H.R. 4937, PIPES Act of 2016</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/51632</url>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. DENHAM:H.R. 4937.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8 of the United States Constitution,specifically Clause 3 and Clause 18.[Page H1736]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <billNumber>4937</billNumber>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>15</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 631.</text>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H12410</actionCode>
        <type>Calendars</type>
        <actionDate>2016-11-14</actionDate>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Commerce discharged.</text>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H12300</actionCode>
        <type>Discharge</type>
        <actionDate>2016-11-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Commerce discharged.</text>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>5500</actionCode>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionDate>2016-11-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 114-807, Part I.</text>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/house-report/807</url>
            <name>H. Rept. 114-807</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H12200</actionCode>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionDate>2016-11-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 114-807, Part I.</text>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/house-report/807</url>
            <name>H. Rept. 114-807</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>5000</actionCode>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionDate>2016-11-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-04-20</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-04-20</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-04-20</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials Discharged.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-04-15</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hspw14</systemCode>
          <name>Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-04-15</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsif03</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Power Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2016-04-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H11100-A</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2016-04-14</actionDate>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2016-04-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2016-04-14</actionDate>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2016-04-14</actionDate>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>2</billReferrals>
        <houseCommitteeDischarged>1</houseCommitteeDischarged>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <committeeDischarged>1</committeeDischarged>
        <committeeReportOfABill>1</committeeReportOfABill>
        <actionStageOverride>1</actionStageOverride>
        <reportedToHouse>1</reportedToHouse>
        <placeholderTextForH>4</placeholderTextForH>
        <unionCalendarAssignment>1</unionCalendarAssignment>
        <billReferralsAggregate>1</billReferralsAggregate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <number />
        <calendar>U00631</calendar>
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-04-14</sponsorshipDate>
        <fullName>Rep. Capuano, Michael E. [D-MA-7]</fullName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <lastName>CAPUANO</lastName>
        <firstName>MICHAEL</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>C001037</bioguideId>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7973</gpoId>
          <lisID>1564</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C001037</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MA</state>
        <district>7</district>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-04-14</sponsorshipDate>
        <fullName>Rep. Shuster, Bill [R-PA-9]</fullName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>Shuster</lastName>
        <firstName>Bill</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>S001154</bioguideId>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8127</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>S001154</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1681</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>PA</state>
        <district>9</district>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-04-14</sponsorshipDate>
        <fullName>Rep. DeFazio, Peter A. [D-OR-4]</fullName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <middleName>A.</middleName>
        <lastName>DEFAZIO</lastName>
        <firstName>PETER</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>D000191</bioguideId>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>279</lisID>
          <bioguideId>D000191</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8117</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>OR</state>
        <district>4</district>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-11-14</actionDate>
      <links />
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 631.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Accidents</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative remedies</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Advisory bodies</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Aquatic ecology</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Business records</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Transportation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Economic performance and conditions</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Emergency communications systems</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Emergency planning and evacuation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Energy storage, supplies, demand</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Geography</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government trust funds</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Great Lakes</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Hazardous wastes and toxic substances</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Intergovernmental relations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Marine pollution</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Materials</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Navigation, waterways, harbors</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Oil and gas</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Pipelines</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local government operations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Transportation programs funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Transportation safety and security</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>User charges and fees</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water quality</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water storage</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water use and supply</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000612</bioguideId>
        <lastName>Denham</lastName>
        <district>10</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Denham, Jeff [R-CA-10]</fullName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <middleName />
        <byRequestType />
        <firstName>Jeff</firstName>
        <party>R</party>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>D000612</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1995</lisID>
          <gpoId>7824</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

