<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <relatedBills />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Education</name>
    </policyArea>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <laws />
    <billNumber>2524</billNumber>
    <notes />
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-06-24</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:31:07Z</updateDate>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Pathways to Prosperity Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to support access to career and technical education programs of study that provide students with education and training combining rigorous academics with technical curricula focused on specific high-skill, high-wage, high-demand and high-growth occupations and industries.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Pathways to Prosperity Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <title>Pathways to Prosperity Act of 2014</title>
    <committeeReports />
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000805</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Warner, Mark R. [D-VA]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1897</lisID>
          <gpoId>8269</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>W000805</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <byRequestType />
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <lastName>Warner</lastName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <introducedDate>2014-06-24</introducedDate>
    <createDate>2014-06-25T04:54:44Z</createDate>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-06-24T21:22:09Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>K000384</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Kaine, Tim [D-VA]</fullName>
        <lastName>Kaine</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>K000384</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2176</lisID>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
        <middleName />
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-06-24</sponsorshipDate>
        <firstName>Timothy</firstName>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Pathways to Prosperity Act of 2014 - Amends the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act to replace specified minimum measures of student attainment in the core indicators of performance for career and technical education students at the secondary level with a measure of the median earnings of students employed during the second quarter after completing a career and technical education program of study in the state.</p> <p>Requires the national research center, established under the Act, to engage in evaluation and technical assistance activities that will assist in: (1) collecting information on the industry-recognized credentials awarded to participants in career and technical education programs, and (2) developing the necessary infrastructure to support the state and local reporting of specified related information.</p> <p>Makes it a responsibility of the state agency involved to establish statewide credit transfer agreements aligned to approved career and technical education programs of study.</p> <p>Requires each local plan for career and technical education programs to describe how the eligible recipient of assistance will partner with business and industry to: (1) identify opportunities for experiential and work-based learning opportunities either in-person or virtually, (2) ensure the career and technical education programs of study are responsive to community and employment demands and meet other specified criteria, and (3) ensure funding under the Act is spent in a coordinated manner with other local resources.</p> <p>Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to revise the purpose of grants for demonstration projects of innovative practices to require the projects to show the most promise of enabling the children served to meet rigorous, state-identified college and career readiness standards that address both certain academic content and certain career and technical education content.</p> <ul> <ul> </ul> </ul>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-10-24T18:19:21Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2014-06-24</actionDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <updateDate>2014-06-24T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <recordedVotes />
    <amendments />
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-06-24</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <actionDate>2014-06-24</actionDate>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Academic performance and assessments</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Census and government statistics</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Elementary and secondary education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Higher education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Personnel records</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Vocational and technical education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Wages and earnings</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Education</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

