<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees />
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2016-07-12T14:52:16Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2016-07-12</actionDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Alternatives to Licensing that Lower Obstacles to Work Act of 2016 or the ALLOW Act</b></p> <p>This bill declares, for purposes of establishing an individual's authorization to engage in an occupation on a military installation located on federally-owned land, that the federal government endorses occupational licenses and certifications granted by a state (including the District of Columbia [DC]), regardless of whether the installation is located in the issuing state or DC, provided that:</p> <ul> <li> the license or certification is not expired, revoked, or suspended by the issuing state; and</li> <li> there are no outstanding enforcement actions against the individual brought by the licensing board or certifying authority for that occupation in the issuing state.</li> </ul> <p><i>District of Columbia Occupational Licensing Reform Act</i></p> <p>The bill declares DC policy regarding occupational licensing laws.</p> <p>The bill establishes an Office of Supervision of Occupational Boards in the office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, or another appropriate DC government agency, to be responsible for exercising active supervision over each occupational licensing board to ensure compliance with occupational licensing policy.</p> <p>The bill prescribes procedures for the Office's review, approval, or rejection of occupational licensure actions before their adoption. </p> <p>The DC Council shall establish a legislative committee to analyze occupational regulations and review any proposed legislation to impose or modify an occupational regulation to ensure compliance.</p> <p>An individual may engage in a lawful occupation without being subject to occupational regulations that are arbitrary or unnecessary and substantially burdensome.</p> <p>The DC government and its boards may not require an occupational license, certification, or registration for a person, or impose any other occupational regulation that imposes a substantial burden on a person, unless:</p> <ul> <li> the government has an important interest in protecting against present and recognizable harm to public health, safety, or welfare; and</li> <li>the regulation is substantially related to achievement of that interest.</li> </ul> <p>Any person providing tour guide services for a fee at certain national parks and memorials shall not be required to obtain a license, certification, or permit to provide those services.</p>]]></text>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-12-28T17:18:34Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <updateDate>2016-07-12T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <introducedDate>2016-07-12</introducedDate>
    <updateDate>2016-12-31T09:52:34Z</updateDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000577</bioguideId>
        <lastName>Lee</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <firstName>Mike</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. Lee, Mike [R-UT]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <byRequestType />
        <state>UT</state>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2080</lisID>
          <bioguideId>L000577</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8303</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <firstName>Ben</firstName>
        <party>R</party>
        <lastName>Sasse</lastName>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>S001197</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <state>NE</state>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <fullName>Sen. Sasse, Ben  [R-NE]</fullName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2289</lisID>
          <bioguideId>S001197</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <billNumber>3158</billNumber>
    <createDate>2016-07-13T05:52:04Z</createDate>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
          <actionDate>2016-12-01</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>ALLOW Act</latestTitle>
        <type>HR</type>
        <number>6312</number>
        <congress>114</congress>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Commerce</name>
    </policyArea>
    <committeeReports />
    <laws />
    <title>ALLOW Act</title>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <notes />
    <congress>114</congress>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative remedies</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>District of Columbia</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Historic sites and heritage areas</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military facilities and property</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military history</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Monuments and memorials</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Parks, recreation areas, trails</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local government operations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Travel and tourism</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Commerce</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <amendments />
    <recordedVotes />
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2016-07-12</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>District of Columbia Occupational Licensing Reform Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>ALLOW Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Alternatives to Licensing that Lower Obstacles to Work Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to promote economic opportunity for military families, to facilitate workforce attachment for military spouses in their chosen occupation across multiple geographical postings, to reduce barriers to work on military installations, to amend the District of Columbia Code to promote greater freedom in the practice of regulated occupations, to combat abuse of occupational licensing laws by economic incumbents, to promote competition, encourage innovation, protect consumers, and promote compliance with Federal antitrust law, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>ALLOW Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-12</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-07-12</actionDate>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

