<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:26:52Z</updateDate>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 191.</text>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2013-09-18</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Environmental Protection</name>
    </policyArea>
    <laws />
    <introducedDate>2013-09-17</introducedDate>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <actionDate>2013-09-17</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2013-09-17T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-11-07T15:33:11Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Saving Coal Jobs Act of 2013 - Prohibits the head of a federal agency from promulgating any regulation relating to power sector carbon pollution standards or any substantially similar regulation on or after June 25, 2013, unless that regulation is explicitly authorized by Congress.</p> <p>Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act or CWA) to revise the National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System (NPDES) to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) or a state acting pursuant to an equivalent approved state program (permitting authority) to base a determination on approving a new or renewed permit covering discharges from a structure only on compliance with regulations issued by such permitting authority. Prohibits such permitting authority from basing such determination on the extent of the permit applicant's adherence to guidance issued by the Administrator, including: (1) the comprehensive guidance issued by the Administrator and dated April 1, 2010, (2) the proposed guidance entitled &quot;Draft Guidance on Identifying Waters Protected by the Clean Water Act&quot; and dated April 28, 2011, and (3) the final guidance proposed by the Administrator and dated July 21, 2011. Authorizes an applicant, if the permitting authority does not approve or deny an application for a new permit within 270 days after the date of receipt of an application, to operate as if the application were approved.</p> <p> Prohibits the Administrator from disapproving or withdrawing approval of a state permit program under NPDES based on: (1) the failure of such program to incorporate or comply with such guidance, or (2) the implementation of a water quality standard that has been adopted by the state and approved by the Administrator.</p> <p> Establishes environmental review requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) for permits to discharge dredged or fill material into navigable waters.</p> <p> Removes the authority of the EPA to prohibit the specification, or restrict the use, of an area as a disposal site for discharges of dredged or fill materials into waters of the United States once the Army Corps of Engineers has issued a permit for the discharge.</p> <p> Requires the Administrator: (1) before issuing a regulation, policy statement, guidance, response to a petition, or other requirement or implementing a new or substantially altered program under the CWA, to analyze the impact of such action on employment levels or economic activity in each state; and (2) upon concluding that such action will have more than a de minimis negative impact on employment levels or economic activity in a state, to hold a public hearing in each such state at least 30 days prior to the effective date of the action and to give notice of such impact to the state's congressional delegation, governor, and legislature at least 45 days before such effective date.</p> <p> Prohibits the Secretary of the Army and the Administrator from: (1) finalizing, adopting, implementing, administering, or enforcing the proposed guidance described in the notice of availability and request for comments entitled &quot;EPA and Army Corps of Engineers Guidance Regarding Identification of Waters Protected by the Clean Water Act&quot;; or (2) using such Guidance, or any substantially similar guidance made publicly available on or after December 3, 2008, as the basis for any decision regarding the scope of the CWA or any rulemaking. Provides that the use of such guidance as the basis for any rule shall be grounds for vacating such rule.</p> <p> Prohibits the Administrator from: (1)&nbsp;promulgating a&nbsp;revised or new water quality standard for a&nbsp;pollutant when&nbsp;the Administrator has approved&nbsp;a state water quality standard for&nbsp;such pollutant unless the state concurs with the Administrator's determination that the revised or new standard is necessary to meet CWA requirements; or (2) taking action to supersede a state's determination that a discharge will comply with effluent limitations, water quality standards, controls on the discharge of pollutants, and toxic and pretreatment effluent standards under the CWA.</p> Authorizes states to disregard, accept, or modify the Administrator's disagreement with, and recommendations for, a state's identification of: (1) waters as areas with insufficient controls, and (2) pollutants suitable for maximum daily load measurement.]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <recordedVotes />
    <notes />
    <billNumber>1514</billNumber>
    <committeeReports />
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <calendar>Senate Calendar of Business</calendar>
        <number>0191</number>
      </item>
      <item>
        <calendar>Senate Calendar of Business</calendar>
        <number />
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <amendments />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <createDate>2013-09-18T07:01:07Z</createDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Environmental Protection</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Army Corps of Engineers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Climate change and greenhouse gases</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Coal</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Defense</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Economic performance and conditions</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Electric power generation and transmission</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Environmental regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Hazardous wastes and toxic substances</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Intergovernmental relations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Mining</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public participation and lobbying</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Solid waste and recycling</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local government operations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Unemployment</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water quality</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>MCCONNELL</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1395</lisID>
          <bioguideId>M000355</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8254</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>MITCH</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. McConnell, Mitch [R-KY]</fullName>
        <bioguideId>M000355</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors />
    <title>Saving Coal Jobs Act of 2013</title>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-18</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 191.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-17</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>S6524-6527</name>
            <url>/congressional-record/2013/senate-section/page/S6524-6527</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time. (text of measure as introduced: CR S6524-6527)</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <actionDate>2013-09-17</actionDate>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <placedOnCalendarSection>2</placedOnCalendarSection>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>3</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <title>Saving Coal Jobs Act of 2013</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to save coal jobs, and for other purposes.</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Saving Coal Jobs Act of 2013</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestTitle>Coal Jobs Protection Act of 2014</latestTitle>
        <type>HR</type>
        <number>5077</number>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 449.</text>
          <actionDate>2014-09-18</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
      </item>
      <item>
        <latestTitle>Coal Jobs Protection Act of 2013</latestTitle>
        <type>HR</type>
        <number>1829</number>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
          <actionDate>2013-05-07</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
      </item>
      <item>
        <latestTitle>Clean Water Cooperative Federalism Act of 2013</latestTitle>
        <type>HR</type>
        <number>1948</number>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
          <actionDate>2013-05-14</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
      </item>
      <item>
        <latestTitle>A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to provide guidance and clarification regarding issuing new and renewal permits, and for other purposes.</latestTitle>
        <type>S</type>
        <number>861</number>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works. (text of measure as introduced: CR S3093-3096)</text>
          <actionDate>2013-05-06</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
      </item>
      <item>
        <latestTitle>National Energy Tax Repeal Act</latestTitle>
        <type>S</type>
        <number>1324</number>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
          <actionDate>2013-07-18</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees />
    </committees>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

