<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <title>United States Grain Standards Act Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
    <updateDate>2016-11-08T15:20:55Z</updateDate>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestTitle>Agriculture Reauthorizations Act of 2015</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <text>By Senator Roberts from Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry filed written report. Report No. 114-206.</text>
          <actionDate>2016-02-08</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <number>2051</number>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <type>HR</type>
        <congress>114</congress>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <introducedDate>2015-05-21</introducedDate>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <title>S. 1417, United States Grain Standards Act Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
        <pubDate>2015-06-04T21:27:55Z</pubDate>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/50271</url>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Agriculture and Food</name>
    </policyArea>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <billNumber>1417</billNumber>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <amendments />
    <recordedVotes />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
          <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Reported original measure</name>
              <date>2015-05-21T16:32:29Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <laws />
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Advisory bodies</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Agricultural practices and innovations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Agricultural trade</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Agriculture</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Free trade and trade barriers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Grain</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Intergovernmental relations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Navigation, waterways, harbors</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local government operations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>User charges and fees</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Washington State</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Agriculture and Food</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <notes />
    <committeeReports />
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>1</placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>
        <reportedToSenate>1</reportedToSenate>
        <originalBillReported>1</originalBillReported>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-05-21</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 90.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-05-21</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
          <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Roberts. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-05-21</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Roberts. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <links />
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
          <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-05-21</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>4</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <number>0090</number>
        <calendar>Senate Calendar of Business</calendar>
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2015-05-21</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 90.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
        <title>United States Grain Standards Act Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles Senate</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>United States Grain Standards Act Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>An original bill to reauthorize the United States Grain Standards Act, and for other purposes.</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>United States Grain Standards Act Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2015-05-21</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>United States Grain Standards Act Reauthorization Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>This bill reauthorizes and amends provisions of the United States Grain Standards Act. The Act authorizes the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish official marketing standards for grains, and to provide procedures for grain inspection and weighing. The bill reauthorizes several expiring provisions, establishes procedures in the event of an interruption of inspection and weighing services, revises the process for delegating inspections to state agencies, and revises fees for inspection and weighing services.</p> <p> The bill provides that transfers of grain into an export elevator by any mode of transportation are not required to be officially weighed. In the case of a disruption in official grain inspection or weighing services, the bill requires USDA to immediately take the actions necessary to address the disruption and resume services. </p> <p>The bill ends the permanent delegation to state agencies to carry out export inspection and weighing services. Every five years, USDA must certify that each state agency with a delegation of authority is meeting specified criteria.</p> <p>In order to review the performance of states, local agencies, and individuals that have applied to perform official inspections other than at export port locations, USDA must periodically consult with customers of the applicant. </p> <p>The bill extends the duration of licenses for inspectors from three to five years. Designations of official agencies terminate at a time specified by USDA that is no later than every five years. </p> <p>The bill changes the fee calculation for inspection and weighing services and extends the authority to collect fees through FY2020. </p> <p>The bill extends the limitation on total administrative and supervisory costs, the authorization of appropriations, and the authorization of the advisory committee through FY2020. </p> <p> USDA must report to Congress on the disruption in federal inspection of grain exports at the Port of Vancouver and policy barriers to grain producers. </p>]]></text>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-08-17T16:52:05Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <updateDate>2015-05-21T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
        <item>
          <versionCode>80</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2015-05-21</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>United States Grain Standards Act Reauthorization Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>This bill reauthorizes and amends provisions of the United States Grain Standards Act. The Act authorizes the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish official marketing standards for grains, and to provide procedures for grain inspection and weighing. The bill reauthorizes several expiring provisions through FY2020, establishes procedures in the event of an interruption of inspection and weighing services, revises the process for delegating inspections to state agencies, and revises fees for inspection and weighing services.</p> <p> (Sec. 2) The bill provides that transfers of grain into an export elevator by any mode of transportation are not required to be officially weighed. In the case of a disruption in official grain inspection or weighing services, the bill requires USDA to immediately take the actions necessary to address the disruption and resume services. USDA must also report to Congress on the disruption and provide daily updates until services have resumed. </p> <p>The bill ends the permanent delegation to state agencies to carry out export inspection and weighing services. Every five years, USDA must certify that each state agency with a delegation of authority is meeting specified criteria. The certification process must include public notice and a comment period. State agencies that have been delegated authority and intend to temporarily discontinue official inspection or weighing services, except in the case of a major disaster, must notify USDA in advance. </p> <p>In order to review the performance of states, local agencies, and individuals that have applied to perform official inspections other than at export port locations, USDA must periodically consult with customers of the applicant and work with the applicant to address any concerns. </p> <p>The bill extends the duration of licenses for inspectors from three to five years. Designations of official agencies terminate at a time specified by USDA that is no later than every five years. </p> <p>The bill changes the fee calculation for inspection and weighing services and extends the authority to collect fees through FY2020. </p> <p>The bill extends the limitation on total administrative and supervisory costs, the authorization of appropriations, and the authorization of the advisory committee through FY2020. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) USDA must report to Congress on the disruption in federal inspection of grain exports at the Port of Vancouver in the summer of 2014. The report must include factors that led or contributed to the disruption and changes in policy USDA has implemented to ensure that a similar disruptions does not occur in the future. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) USDA must report to Congress on policy barriers to U.S. grain producers in countries that: (1) produce grain that receives official grading in the United States, and (2) do not offer official grading for U.S. grain or provide only the lowest designation for U.S. grain. </p>]]></text>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-08-17T16:54:06Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Reported to Senate without amendment</actionDesc>
          <name>Reported to Senate without amendment</name>
          <updateDate>2015-05-21T17:13:16Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <createDate>2015-05-22T13:34:49Z</createDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <state>KS</state>
        <fullName>Sen. Roberts, Pat [R-KS]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>R000307</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8275</gpoId>
          <lisID>968</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>PAT</firstName>
        <lastName>ROBERTS</lastName>
        <bioguideId>R000307</bioguideId>
        <byRequestType />
        <party>R</party>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

