<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <laws />
    <recordedVotes />
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <prayer>1</prayer>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>5</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-05-24</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
          <name>Water, Power and Oceans Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-05-16</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
          <name>Water, Power and Oceans Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-05-12</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-05-12</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-05-12</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <billNumber>5217</billNumber>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Water Resources Development</name>
    </policyArea>
    <notes />
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-05-24</actionDate>
      <links />
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestTitle>San Luis Unit Drainage Resolution Act</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
          <actionDate>2016-05-24</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <number>4366</number>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <type>HR</type>
        <congress>114</congress>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2016-05-12T14:03:20Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
              <name>Water, Power and Oceans Subcommittee</name>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Hearings by</name>
                  <date>2016-05-24T18:36:45Z</date>
                </item>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2016-05-16T21:46:06Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <cosponsors />
    <createDate>2016-05-13T05:18:13Z</createDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Rep. Costa, Jim [D-CA-16]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jim</firstName>
        <lastName>Costa</lastName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>16</district>
        <bioguideId>C001059</bioguideId>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>C001059</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7825</gpoId>
          <lisID>1774</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName />
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <committeeReports />
    <updateDate>2016-11-02T22:44:20Z</updateDate>
    <introducedDate>2016-05-12</introducedDate>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2016-05-12T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>San Luis Unit Drainage Resolution Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of the Interior to implement the Agreement between the United States and Westlands Water District August 2015 (Westlands Agreement) and the Agreement between Interior and the San Luis Water District, the Panoche Water District, and the Pacheco Water District (Northerly Districts Agreement).</p> <p>The bill amends the San Luis Act (the 1960 statute that authorized Interior to construct the San Luis Unit of the Central Valley Project (CVP), California) to: (1) repeal provisions that include distribution systems and drains as features of such unit, and (2) eliminate requirements for Interior to meet drainage requirements for such unit. Each contractor within the unit that receives water for irrigation shall be responsible for the management of drainage water within its boundaries. </p> <p>Each San Luis Unit Contractor (i.e., the Westlands Water District, San Luis Water District, Panoche Water District, and Pacheco Water District) shall assume all legal responsibility for the management of drainage water within, and shall not discharge drain water outside of, its boundaries.</p> <p>Interior shall: </p> <ul> <li>convert each San Luis Unit Contractor's existing long-term or interim renewal water service contract to a repayment contract;</li> <li>make allocation decisions in the CVP consistent with federal law and all decisions of the California State Water Resources Control Board establishing conditions on applicable licenses and permits for the CVP, and </li> <li>enter into a contract with the Navy for the delivery of CVP water to the Lemoore Naval Air Station. </li> </ul> <p>The bill suspends each San Luis Unit Contractor's capital repayment obligation and payments under its water service contracts and the April 1, 1965, repayment contract with the United States until the execution of a repayment contract under this bill, after which each contractor shall: (1) receive a specified credit against future operation and maintenance costs payable to the United States, and (2) be relieved of capital repayment obligations under specified water service contracts.</p> <p>CVP construction costs or other capitalized costs allocated to the Westlands Water District after the date of the Westlands Agreement shall be repaid within five years after notification of the allocation of less than $5 million. If the amount allocated is $5 million or greater, such cost shall be repaid as provided by applicable reclamation law. CVP construction costs or other capitalized costs allocated to any of the Northerly San Luis Unit Districts after the date of the Northerly District Agreement shall be repaid as provided by applicable reclamation law.</p> <p>Interior is authorized to provide financial assistance as specified in the Northerly District Agreement, which shall be non-reimbursable.</p> <p>The bill requires Interior to transfer title to specified facilities to the San Luis Unit Contractors upon the execution of the repayment contracts under this bill, consistent with all applicable reclamation policies and procedures. Interior and the San Luis Unit Contractor or other entity acquiring title shall comply with all applicable requirements under federal and California law before facility title is transferred.</p>    <p>For any year in which the allocation for south-of-Delta CVP long-term water irrigation service contractors or irrigation repayment contractors is greater than 75%, Interior shall calculate for the Westlands Water District a per acre foot Restoration Fund payment based on a projection that such District would take delivery of the full allocation.</p>]]></text>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-08-23T21:05:29Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2016-05-12</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <title>San Luis Unit Drainage Resolution Act</title>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>California</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Dams and canals</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Farmland</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military facilities and property</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water resources funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water use and supply</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Water Resources Development</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <amendments />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <congress>114</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. COSTA:H.R. 5217.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 18 of the Constitution of theUnited States[Page H2342]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>San Luis Unit Drainage Resolution Act</title>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>To affirm "The Agreement Between the United States and Westlands Water District" dated September 15, 2015, "The Agreement Between the United States, San Luis Water District, Panoche Water District and Pacheco Water District", and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>San Luis Unit Drainage Resolution Act</title>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

