<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <number>0470</number>
        <calendar>Senate Calendar of Business</calendar>
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <billNumber>1724</billNumber>
    <updateDate>2016-12-15T21:31:17Z</updateDate>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-05-18</actionDate>
      <links />
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 470.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <recordedVotes />
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 114-256</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>Heller</lastName>
        <firstName>Dean</firstName>
        <bioguideId>H001041</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Heller, Dean [R-NV]</fullName>
        <state>NV</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>H001041</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1863</lisID>
          <gpoId>8060</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <byRequestType />
        <middleName />
        <party>R</party>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <amendments />
    <createDate>2015-07-10T09:26:21Z</createDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Environmental Protection</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>California</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Lakes and rivers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Land transfers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Nevada</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water quality</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <title>S. 1724, Lake Tahoe Restoration Act of 2015</title>
        <pubDate>2016-05-18T11:25:01Z</pubDate>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/51587</url>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <introducedDate>2015-07-09</introducedDate>
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>6</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <reportedToSenate>2</reportedToSenate>
        <placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>1</placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <orderedReported>1</orderedReported>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-05-18</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 470.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-05-18</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
          <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe with an amendment. With written report No. 114-256.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
          <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe with an amendment. With written report No. 114-256.</text>
        <links />
        <actionDate>2016-05-18</actionDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-01-20</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
          <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-07-09</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
          <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <links />
        <actionDate>2015-07-09</actionDate>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <laws />
    <title>Lake Tahoe Restoration Act of 2015</title>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Environmental Protection</name>
    </policyArea>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Reported by</name>
              <date>2016-05-18T19:00:04Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Markup by</name>
              <date>2016-01-20T15:08:34Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2015-07-09T15:33:58Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
          <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <type>HR</type>
        <number>3692</number>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
          <actionDate>2015-10-26</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>Lake Tahoe Restoration Act of 2015</latestTitle>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>S</type>
        <number>2848</number>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionTime>16:11:15</actionTime>
          <text>Held at the desk.</text>
          <actionDate>2016-09-19</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>Water Resources Development Act of 2016</latestTitle>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>S</type>
        <number>612</number>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Presented to President.</text>
          <actionDate>2016-12-14</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>WIIN Act</latestTitle>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <notes />
    <billType>S</billType>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles Senate</parentTitleType>
        <title>Lake Tahoe Restoration Act of 2015</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Lake Tahoe Restoration Act of 2015</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>A bill to provide for environmental restoration activities and forest management activities in the Lake Tahoe Basin, and for other purposes.</title>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Lake Tahoe Restoration Act of 2015</title>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>REID</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8271</gpoId>
          <lisID>952</lisID>
          <bioguideId>R000146</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-07-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <firstName>HARRY</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. Reid, Harry [D-NV]</fullName>
        <state>NV</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <bioguideId>R000146</bioguideId>
        <middleName>M.</middleName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
      </item>
      <item>
        <lastName>BOXER</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>116</lisID>
          <bioguideId>B000711</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8306</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-07-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <firstName>BARBARA</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. Boxer, Barbara [D-CA]</fullName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <bioguideId>B000711</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
      </item>
      <item>
        <lastName>FEINSTEIN</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8338</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>F000062</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1332</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-07-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <firstName>DIANNE</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. Feinstein, Dianne [D-CA]</fullName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <bioguideId>F000062</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <updateDate>2015-07-09T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Lake Tahoe Restoration Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>This bill revises and reauthorizes the Lake Tahoe Restoration Act for 10 fiscal years after the enactment of this bill. </p> <p>The bill adds requirements for the management of the Lake Tahoe Basin Management Unit, including requiring the U.S. Forest Service to: </p> <ul> <li>coordinate with the Environmental Protection Agency and state and local entities in managing the Basin; </li> <li>conduct forest management activities in the Basin in a manner that attains multiple ecosystem benefits, unless such activities would excessively increase the cost of any project; and </li> <li>establish and monitor post-program ground condition criteria for ground disturbance caused by forest management activities. </ul> <p>The Forest Service may enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with governmental and other public and private entities to provide for fuel reduction, erosion control, reforestation, restoration, and similar activities in the Basin. </p> <p>The bill mandates priority programs in the Basin, including programs for fire risk reduction and forest management, invasive species management, and stormwater management. <p>The bill requires relevant federal and state agencies, including the Tahoe Regional Planning Agency, and the states of California and Nevada, to develop and update an integrated multiagency assessment and monitoring plan to measure the effectiveness of the Agency's Environmental Improvement Program.        <p>The bill amends the Santini-Burton Act to authorize: (1) a donation from California to the Forest Service of lands administered by its agencies, and (2) a transfer from the Forest Service to Nevada of certain lands in the Basin.</p>]]></text>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-09-08T14:51:22Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2015-07-09</actionDate>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Reported to Senate amended</name>
          <actionDesc>Reported to Senate amended</actionDesc>
          <updateDate>2016-05-18T16:29:01Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>01</versionCode>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Lake Tahoe Restoration Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>This bill revises and reauthorizes the Lake Tahoe Restoration Act for 10 fiscal years after the bill's enactment. </p> <p>(Sec. 2) The bill amends the findings and purposes of the Lake Tahoe Restoration Act to include relevant findings since its enactment in 2000, including references to the 2011 and 2012 Lake Tahoe Forums and updated levels of support provided by public and private entities to the Lake Tahoe Basin since 1997. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill adds definitions, including &quot;Environmental Improvement Program&quot; as the program adopted by the Tahoe Regional Planning Agency and &quot;forest management activity&quot; to mean: (1) prescribed burning for ecosystem health and hazardous fuels reduction, (2) mechanical and minimum tool treatment, (3) stream environment zone restoration and other watershed and wildlife habitat enhancements, and (4) other activities consistent with practices of the Forest Service of the Department of Agriculture. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill adds additional requirements for the management of the Lake Tahoe Basin Management Unit, including by requiring the Forest Service to: </p> <ul> <li>coordinate with the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) and state, local, and private entities, including local fire departments and volunteer groups; </li> <li>conduct forest management activities in the Basin in a manner that helps achieve and maintain the environmental threshold carrying capacities established by the Tahoe Regional Planning Agency and that attains multiple ecosystem benefits, unless such activities would excessively increase the cost of a program; and </li> <li>establish and monitor post-program ground condition criteria for ground disturbance caused by forest management activities. </li> </ul>   <p>Subject to valid existing rights, the federal land located in the Basin is withdrawn from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under all laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing. A land conveyance is exempt from the withdrawal if it is carried out under the Lake Tahoe Restoration Act or the Santini-Burton Act. </p> <p>The Lake Tahoe Basin Management Unit must support the attainment of the environmental threshold carrying capacities established by the Planning Agency.</p> <p>The Forest Service may enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with public and private entities to provide for fuel reduction, erosion control, reforestation, Stream Environment Zone restoration, and similar management activities on federal and nonfederal land within programs in the Basin. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) The bill mandates and funds priority programs in the Basin, including programs for fire risk reduction and forest management, invasive species management, stormwater management, erosion projects, and for the Lahontan Cutthroat Trout Recovery Program. </p> <p>The bill imposes civil penalties up to $1,000 for launching a boat that is not decontaminated to prevent the spread of invasive species.       <p>(Sec. 6) The bill authorizes the Army Civil Works Division to enter into interagency agreements with nonfederal interests in the Basin to provide technical assistance for the Environmental Improvement Program. </p> <p>The Forest Service, the EPA, the Fish and Wildlife Service, and the U.S. Geological Survey, in coordination with the Tahoe Regional Planning Agency and the states of California and Nevada, must develop and implement a plan for monitoring, assessment, and research to evaluate the effectiveness of the Environmental Improvement Program. <p>The bill requires reporting on the status of all programs authorized by this bill. </p> <p>The President must submit information as part of the President's annual budget about each federal agency involved in the Environmental Improvement Program. <p>(Sec. 8) The Forest Service must reimburse two-thirds of the costs incurred by local utility districts for relocating facilities in connection with environmental restoration programs under this bill and erosion control programs.</p> <p>A program provided assistance under this bill shall include signage at the program site that informs the public about the amount of federal funds being provided to the program and that displays the visual identity mark of the EPA.    <p>(Sec. 9) The bill amends the Santini-Burton Act to authorize: (1) a donation from the California Tahoe Conservancy and the California Department of Parks and Recreation to the Forest Service of 1,981 acres of land administered by the Conservancy and 187 acres of land administered by California State Parks; and (2) a transfer from the Forest Service to Nevada of 38.68 acres of land known as the Van Sickle Unit USFS Inholding and 92.28 acres of land known as the Lake Tahoe Nevada State Park USFS Inholding.</p>]]></text>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-09-12T16:07:48Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2016-05-18</actionDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

