<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-03-28</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <number>1230</number>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestTitle>Molalla River Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</latestTitle>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-03-26</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <number>1215</number>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestTitle>Chetco River Protection Act of 2013</latestTitle>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-06-28</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <number>2488</number>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestTitle>Rogue Wilderness Area Expansion Act</latestTitle>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/44440</url>
        <pubDate>2013-07-22T16:45:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 353, Oregon Treasures Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/44440</url>
        <pubDate>2013-07-22T16:45:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 353, Oregon Treasures Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <laws />
    <billNumber>353</billNumber>
    <notes />
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-09-10</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 178.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:21:02Z</updateDate>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <calendar>Senate Calendar of Business</calendar>
        <number>0178</number>
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <title>Oregon Treasures Act of 2013</title>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles Senate</parentTitleType>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Oregon Treasures Act of 2013</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to designate certain land in the State of Oregon as wilderness, to make additional wild and scenic river designations in the State of Oregon, and for other purposes.</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Oregon Treasures Act of 2013</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <title>Oregon Treasures Act of 2013</title>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 113-100</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000779</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Wyden, Ron [D-OR]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>W000779</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1247</lisID>
          <gpoId>8265</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <byRequestType />
        <middleName />
        <firstName>RON</firstName>
        <lastName>WYDEN</lastName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <introducedDate>2013-02-14</introducedDate>
    <createDate>2013-02-15T07:00:53Z</createDate>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Hearings by</name>
                  <date>2013-04-25T20:33:43Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
              <systemCode>sseg03</systemCode>
              <name>Public Lands, Forests, and Mining Subcommittee</name>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Reported by</name>
              <date>2013-09-10T22:29:35Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Markup by</name>
              <date>2013-06-18T19:31:13Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2013-02-14T20:47:22Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>Jeff</firstName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1900</lisID>
          <gpoId>8238</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>M001176</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>M001176</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Merkley, Jeff [D-OR]</fullName>
        <lastName>Merkley</lastName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-02-14</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Oregon Treasures Act of 2013 - Designates specified Bureau of Land Management (BLM) land in Oregon as potential wilderness areas. </p> <p>Provides for the designation of such areas, to be known as the Cathedral Rock Wilderness and the Horse Heaven Wilderness, as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. </p> <p>Authorizes certain land exchanges with specified landowners. </p> <p> Adds specified federal land managed by the BLM in the Wild Rogue Wilderness as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System. </p> <p>Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (the Act) to add specified segments of creeks to the designation of the Rogue River in Oregon as a component of the national wild and scenic rivers system. </p> <p>Prohibits: (1) the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) from licensing the construction of any dam, conduit, reservoir, powerhouse, transmission line, or other project works affecting specified stream segments; and (2) any federal department or agency from assisting in the construction of any water resources project affecting any such segment, except for maintaining or repairing existing projects. </p> <p> Amends the Act <times/> <times/> to designate specified segments of the Molalla River in Oregon as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. </p> <p>Amends the Act to rename the Squaw Creek in Oregon as Whychus Creek. <times/> <times/> <p> Amends the Act to make corrections to the segment designations for the Chetco River, Oregon, including revising segment lengths.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-03-14T18:33:18Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2013-02-14</actionDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <updateDate>2013-02-14T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Oregon Treasures Act of 2013 - (Sec. 2) Authorizes certain land exchanges with specified landowners (Smith, Shrum, and Young Life) for the benefit of the Cathedral Rock and Horse Heaven Wildernesses designated under this Act.</p> <p>Requires each land exchange to be carried out in accordance with the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, including the requirement that the Secretary of the Interior determine that the public interest will be well served by making the exchange. </p> <p>Subjects each such exchange to valid existing rights and the conditions that: (1) the owner make the offer to convey all or part of the non-federal land during the three-year period following enactment of this Act; (3) the owner of the non-federal land pay at least half of all costs relating to the land exchange; (4) title to the non-federal land be acceptable to the Secretary and in conformance with the title approval standards applicable to Federal land acquisitions; and (5) any sites on the federal land that are eligible for inclusion in the National Register of Historic Places shall not be included in the exchange, with any exclusion of land limited to the smallest area necessary. </p> <p>Requires the value of the federal and non-federal land in each land exchange: (1) to be equal, as determined by appraisals; or (2) if not equal, then equalized by making a cash equalization payment to the Secretary or to the owner, as appropriate, or by reducing the acreage of the federal land or non-federal land to be exchanged. </p> <p>Requires any cash equalization payments received by the Secretary to be deposited in the Federal Land Disposal Account established by the Federal Land Transaction Facilitation Act and used in accordance with that Act.</p> <p>Expresses the intent of Congress that these land exchanges be completed within five years after enactment of this Act. </p> <p>Transfers from the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) of the Department of the Interior to the Forest Service of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) the administrative jurisdiction over a approximately 750 acres of specified federal land, any related costs to be paid by the Secretary of Agriculture. </p> <p> Requires the designation of specified federal land, by a date certain contingencies occur, as the Cathedral Rock Wilderness and the Horse Heaven Wilderness in the National Wilderness Preservation System. </p> <p>Permits grazing in the designated wilderness areas to continue if already established. </p> <p>Prohibits anything in these designations from altering, modifying, enlarging, diminishing, or abrogating the treaty rights of any Indian tribe, including the off-reservation reserved rights secured by a specified treaty. </p> <p>Prohibits anything in these designations from affecting the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the state of Oregon respecting fish and wildlife. </p> <p>Prohibits anything in these designations from creating any protective perimeter or buffer zone around the designated wilderness areas.</p>  <p>Authorizes access to the Cathedral Rock Wilderness from Muddy Creek Road on terms acceptable to Jefferson County, Oregon, and the owners of the applicable non-federal land. </p> <p>Requires the federal land within each wilderness area, before its designation, to be managed in a manner that: (1) protects cultural and archaeological resources, and (2) maintains the suitability of the area for designation as wilderness.</p>  <p>Terminates authority for designation and interim management of the Cathedral Rock Wilderness and the Horse Heaven Wilderness if they are not designated as wilderness within ten years after enactment of this Act.</p> <p> (Sec. 3) Adds specified federal land in Oregon to the Wild Rogue Wilderness, except that the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior shall administer the land under their respective jurisdictions. </p>  <p>Adds also to the Wild Rogue Wilderness certain public land in Oregon administered by the Secretary of the Interior as potential wilderness. </p>     <p>Allows such federal land to be used only for recreational, scenic, and scientific purposes and bars its use for permanent roads, commercial enterprises, and, except as necessary to meet minimum administrative and public health and safety requirements, the use of motor vehicles or the establishment of temporary roads. </p>  <p>Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (the Act) to add specified segments of certain creeks to the designation of the Rogue River in Oregon as a component of the national wild and scenic rivers system.</p>   <p>Prohibits: (1) the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) from licensing the construction of any dam, water conduit, reservoir, powerhouse, transmission line, or other project works affecting specified stream segments; and (2) any federal department or agency from assisting in the construction of any water resources project affecting any such segment, except to maintain or repair existing projects.</p> <p>States that nothing prohibits any federal department or agency from assisting in a water resources project: (1) the primary purpose of which is ecological or aquatic restoration, and (2) that provides a net benefit to water quality and aquatic resources. </p>  <p>(Sec. 4) Amends the Act <times/> <times/> to designate specified segments of the Molalla River in Oregon as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</p>  <p>Renames the Squaw Creek in Oregon as Whychus Creek.]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Reported to Senate amended</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-11-05T21:30:51Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <versionCode>01</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2013-09-10</actionDate>
          <name>Reported to Senate amended</name>
          <updateDate>2013-09-10T13:02:29Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <recordedVotes />
    <amendments />
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-10</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 178.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-10</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>report No. 113-100</name>
            <url>/congressional-report/113th-congress/senate-report/100</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Wyden with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-100.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2013-09-10</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>report No. 113-100</name>
            <url>/congressional-report/113th-congress/senate-report/100</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Wyden with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-100.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-06-18</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-04-25</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sseg03</systemCode>
          <name>Public Lands, Forests, and Mining Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-28.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-02-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2013-02-14</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>S780-782</name>
            <url>/congressional-record/2013/senate-section/page/S780-782</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S780-782)</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2013-02-14</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>7</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>1</placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>
        <placeholderTextForB>1</placeholderTextForB>
        <reportedToSenate>2</reportedToSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <hearingsHeld>1</hearingsHeld>
        <orderedReported>1</orderedReported>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Dams and canals</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Electric power generation and transmission</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Lakes and rivers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Land transfers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Oregon</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water storage</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

