<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <introducedDate>2015-01-07</introducedDate>
    <recordedVotes />
    <createDate>2015-01-08T02:24:27Z</createDate>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2015-01-07T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-01-21T17:34:10Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <actionDate>2015-01-07</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stopping Illegal Obamacare Subsidies Act </b></p> <p> Prohibits American Health Benefit Exchanges from providing for automatic enrollment in health plans until the Inspector General (IG) of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) verifies that each state exchange and the federal exchange established under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) have resolved the inconsistencies outlined in the June 14 IG report.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of HHS to make public the steps that the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) and the federal exchange will take to clear any inconsistencies that arose on or before the enactment of this Act and to ensure that the systems used by the CMS to determine or assess eligibility for premium tax credits, cost-sharing reductions, Medicaid under title XIX of the Social Security Act (SSAct), and the State Children's Health Insurance Program under SSAct title XXI can resolve such inconsistencies within 30 days after enactment of this Act.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to make public the methods that the CMS use to monitor, track, and measure the progress of the federal and state exchanges in resolving inconsistencies.</p> <p>Suspends for plan year 2015 the availability of premium assistance tax credits and the reduced cost-sharing program under PPACA; and allows them to resume only after the Commissioner of the Social Security Administration declares affirmatively that all inconsistencies related to invalid Social Security numbers have been resolved, and the IG determines that this is so.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to request additional information from any applicant for a qualified health plan on a state or federal exchange whose information contains inconsistencies. Requires the applicant to: (1) be withdrawn from the premium assistance credit and reduced cost-sharing programs if the additional information is not provided within 90 days, and (2) re-enroll in a qualified health plan with appropriate and accurate information during the next open enrollment period.</p>]]></text>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <committeeReports />
    <notes />
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2015-01-07</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <state>LA</state>
        <fullName>Sen. Vitter, David [R-LA]</fullName>
        <firstName>David</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>V000127</bioguideId>
        <lastName>Vitter</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8267</gpoId>
          <lisID>1609</lisID>
          <bioguideId>V000127</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <billNumber>118</billNumber>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Stopping Illegal Obamacare Subsidies Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to address certain inconsistencies between the self-attested information provided by an applicant in enrolling a health plan on an Exchange and being determined eligible for premium tax credits and cost-sharing reductions or in being determined to be eligible for enrollment in a State Medicaid plan or a State child health plan under the State Children's Health Insurance Program and the data received through the Federal Data Services Hub or from other data sources.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Stopping Illegal Obamacare Subsidies Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <title>Stopping Illegal Obamacare Subsidies Act</title>
    <laws />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees />
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2015-01-07T22:56:54Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
          <name>Finance Committee</name>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <updateDate>2016-11-02T23:17:46Z</updateDate>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestTitle>Stopping Illegal Obamacare Subsidies Act</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
          <actionDate>2015-01-07</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <number>42</number>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <type>S</type>
        <congress>114</congress>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Health</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Child health</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Comprehensive health care</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health care costs and insurance</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health care coverage and access</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Income tax credits</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Medicaid</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-07</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Finance Committee</name>
          <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-07</actionDate>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <amendments />
    <congress>114</congress>
    <cosponsors />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

