<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Strong Forests Grow Strong Communities Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To require the Forest Service to meet annual volume targets for timber harvesting in the management of a unit of the National Forest System and to provide for the transfer of such management responsibility to the State in which the unit is located when such targets are not consistently met, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Strong Forests Grow Strong Communities Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <introducedDate>2014-05-01</introducedDate>
    <notes />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <name>Agriculture Committee</name>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2014-06-03T20:32:51Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
              <systemCode>hsag15</systemCode>
              <name>Conservation and Forestry Subcommittee</name>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hsag00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-05-01T13:01:50Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>Duffy</lastName>
        <middleName>P.</middleName>
        <bioguideId>D000614</bioguideId>
        <firstName>Sean</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <fullName>Rep. Duffy, Sean P. [R-WI-7]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8220</gpoId>
          <lisID>2072</lisID>
          <bioguideId>D000614</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Endangered and threatened species</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Intergovernmental relations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local government operations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Wildlife conservation and habitat protection</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <createDate>2014-05-02T07:23:17Z</createDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <recordedVotes />
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-06-03</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsag15</systemCode>
          <name>Conservation and Forestry Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsag00</systemCode>
          <name>Agriculture Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2014-05-01</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2014-05-01</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2014-05-01</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>4</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-05-13T16:41:13Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Strong Forests Grow Strong Communities Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to publish in the Federal Register and make available on the Forest Service website, the annual volume requirement for each unit of the National Forest System (NFS). Defines the &quot;annual volume requirement&quot; for an NFS unit as a volume of national forest materials (trees, portions of trees, or forest products from NFS lands) that is at least 50% of the unit's sustained yield. Prohibits the Secretary from reducing the annual volume requirement for a unit without the consent of a new Act of Congress.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to manage the sale of national forest materials in each NFS unit in the manner necessary so that the annual volume requirement for that unit is met each calendar year. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary, if a sale of national forest materials may affect the continued existence of any endangered or threatened species, to issue a determination explaining the view that the proposed sale is not likely to jeopardize the continued existence of that species. </p> <p>Authorizes the state in which an NFS unit is located, if the Secretary fails to meet the annual volume requirement for that unit for five calendar years, whether consecutively or over a longer than five-year period, to request a cooperative agreement with the Secretary for purposes of managing the unit. Permits a state that undertakes the management of an NFS unit to conduct the management directly, through an agreement with a political subdivision of the state, or through contracts with third parties. Limits a state's request to only those NFS lands of a unit located in the state if the unit covers more than one state. </p> <p>Declares that state environmental, wildlife, and land management laws shall supercede federal environmental, wildlife, and management laws on an NSF unit managed by a state under a cooperative agreement in place pursuant to this Act.</p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2014-05-01T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2014-05-01</actionDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. DUFFY:H.R. 4549.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article IV, Section III, Clause II``The Congress shall have Power to dispose of and make allneedful Rules and Regulations respecting the Territory orother Property belonging to the United States; and nothing inthis Constitution shall be so construed as to Prejudice anyClaims of the United States, or of any particular State.''[Page H3408]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <relatedBills />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:12:49Z</updateDate>
    <cosponsors />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <latestAction>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <actionDate>2014-06-03</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <committeeReports />
    <title>Strong Forests Grow Strong Communities Act of 2014</title>
    <amendments />
    <laws />
    <billNumber>4549</billNumber>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

