<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-01-22</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <type>HR</type>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <number>3697</number>
        <latestTitle>Adult Education and Economic Growth Act</latestTitle>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Labor and Employment</name>
    </policyArea>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <laws />
    <billNumber>1400</billNumber>
    <notes />
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-07-30</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:26:25Z</updateDate>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Adult Education and Economic Growth Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to increase access to adult education to provide for economic growth.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Adult Education and Economic Growth Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <title>Adult Education and Economic Growth Act</title>
    <committeeReports />
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000122</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Reed, Jack [D-RI]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>R000122</bioguideId>
          <lisID>949</lisID>
          <gpoId>8272</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <byRequestType />
        <middleName>F.</middleName>
        <firstName>JOHN</firstName>
        <lastName>REED</lastName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <introducedDate>2013-07-30</introducedDate>
    <createDate>2013-07-31T15:52:22Z</createDate>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <name>Finance Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2013-07-30T22:41:10Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>B000944</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Brown, Sherrod [D-OH]</fullName>
        <lastName>BROWN</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>136</lisID>
          <bioguideId>B000944</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8309</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-30</sponsorshipDate>
        <firstName>SHERROD</firstName>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-11-05T17:24:45Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Adult Education and Economic Growth Act - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1988 to revise requirements for statewide and local workforce investment systems to include adult education activities.</p> <p>Replaces statewide and local workforce investment systems with adult education and workforce investment systems.</p> <p>Revises member composition of: (1) state workforce investment boards to include the lead state agency officials with particular responsibility for implementing adult education and literacy activities; and (2) youth councils established by local workforce investment boards to include representatives of adult education.</p> <p>Revises requirements for five-year state and local worker investment plans.</p> <p>Authorizes the use of funds for: (1) statewide and local youth activities to provide opportunities for multiple career pathways for eligible youth, and (2) training services for local adult and dislocated workers to include integrated education and training and career pathway services.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Labor to carry out specified employment and training demonstration and pilot projects. </p> <p>Amends the Adult Education and Family Literacy Act (AEFLA) to include among adult education and literacy services programs activities to assist adults with limited English proficiency to improve their English and mathematical skills, acquire an understanding of the American system of government and responsibilities of citizenship, and, where necessary, obtain knowledge and skills to transition to postsecondary education, job training, and employment in family-sustaining jobs.</p> <p>Revises requirements for the allocation and reservation of AEFLA funds.</p> <p>Revises state distribution requirements with respect to grants and contracts to eligible providers of activities for adult education and literacy and corrections education of institutionalized individuals.</p> <p>Expands an eligible agency's use of funds for corrections education and education for other institutionalized individuals to include academic programs for: (1) integrated education and training and sequential education and training programs, (2) career pathways, (3) dual enrollment, and (4) preparation for postsecondary education and training.</p> <p>Replaces the National Institute for Literacy with the National Center for Adult Education, Literacy, and Workplace Skills (Center).</p> <p>Requires national leadership activities to include activities to improve workplace skills programs nationwide.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Education to allocate grants to states for integrated English literacy and civics education programs.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Education to award grants to assist states in developing a 21st century delivery system for adult education, literacy, and workplace skills services as well as adults in developing digital literacy skills.</p> <p>Requires the Center to establish the National Adult Learning and Technology Resource Clearinghouse.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Education to direct the Commissioner for Education Research of the National Center for Education Research to establish a national research and development center for adult education, literacy, and workplace skills.</p> <p>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an employer educational assistance program credit for 50% of the qualified educational assistance expenses (up to $5,250) paid per taxable year on behalf of an employee.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2013-07-30</actionDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2013-07-30T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <recordedVotes />
    <amendments />
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <placeholderTextForB>1</placeholderTextForB>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-30</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Finance Committee</name>
          <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2013-07-30</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6077-6078)</text>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>S6077-6078</name>
            <url>/congressional-record/2013/senate-section/page/S6077-6078</url>
          </link>
        </links>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2013-07-30</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <links />
      </item>
    </actions>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Labor and Employment</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Adult education and literacy</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Citizenship and naturalization</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Correctional facilities and imprisonment</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Education programs funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Educational technology and distance education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Elementary and secondary education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Employee benefits and pensions</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Employment and training programs</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Foreign language and bilingual programs</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Higher education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Income tax credits</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Performance measurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public-private cooperation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Research administration and funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Research and development</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Teaching, teachers, curricula</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Youth employment and child labor</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

