<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees />
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2016-06-14T19:31:40Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <subcommittees />
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2016-06-13T20:22:20Z</date>
              <name>Reported by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2016-05-24T14:02:10Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <title>H.R. 5312, Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Modernization Act of 2016</title>
        <pubDate>2016-06-13T15:14:06Z</pubDate>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/51686</url>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2016-05-24</actionDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <updateDate>2016-05-24T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-06-06T18:30:02Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Modernization Act of 2016</b> </p> <p> This bill amends the High-Performance Computing Act of 1991 to rename the National High-Performance Computing Program as the Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Program. </p> <p>The Program, in addition to its current requirements, shall:</p> <ul> <li>conduct or arrange for research and development on human-computer interactions, visualization, and big data, as well as the enhancement of cybersecurity; and</li> <li>create a research framework to leverage cyber-physical systems, high capacity and high speed communication networks, and large-scale data analytics to integrate city-scale information technology and physical infrastructures. </li> </ul>   <p> Participating federal agencies, working through the National Science and Technology Council, shall develop, and update every five years, a strategic plan for the Program. </p> <p> The bill replaces the National Research and Education Network with a National Coordination Office, which the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall maintain, and which shall give technical and administrative support to participating federal agencies.</p> <p>The bill repeals the authorization for a Next Generation Internet program.</p> <p>The Program shall encourage participating agencies to support large-scale, long-term, interdisciplinary research and development activities in networking and information technology directed toward agency mission areas that have the potential for significant contributions to national economic competitiveness and for other significant societal benefits.</p> <p>The National Coordination Office may conduct workshops and other activities on research areas of emerging importance.</p> <p>The National Science Foundation, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), the Department of Energy, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Department of Education shall each engage in specified research and development activities in conjunction with the Program. </p>]]></text>
        </item>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2016-06-13</actionDate>
          <name>Passed House amended</name>
          <updateDate>2016-06-13T14:00:27Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>36</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-06-29T16:35:14Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Passed House amended</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Modernization Act of 2016</b> </p> <p> (Sec. 5) This bill amends the High-Performance Computing Act of 1991 to rename the National High-Performance Computing program as the Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Program. </p> <p>The program, in addition to its current requirements, shall: </p> <ul> <li>promote increased understanding of the scientific principles of cyber-physical systems and improve methods available for the design, development, and operation of those that are characterized by high reliability, safety, and security;</li> <li>conduct or arrange for research and development on human-computer interactions, visualization, and big data, as well as the enhancement of cybersecurity; and</li> <li>create a research framework to leverage cyber-physical systems, high capacity and high speed communication networks, and large-scale data analytics to integrate city-scale information technology and physical infrastructures.</li></ul> <p>The Office of Science and Technology Policy shall encourage and monitor the efforts of agencies participating in the program to allocate the resources and management attention necessary to ensure that the strategic plan is executed effectively and that program objectives are met. </p> <p> Annual reports on the implementation of the program shall, among other things, furnish:</p> <ul> <li> a list of the senior steering groups and strategic plans that address research areas of emerging importance, and</li> <li>a description of the workshops and other activities conducted.</li> </ul>  <p>Each chair of the advisory committee on networking and information technology (currently on high-performance computing) shall meet membership qualifications, and may be a member of the President's Council of Advisors on Science and Technology.</p>   <p>Participating federal agencies, working through the National Science and Technology Council and with the assistance of the National Coordination Office (established by this bill), shall develop, and update every five years, a strategic plan for the program. </p> <p> The plan shall specify near-term and long-term objectives and how the program will accomplish other specified objectives, including by: </p> <ul> <li> fostering the transfer of research and development (R&amp;D) results into new technologies and applications for the benefit of society, </li> <li> encouraging and supporting mechanisms for interdisciplinary R&amp;D in networking and information technology, and </li> <li>promote cyberinfrastructure needs across federally funded large-scale research facilities that produce or will produce large amounts of data that will need to be stored, curated, and made available to the public.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 6) The bill replaces the National Research and Education Network with a National Coordination Office, which the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall maintain, and which shall give technical and administrative support to participating federal agencies and, as appropriate, the advisory committee.</p> <p> The National Coordination Office shall: </p> <ul> <li> serve as the primary point of contact on federal networking and information technology activities; </li> <li>through at least one workshop solicit recommendations from stakeholders during the development of each strategic plan; </li> <li>conduct outreach to relevant organizations and the public in order to increase awareness of the program and its benefits, and potential opportunities for collaboration between the participating agencies and the private sector; and </li> <li> promote access to and early application of the technologies, innovations, and expertise derived from program activities to agency missions and systems across the federal government and to U.S. industry. </li> </ul> <p>The operation of the National Coordination Office shall be supported by funds from participating agencies.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) The bill repeals the authorization for a Next Generation Internet program.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) The program shall encourage participating agencies to support large-scale, long-term, interdisciplinary R&amp;D activities in networking and information technology designed to advance the development of fundamental discoveries, and directed toward agency grand challenge mission areas with the potential for significant contributions to national economic competitiveness and other significant societal benefits.</p> <p>Such R&amp;D activities shall: </p> <ul> <li> include projects based on applications selected through a competitive, merit-based process; </li> <li> involve collaborations among researchers in institutions of higher education and industry, and may involve nonprofit research institutions and federal laboratories; </li> <li> leverage federal investments through collaboration with related state and private sector initiatives; and </li> <li> include a plan for fostering the transfer of research discoveries and the results of technology demonstration activities to industry for commercial development. </li> </ul> <p> Participating agencies may give special consideration to projects that include cost-sharing from nonfederal sources. </p>  <p>R&amp;D activities may be supported through existing or new interdisciplinary research centers organized to investigate basic research questions and carry out technology demonstration activities.</p> <p>(Sec. 9) The National Coordination Office may conduct workshops and other activities on research areas of emerging importance, which may include grand challenge areas, to help guide program investments and strategic planning in those areas.</p> <p>Workshop participants shall: </p> <ul> <li> develop options for models for R&amp;D partnerships among institutions of higher education, federal laboratories, and industry; </li> <li> develop R&amp;D options for specific issues addressed through those partnerships; and </li> <li> propose guidelines for assigning intellectual property rights and for transferring research results to the private sector. </li> </ul> <p>The National Coordination Office shall: </p> <ul> <li> ensure that workshop participants have knowledge and expertise in the specific issue areas and represent a broad mix of relevant stakeholders; and </li> <li> establish senior steering groups and develop focused strategic plans to coordinate and guide activities under the identified research areas. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 10) The National Science Foundation, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), the Department of Energy, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Department of Education shall each engage in specified research and development activities in conjunction with the program.</p>]]></text>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <introducedDate>2016-05-24</introducedDate>
    <updateDate>2017-01-03T09:48:12Z</updateDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000585</bioguideId>
        <lastName>LaHood</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <firstName>Darin</firstName>
        <fullName>Rep. LaHood, Darin [R-IL-18]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <byRequestType />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2295</lisID>
          <bioguideId>L000585</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
        <state>IL</state>
        <district>18</district>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>J000126</bioguideId>
        <district>30</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-05-24</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <state>TX</state>
        <middleName>BERNICE</middleName>
        <firstName>EDDIE</firstName>
        <lastName>JOHNSON</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Johnson, Eddie Bernice [D-TX-30]</fullName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>J000126</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8186</gpoId>
          <lisID>599</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <party>D</party>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000583</bioguideId>
        <district>21</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-05-24</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <state>TX</state>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>LAMAR</firstName>
        <lastName>SMITH</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Smith, Lamar [R-TX-21]</fullName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>S000583</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8177</gpoId>
          <lisID>1075</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <party>R</party>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000563</bioguideId>
        <district>3</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-05-24</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <state>IL</state>
        <middleName>William</middleName>
        <firstName>Daniel</firstName>
        <lastName>Lipinski</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Lipinski, Daniel [D-IL-3]</fullName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7923</gpoId>
          <lisID>1781</lisID>
          <bioguideId>L000563</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <party>D</party>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000491</bioguideId>
        <district>3</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-05-24</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <state>OK</state>
        <middleName>D.</middleName>
        <firstName>FRANK</firstName>
        <lastName>LUCAS</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Lucas, Frank D. [R-OK-3]</fullName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8111</gpoId>
          <lisID>711</lisID>
          <bioguideId>L000491</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <party>R</party>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001105</bioguideId>
        <district>10</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-05-24</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <state>VA</state>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>Barbara</firstName>
        <lastName>Comstock</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Comstock, Barbara [R-VA-10]</fullName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2273</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C001105</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
        <party>R</party>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001194</bioguideId>
        <district>4</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-05-24</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <state>MI</state>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Moolenaar</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Moolenaar, John R. [R-MI-4]</fullName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>M001194</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2248</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <party>R</party>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>A000374</bioguideId>
        <district>5</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-05-24</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <state>LA</state>
        <middleName>Lee</middleName>
        <firstName>Ralph</firstName>
        <lastName>Abraham</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Abraham, Ralph Lee [R-LA-5]</fullName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2244</lisID>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>A000374</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <party>R</party>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000619</bioguideId>
        <district>13</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-06-10</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <state>IL</state>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>Rodney</firstName>
        <lastName>Davis</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Davis, Rodney [R-IL-13]</fullName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>D000619</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2126</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <party>R</party>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <title>Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Modernization Act of 2016</title>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <calendar>U00482</calendar>
        <number />
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <billNumber>5312</billNumber>
    <createDate>2016-05-25T05:16:53Z</createDate>
    <relatedBills />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
    </policyArea>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>H. Rept. 114-620</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <laws />
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. LaHOOD:H.R. 5312.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 18:The Congress shall have power to make all Laws which shallbe necessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by thisConstitution in the Government of the United States, or inany Department of Officer thereof.[Page H3094]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <notes />
    <congress>114</congress>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Advisory bodies</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Computer security and identity theft</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Computers and information technology</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Intellectual property</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Internet and video services</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public-private cooperation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Research administration and funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Research and development</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Science and engineering education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Technology transfer and commercialization</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <amendments />
    <recordedVotes>
      <recordedVote>
        <rollNumber>298</rollNumber>
        <date>2016-06-13T23:02:42Z</date>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <fullActionName>Final Passage Under Suspension of the Rules Results</fullActionName>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <sessionNumber>2</sessionNumber>
        <url>http://clerk.house.gov/evs/2016/roll298.xml</url>
      </recordedVote>
    </recordedVotes>
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2016-06-14</actionDate>
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <title>Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Modernization Act of 2016</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House</titleType>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <title>Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Modernization Act of 2016</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to House</titleType>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <title>Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Modernization Act of 2016</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <title>To amend the High-Performance Computing Act of 1991 to authorize activities for support of networking and information technology research, and for other purposes.</title>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <title>Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Modernization Act of 2016</title>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-06-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-06-13</actionDate>
        <links />
        <actionTime>19:02:43</actionTime>
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <committee />
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-06-13</actionDate>
        <links />
        <actionTime>19:02:42</actionTime>
        <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 385 - 7 (Roll no. 298). (text: CR H3708-3711)</text>
        <committee />
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H37300</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-06-13</actionDate>
        <links />
        <actionTime>19:02:42</actionTime>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 385 - 7 (Roll no. 298).(text: CR H3708-3711)</text>
        <committee />
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-06-13</actionDate>
        <links />
        <actionTime>18:56:58</actionTime>
        <text>Considered as unfinished business. (consideration: CR H3731-3732)</text>
        <committee />
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-06-13</actionDate>
        <links />
        <actionTime>16:51:15</actionTime>
        <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
        <committee />
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H37220</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-06-13</actionDate>
        <links />
        <actionTime>16:31:24</actionTime>
        <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5312.</text>
        <committee />
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-06-13</actionDate>
        <links />
        <actionTime>16:31:22</actionTime>
        <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR H3708-3714)</text>
        <committee />
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-06-13</actionDate>
        <links />
        <actionTime>16:31:03</actionTime>
        <text>Mr. LaHood moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
        <committee />
        <type>Floor</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H30300</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-06-13</actionDate>
        <links />
        <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 482.</text>
        <committee />
        <type>Calendars</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H12410</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-06-13</actionDate>
        <links />
        <text>Reported by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 114-620.</text>
        <committee>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H12200</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-06-13</actionDate>
        <links />
        <text>Reported by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 114-620.</text>
        <committee>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>5000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-05-24</actionDate>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
        <committee>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-05-24</actionDate>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-05-24</actionDate>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>14</houseOfRepresentatives>
        <senate>1</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>1</finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>
        <committeeReportOfABill>1</committeeReportOfABill>
        <motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>1</motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>
        <reportedToHouse>1</reportedToHouse>
        <passedAgreedToInHouse>1</passedAgreedToInHouse>
        <considerationByHouse>2</considerationByHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <unionCalendarAssignment>1</unionCalendarAssignment>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <motionToReconsiderResults>1</motionToReconsiderResults>
        <generalDebate>1</generalDebate>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

