<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:03:52Z</updateDate>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2013-05-22</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Social Welfare</name>
    </policyArea>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. LEWIS:H.R. 2110.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:This bill is enacted pursuant to the power granted toCongress under Article I of the United States Constitutionand its subsequent amendments, and further clarified andinterpreted by the Supreme Court of the United States.[Page H2912]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <introducedDate>2013-05-22</introducedDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Social Welfare</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Bank accounts, deposits, capital</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Financial services and investments</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government trust funds</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Higher education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Poverty and welfare assistance</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Residential rehabilitation and home repair</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Student aid and college costs</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Vocational and technical education</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Stephanie Tubbs Jones Assets for Independence Reauthorization Act of 2013 - Amends the Assets for Independence Act, which provides for demonstration projects designed to provide individuals and families of limited means with an incentive to save a portion of their earned income and thereby accumulate assets, increase their economic self-sufficiency, and stabilize such families and the communities in which they live.</p> <p>Expresses the sense of Congress that a qualified entity conducting a demonstration project under the Act should, to the maximum extent practicable, increase: (1) the rate at which it matches contributions by participating individuals, or (2) the number of such participating individuals.</p> <p>States that multiple households may share a single residence. Specifies public housing agencies and tribally designated housing entities as entities qualified to participate in a demonstration project. Repeals the requirement that state or local government or other public agencies apply jointly with a tax-exempt not-for-profit charitable organization or collaborate with certain kinds of local community-based organizations. Includes among postsecondary educational expenses any expenses for preparatory courses, room and board, and transportation.</p> <p>Revises requirements for: (1) applications for new and renewals of existing projects; (2) limitations on uses of the Reserve Fund; and (3) the adjusted gross household income eligibility test, requiring regulations for transfers from one project to another for individuals who move because of major disasters or emergencies, to find employment, or to a community where no project is available.</p> <p>Revises requirements for deposits by qualified entities in the individual development accounts (IDAs) of participating individuals to: (1) increase maximum deposits per individual and per household; (2) facilitate withdrawal of funds from an IDA, with formal approval, during the year following the end of a demonstration project; and (3) require disposal of funds remaining in an IDA at the end of that year.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of Community Services, to make every effort, 90 days after terminating the authority of one qualified entity to operate a demonstration project, to identify another qualified entity (or entities), in the same or a different community, willing and able to conduct one or more demonstration projects. Specifies criteria for giving priority consideration to candidate entities.</p> <p>Revises requirements for contracting with independent research organizations to evaluate demonstration projects.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) use certain funds to cover the necessary costs of training for a qualified entity conducting a demonstration project, including costs of travel, accommodations, and meals; and (2) waive any requirement of the Act in certain circumstances.</p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2013-05-22T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-06-04T20:34:29Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2013-05-22</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <recordedVotes />
    <notes />
    <billNumber>2110</billNumber>
    <committeeReports />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <congress>113</congress>
    <amendments />
    <laws />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <createDate>2013-05-23T07:02:05Z</createDate>
    <title>Stephanie Tubbs Jones Assets for Independence Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>LEWIS</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>688</lisID>
          <bioguideId>L000287</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7902</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>JOHN</firstName>
        <fullName>Rep. Lewis, John [D-GA-5]</fullName>
        <bioguideId>L000287</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>RANGEL</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Rangel, Charles B. [D-NY-13]</fullName>
        <bioguideId>R000053</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8076</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>R000053</bioguideId>
          <lisID>944</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <firstName>CHARLES</firstName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-30</sponsorshipDate>
        <middleName>B.</middleName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <lastName>CAPUANO</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Capuano, Michael E. [D-MA-7]</fullName>
        <bioguideId>C001037</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1564</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C001037</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7973</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <firstName>MICHAEL</firstName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-09-10</sponsorshipDate>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <lastName>Ellison</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Ellison, Keith [D-MN-5]</fullName>
        <bioguideId>E000288</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1857</lisID>
          <bioguideId>E000288</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8005</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <firstName>Keith</firstName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-11</sponsorshipDate>
        <middleName />
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-05-22</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-05-22</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-05-22</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>3</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Stephanie Tubbs Jones Assets for Independence Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>To reauthorize the Assets for Independence Act, to provide for the approval of applications to operate new demonstration programs and to renew existing programs, to enhance program flexibility, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Stephanie Tubbs Jones Assets for Independence Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <relatedBills />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2013-05-22T14:05:25Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

