<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <laws />
    <recordedVotes />
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
          <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <billNumber>3255</billNumber>
    <policyArea>
      <name>International Affairs</name>
    </policyArea>
    <notes />
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
      <links />
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <relatedBills />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2016-07-14T20:37:56Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <cosponsors />
    <committeeReports />
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Toomey, Pat [R-PA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Pat</firstName>
        <lastName>Toomey</lastName>
        <state>PA</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <bioguideId>T000461</bioguideId>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>T000461</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>1594</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName />
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <createDate>2016-07-15T07:14:53Z</createDate>
    <updateDate>2016-11-11T09:49:11Z</updateDate>
    <introducedDate>2016-07-14</introducedDate>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2016-07-14T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-11-08T20:28:45Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Blocking Deadly Fentanyl Imports Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to include in the definition of &quot;major illicit drug producing country&quot; a country that is a significant source of illicit fentanyl, fentanyl analogues, or fentanyl precursor chemicals. (Fentanyl is a synthetic opioid analgesic typically used to relieve pain.) </p> <p> The bill requires the international narcotics control strategy report to: </p> <ul> <li>identify countries that are the most significant exporters of illicit fentanyl, fentanyl analogues, and fentanyl precursor chemicals; </li> <li>identify countries that are the most significant sources of the diversion of such chemical for illicit uses; and </li> <li>describe the extent to which an identified country has cooperated with the United States to prevent the export of such chemical to the United States.</li> </ul> <p>The bill requires the withholding of bilateral and multilateral assistance from an identified country. </p> <p>The Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2003 is amended to require the President, as part of the report identifying major drug transit countries, to designate each country that: </p> <ul> <li>does not utilize specified emergency scheduling procedures for new illicit drugs and other synthetics that are comparable to the procedures used for controlled substances schedules,</li> <li>is incapable of prosecuting criminals for the manufacture or distribution of controlled substance analogues in the same manner that applies to controlled substances, and </li> <li>does not require specified registration of tableting or encapsulating machines. </li> </ul>]]></text>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <title>Blocking Deadly Fentanyl Imports Act</title>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>International Affairs</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects />
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <amendments />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <congress>114</congress>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Blocking Deadly Fentanyl Imports Act</title>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>A bill to gather information about the illicit production of illicit fentanyl in foreign countries and to withhold bilateral assistance from countries that do not have emergency scheduling procedures for new illicit drugs, cannot prosecute criminals for the manufacture or distribution of controlled substance analogues, or do not require the registration of tableting machines and encapsulating machines.</title>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Blocking Deadly Fentanyl Imports Act</title>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

