<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2018-04-25T17:15:24Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2018-04-24T21:19:33Z</date>
              <name>Reported by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2017-06-08T16:06:01Z</date>
              <name>Markup by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2017-06-07T14:03:25Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <recordedVotes />
    <laws />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2017-06-07T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill grants the Office of Space Commerce of the Department of Commerce the authority to issue certifications to U.S. nationals and nongovernmental entities for the operation of: (1) specified human-made objects manufactured or assembled in outer space, including on the Moon and other celestial bodies, with or without human occupants, that were launched from Earth; and (2) all items carried on such objects that are intended for use in outer space. To be eligible for certification, each entity's application must include a space debris mitigation plan for the space objects. </p> <p>The office shall establish a Private Space Activity Advisory Committee to: (1) analyze the status and recent developments of nongovernmental space activities, and (2) advise on matters relating to U.S. private sector activities in outer space. </p> <p>The bill authorizes the office to issue permits to persons for the operation of space-based remote sensing systems. </p> <p>The office shall establish an Advisory Committee on Commercial Remote Sensing to advise on matters relating to the U.S. commercial space-based remote sensing industry. </p> <p>The bill abolishes the Commercial Remote Sensing Regulatory Affairs Office of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration. </p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2017-06-07</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2017-09-25T16:06:06Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
        </item>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2018-04-24T17:32:57Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>36</versionCode>
          <name>Passed House amended</name>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill grants the Office of Space Commerce of the Department of Commerce the authority to issue certifications to U.S. nationals and nongovernmental entities (U.S. entities) for the operation of human-made objects launched from Earth and the items carried on them (space objects). <p> <p>The office shall require only one certification for a U.S. entity to:</p> <ul> <li>conduct multiple operations using a single space object,</li> <li>operate multiple space objects that carry out substantially similar operations, or </li> <li>use multiple space objects to carry out a single space operation. </li> </ul> <p>The bill sets forth requirements for the approval of applications for the issuance or transfer of a certification. Applications must include a space debris mitigation plan. </p> <p>A certification shall expire on the earlier of:</p> <ul> <li>when all operations approved under the certification cease, including the carrying out of a space debris mitigation plan; </li> <li>when all space objects approved under the certification no longer exist; or </li> <li>five years after the certification was approved, if no approved operations have commenced. </li> </ul>   <p>Any U.S. entity for whom a payload has been approved as part of a license issued under current federal law may:</p> <ul> <li>elect to be immediately considered certified for operation, or</li> <li> apply for a certification for the operation of the licensed activities and may continue to operate pursuant to such license until such certification is issued. </li> </ul> <p>A payload of a U.S. entity that is pending approval under current federal law as part of a commercial launch or reentry license that has already been issued, may be, at the election of the applicant, rescinded or deemed to be a pending application for certification.</p> <p>The office shall establish a Private Space Activity Advisory Committee to: </p> <ul> <li> analyze the status and recent developments of nongovernmental space activities;</li> <li>analyze the implementation of the certification process;</li> <li>provide recommendations on how the United States can facilitate and promote a robust and innovative private sector that is investing in, developing, and operating space objects;</li> <li>identify any challenges the private sector is experiencing regarding activities in outer space;</li> <li>review existing best practices for U.S. entities to avoid harmful contamination of celestial bodies and adverse changes in Earth's environment resulting from the introduction of extraterrestrial matter; </li> <li> advise on matters relating to private sector space activities; and </li> <li>provide information, advice, and recommendations related to the office's authority.</li> </ul> <p>The committee shall be terminated 10 years after it is established. </p> <p>The bill directs the President to protect the interests of U.S. entities in outer space, including commercial activity, the exploitation of space resources, and ownership rights over space objects and obtained space resources.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill authorizes the office to issue permits for the operation of space-based remote sensing systems. </p> <p>Only one permit is required for the operation of a space-based remote sensing system to:</p> <ul> <li>conduct multiple operations using such a system,</li> <li>operate multiple such systems that carry out similar operations, or </li> <li>use those systems to carry out a single remote sensing operation. </li> </ul> <p>The bill bars any person from operating any space-based remote sensing system without a permit. </p> <p>Where an applicant for a permit is not a U.S. entity, the applicant must identify a U.S. entity that has consented to being responsible for the permitted operation of the space-based remote sensing system.</p> <p>The operation of a space-based remote sensing system:</p> <ul> <li>begins when it is in outer space and can meet the minimum threshold and objective capabilities for its stated need; and</li> <li> shall not cover acts of distribution, sale, or transfer of data, information, or services. </li> </ul> <p>The bill sets forth permit application and review requirements. If the proposed operation of a space-based remote sensing system poses a significant threat to national security, the office may deny the application or condition the permit to address the threat. The office may place on a permit only a condition that is achievable using reasonably commercially available efforts. An application may not be denied and a permit may not be conditioned for a system with similar capabilities to systems that are already commercially available or expected to be available in the next three years. </p> <p>The office shall provide for the transfer of a permit. </p> <p>A person may apply for a permit to operate a space-based remote sensing system that utilizes a civilian federal government satellite or vehicle as a platform. The office may offer assistance in finding such opportunities. An executive agency may enter into an agreement for such use if the agreement is consistent with the agency's mission and statutory authority. </p> <p>The office shall establish an Advisory Committee on Commercial Remote Sensing to: </p> <ul> <li> advise on matters relating to the commercial space-based remote sensing industry;</li> <li>analyze the implementation of the space-based remote sensing system permitting process; </li> <li>provide recommendations on how the United States can facilitate and promote a robust and innovative private sector that is investing in, developing, and operating such systems;</li> <li>identify any challenges the private sector is experiencing with the authorization and supervision of the operation of such systems; and </li> <li>provide information, advice, and recommendations related to the office's authority or to authorized private sector activities in outer space.</li> </ul> <p>Such committee shall be terminated 10 years after it is established.</p> <p>Any U.S. entity with a valid license for the operation of space-based remote sensing system may:</p> <ul> <li>elect to be immediately considered permitted, or </li> <li>apply for a permit and continue to operate pursuant to such license until a permit is issued. </li> </ul> <p>A pending application for a remote sensing license may be, at the election of such applicant, rescinded or deemed to be a pending application for a permit. </p> <p>The bill abolishes the Commercial Remote Sensing Regulatory Affairs Office of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) The bill sets forth administrative authority and procedures related to certifications and permits. </p>  <p>(Sec. 6) The bill repeals provisions relating to the licensing of private remote sensing space systems and relating to certain consultations concerning the management of the Landsat Program.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) The office must be located in the principal physical location of the Office of the Secretary of Commerce. </p> <p>Future directors of the office shall be appointed by the President and confirmed by the Senate. The director shall be the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Space Commerce and shall report directly to the Secretary of Commerce. </p> <p>As an additional function, the office shall facilitate and promote the development of best practices among operators of space objects and space-based remote sensing systems to address risks to federal government space objects. </p> <p>(Sec. 8) No launch or reentry may be prevented under the authority of the Department of Transportation (DOT) on the basis of national security, foreign policy, or international obligations of the United States if the payload has received a certification to operate as a space object. </p> <p>(Sec. 9) The office shall report on the implementation of the space object registration obligations of the United States and other countries under Article VIII of the Treaty on Principles Governing the Activities of States in the Exploration and Use of Outer Space, including the Moon and Other Celestial Bodies (1967) and the Convention on Registration of Objects Launched into Outer Space (1975). </p> <p>(Sec. 10) The Government Accountability Office shall report on removing the Office of Commercial Space Transportation from under the jurisdiction of the Federal Aviation Administration and reestablishing such office under the jurisdiction of DOT.</p> <p>(Sec. 11) Commerce shall report to the Advisory Committee on Commercial Remote Sensing on space-based radiofrequency mapping, including whether there is a need to regulate such mapping. </p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2018-04-24</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Passed House amended</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2018-05-17T21:55:23Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <calendar>U00498</calendar>
        <number />
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House</titleType>
        <title>American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act</title>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to House</titleType>
        <title>American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act of 2017</title>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act of 2017</title>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend title 51, United States Code, to provide for the authorization and supervision of nongovernmental space activities, and for other purposes.</title>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act</title>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <titleType>(Extracted from GPO) Short Titles as Passed House</titleType>
        <title>American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act</title>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <titleType>(Extracted from GPO) Short Titles as Reported to House</titleType>
        <title>American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act of 2017</title>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>(Extracted from GPO) Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act of 2017</title>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-06-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>36</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Babin, Brian [R-TX-36]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>B001291</bioguideId>
        <firstName>Brian</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <lastName>Babin</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2270</lisID>
          <bioguideId>B001291</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OK</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-06-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>1</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Bridenstine, Jim [R-OK-1]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>B001283</bioguideId>
        <firstName>Jim</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <lastName>Bridenstine</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2155</lisID>
          <bioguideId>B001283</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-06-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>7</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Perlmutter, Ed [D-CO-7]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>P000593</bioguideId>
        <firstName>Ed</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <lastName>Perlmutter</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1835</lisID>
          <bioguideId>P000593</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7865</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-06-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>48</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Rohrabacher, Dana [R-CA-48]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>R000409</bioguideId>
        <firstName>DANA</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <lastName>ROHRABACHER</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>R000409</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7851</gpoId>
          <lisID>979</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>IL</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-06-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>14</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Hultgren, Randy [R-IL-14]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>H001059</bioguideId>
        <firstName>Randy</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <lastName>Hultgren</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7934</gpoId>
          <lisID>2015</lisID>
          <bioguideId>H001059</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-06-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>14</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Weber, Randy K., Sr. [R-TX-14]</fullName>
        <middleName>K.</middleName>
        <bioguideId>W000814</bioguideId>
        <firstName>Randy</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <lastName>Weber</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2161</lisID>
          <bioguideId>W000814</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>LA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-06-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>3</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Higgins, Clay [R-LA-3]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>H001077</bioguideId>
        <firstName>Clay</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <lastName>Higgins</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2329</lisID>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>H001077</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-06-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>6</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Kilmer, Derek [D-WA-6]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>K000381</bioguideId>
        <firstName>Derek</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <lastName>Kilmer</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2169</lisID>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>K000381</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-06-26</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>5</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Lamborn, Doug [R-CO-5]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>L000564</bioguideId>
        <firstName>Doug</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <lastName>Lamborn</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7863</gpoId>
          <lisID>1834</lisID>
          <bioguideId>L000564</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>FL</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-07-11</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>2</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Dunn, Neal P. [R-FL-2]</fullName>
        <middleName>P.</middleName>
        <bioguideId>D000628</bioguideId>
        <firstName>Neal</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <lastName>Dunn</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>D000628</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2315</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-07-11</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>42</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Calvert, Ken [R-CA-42]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>C000059</bioguideId>
        <firstName>KEN</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <lastName>CALVERT</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>165</lisID>
          <gpoId>7849</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>C000059</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-09-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>6</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Coffman, Mike [R-CO-6]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>C001077</bioguideId>
        <firstName>Mike</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <lastName>Coffman</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1912</lisID>
          <gpoId>7864</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>C001077</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>FL</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-12-15</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>9</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Soto, Darren [D-FL-9]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>S001200</bioguideId>
        <firstName>Darren</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <lastName>Soto</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2319</lisID>
          <bioguideId>S001200</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2018-04-24</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>23</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. McCarthy, Kevin [R-CA-23]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>M001165</bioguideId>
        <firstName>Kevin</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <lastName>McCarthy</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7827</gpoId>
          <lisID>1833</lisID>
          <bioguideId>M001165</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2018-04-24</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>7</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Bera, Ami [D-CA-7]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>B001287</bioguideId>
        <firstName>Ami</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <lastName>Bera</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>B001287</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2102</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <title>H.R. 2809, American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act of 2017</title>
        <pubDate>2017-07-07T21:00:57Z</pubDate>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/52879</url>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2018-04-25</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <updateDate>2018-08-28T20:08:30Z</updateDate>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 163, Number 97 (Wednesday, June 7, 2017)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. SMITH of Texas:H.R. 2809.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 18:The Congress shall have power to make all Laws which shallbe necessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by thisConstitution in the Government of the United States, or inany Department or Officer thereof.Article I, Section 8, Clause 3:The Congress shall have power to regulate Commerce withforeign Nations, and among the several States, and with theIndian Tribes.[Page H4701]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
    </policyArea>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <billNumber>2809</billNumber>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <relatedBills />
    <title>American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act</title>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <actionStageOverride>1</actionStageOverride>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <passedAgreedToInHouse>1</passedAgreedToInHouse>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <considerationByHouse>1</considerationByHouse>
        <motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>1</motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>
        <committeeReportOfABill>1</committeeReportOfABill>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>1</finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>
        <generalDebate>1</generalDebate>
        <reportedToHouse>1</reportedToHouse>
        <unionCalendarAssignment>1</unionCalendarAssignment>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <motionToReconsiderResults>1</motionToReconsiderResults>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-04-25</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <actionTime>17:45:31</actionTime>
        <actionDate>2018-04-24</actionDate>
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-164/house-section/page/H3476-3484</url>
            <name>H3476-3484</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionTime>17:45:30</actionTime>
        <actionDate>2018-04-24</actionDate>
        <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR H3476-3484)</text>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H37300</actionCode>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-164/house-section/page/H3476-3484</url>
            <name>H3476-3484</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionTime>17:45:30</actionTime>
        <actionDate>2018-04-24</actionDate>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.(text: CR H3476-3484)</text>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/2809</url>
            <name>H.R. 2809</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionTime>17:20:17</actionTime>
        <actionDate>2018-04-24</actionDate>
        <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2809.</text>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-164/house-section/page/H3476-3489</url>
            <name>H3476-3489</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionTime>17:20:16</actionTime>
        <actionDate>2018-04-24</actionDate>
        <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR H3476-3489)</text>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <actionTime>17:20:01</actionTime>
        <actionDate>2018-04-24</actionDate>
        <text>Mr. Smith (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H30300</actionCode>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>Calendars</type>
        <actionDate>2018-04-24</actionDate>
        <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 498.</text>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H12410</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/115th-congress/house-report/649</url>
            <name>H. Rept. 115-649</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionDate>2018-04-24</actionDate>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 115-649.</text>
        <committee>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H12200</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/115th-congress/house-report/649</url>
            <name>H. Rept. 115-649</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionDate>2018-04-24</actionDate>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 115-649.</text>
        <committee>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>5000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-06-08</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-06-08</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2017-06-07</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
        <committee>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2017-06-07</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2017-06-07</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>14</houseOfRepresentatives>
        <senate>1</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative remedies</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Advisory bodies</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Commerce</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>International law and treaties</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Solid waste and recycling</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Space flight and exploration</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Spacecraft and satellites</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Transportation safety and security</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>H. Rept. 115-649</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <introducedDate>2017-06-07</introducedDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000583</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <byRequestType />
        <fullName>Rep. Smith, Lamar [R-TX-21]</fullName>
        <lastName>SMITH</lastName>
        <state>TX</state>
        <district>21</district>
        <party>R</party>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1075</lisID>
          <gpoId>8177</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>S000583</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>LAMAR</firstName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <notes />
    <createDate>2017-06-08T03:11:41Z</createDate>
    <amendments />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

