<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>Murphy</lastName>
        <fullName>Sen. Murphy, Christopher S. [D-CT]</fullName>
        <middleName>S.</middleName>
        <firstName>Christopher</firstName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>M001169</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1837</lisID>
          <gpoId>7870</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>M001169</bioguideId>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <actionDate>2014-06-25</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <laws />
    <createDate>2014-06-26T05:01:33Z</createDate>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:31:08Z</updateDate>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-06-25T19:37:17Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <recordedVotes />
    <introducedDate>2014-06-25</introducedDate>
    <relatedBills />
    <billNumber>2531</billNumber>
    <amendments />
    <billType>S</billType>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-06-25</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
          <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <actionDate>2014-06-25</actionDate>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>Booker</lastName>
        <fullName>Sen. Booker, Cory A. [D-NJ]</fullName>
        <bioguideId>B001288</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>B001288</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2194</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <firstName>Cory</firstName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-06-25</sponsorshipDate>
        <middleName>A.</middleName>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-10-02T15:18:07Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Better Options for Kids Act of 2014 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, in awarding priority mental health needs grants to programs for youth involved in, or at risk of becoming involved in, the criminal justice system, to give preference to states that: (1) demonstrate greater educational continuity, lower rates of juvenile court involvement, and reduced recidivism through implementation of certain evidence-based policies; (2) demonstrate partnerships through which the state will establish a coordinated process for service delivery and develop the ability to share information and which involve interagency agreements or strategic plans; and (3) have certified a commitment to such partnerships and to the state's responsibility for the desired results. Terminates such grant preference five years after enactment of this Act.</p> <p>Requires a state, to receive such preference, to demonstrate that it has implemented, or will use grant funds to implement, evidence-based policies under which the state:</p> <ul> <li> provides or funds training for local educational agencies (LEAs) in the use of discipline and positive school climate strategies that minimize the use of suspensions, expulsions, and other actions that remove students from instruction and that show evidence of effectiveness for improving the learning environment;</li> <li>requires or provides incentives to LEAs to execute with any law enforcement agency that assigns officers to schools a collaborative agreement that prohibits the involvement of such officers in regular student disciplinary matters and describes their roles and responsibilities;</li> <li>prohibits or limits court referrals for juvenile school-based status offenses;</li> <li>has shifted, or has a plan to shift, significant funding formerly dedicated to secure detention of minors into community-based alternatives to incarceration; and</li> <li>has adopted, or will adopt, a reentry policy to ensure that youth in correctional facilities can continue their education immediately and without delay upon release by providing for prompt re-enrollment.</li> </ul>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2014-06-25</actionDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2014-06-25T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <committeeReports />
    <title>Better Options for Kids Act of 2014</title>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <notes />
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Health</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Child health</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Correctional facilities and imprisonment</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Elementary and secondary education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health programs administration and funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Juvenile crime and gang violence</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Mental health</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>School administration</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Better Options for Kids Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>A bill to reward and incentivize evidence-based State policies that improve educational continuity and limit juvenile court involvement and incarceration for youth through a priority in awarding certain competitive grants offered by the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration.</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Better Options for Kids Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
      </item>
    </titles>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

