<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <amendments />
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-10-17</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects />
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <laws />
    <notes />
    <billType>S</billType>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>P000603</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Paul, Rand [R-KY]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8308</gpoId>
          <lisID>2082</lisID>
          <bioguideId>P000603</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <byRequestType />
        <state>KY</state>
        <firstName>Rand</firstName>
        <party>R</party>
        <lastName>Paul</lastName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <recordedVotes />
    <committeeReports />
    <introducedDate>2017-10-17</introducedDate>
    <updateDate>2018-08-28T20:30:17Z</updateDate>
    <cosponsors />
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-10-17</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-10-17</actionDate>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2017-10-17T21:28:09Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <title>BASIC Research Act</title>
    <createDate>2017-10-18T00:41:22Z</createDate>
    <billNumber>1973</billNumber>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <relatedBills />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>BASIC Research Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires each review panel for a federal research grant to include: (1) at least one individual who is not professionally affiliated with any academic or research institution, has not been professionally affiliated in the preceding 10 years, and is an expert in a field unrelated to that under which the grant proposal was submitted; and (2) at least one individual who shall serve primarily as a taxpayer advocate. Each agency that awards such a grant shall not accept recommendations from an applicant as to who should be on the panel or disclose the identity of any panel member to an applicant.</p> <p>The bill: (1) establishes an Office of the Special Inspector General and Taxpayer Advocate for Research (OSIGTA), which shall randomly select grants for review to determine if the research will deliver value to the taxpayers; and (2) transfers to the OSIGTA all functions which the Office of Inspector General of the National Science Foundation previously exercised. A grant must have OSIGTA's support to receive funds.</p> <p>Each agency with annual extramural research expenditures of over $100 million must develop a federal research public access policy that is consistent with and advances the purposes of the agency and that meets specified requirements. </p> <p>Any person or institution awarded a grant shall submit a statement to the agency that awarded the grant certifying that: (1) no funds derived from the grant will be made available through a subgrant or subsequent grant unless the recipient's name, its organization of affiliation, the intended uses and purposes of funds, and specific amounts subgranted or subsequently granted funds are disclosed to the agency for publication on a publicly accessible website; and (2) each subgrant or subsequent grant award funded is within the scope of the grant award.</p> <p>Each grant application shall be made publicly available. Each agency, in awarding grants for scientific research, shall be impartial and shall not seek to advance any political position or fund a grant to reach a predetermined conclusion.</p>]]></text>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2018-03-26T18:04:53Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <updateDate>2017-10-17T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDate>2017-10-17</actionDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>BASIC Research Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>A bill to provide for Federal research grant reform.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>BASIC Research Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>(Extracted from GPO) Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>BASIC Research Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

