<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <title>Drone Aircraft Privacy and Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <updateDate>2018-08-28T20:24:47Z</updateDate>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Aviation and airports</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Criminal justice information and records</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Criminal procedure and sentencing</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Transportation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Evidence and witnesses</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Federal Trade Commission (FTC)</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government liability</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Law enforcement administration and funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Legal fees and court costs</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>News media and reporting</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Photography and imaging</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Right of privacy</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Telephone and wireless communication</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2017-03-15</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestTitle>Drone Aircraft Privacy and Transparency Act of 2017</latestTitle>
        <number>1526</number>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Digital Commerce and Consumer Protection.</text>
          <actionDate>2017-03-17</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <type>HR</type>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <introducedDate>2017-03-15</introducedDate>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-03-15</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2017-03-15</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <laws />
    <congress>115</congress>
    <committeeReports />
    <billNumber>631</billNumber>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <cosponsors />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2017-03-15T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2017-10-03T20:52:33Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Drone Aircraft Privacy and Transparency Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to direct the Department of Transportation (DOT) to establish procedures to ensure that the integration of unmanned aircraft (drone) systems into the national airspace system is done in compliance with privacy principles. Such procedures shall not apply to a drone system operated for news-gathering activities protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution.</p> <p>DOT may not approve, issue, or award any certificate, license, or other grant of authority to operate a drone system in the national airspace system unless the pertinent application includes a data collection statement that provides reasonable assurance that the applicant will operate the drone in accordance with privacy principles. The same requirement shall apply to any drone system to be operated by a law enforcement agency, except that the application shall include a data minimization statement, instead of a data collection statement, that provides the same assurance.</p> <p>The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) shall make any approved grant of authority, each such statement, and information about the drone's owner, operator, and technical capability available in a searchable format on the public FAA website.</p> <p>A governmental entity may not use a drone system, or request information collected by another entity through a drone system, for protective activities or for law enforcement or intelligence purposes except pursuant to a warrant or as permitted under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, except when: (1) a law enforcement entity reasonably believes there is an imminent danger of death or serious physical injury, or (2) the Department of Homeland Security determines that credible intelligence indicates there is a high risk of an imminent terrorist attack by a specific individual or organization.</p> <p>It shall be unlawful to operate a drone system in a manner that is not in accordance with the terms of a data collection statement or that violates the rule implementing the procedures required by this bill. Any such violation shall be treated as an unfair or deceptive act or practice under the Federal Trade Commission Act. This bill provides for enforcement by the Federal Trade Commission, by a civil action brought by a state, or by a private action. </p> <p>The FAA shall revoke the certificate, license, or other grant of authority of a drone system operated in a violation of this bill. </p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2017-03-15</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2017-03-15T14:24:17Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <notes />
    <amendments />
    <recordedVotes />
    <createDate>2017-03-16T05:28:16Z</createDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M000133</bioguideId>
        <party>D</party>
        <firstName>EDWARD</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. Markey, Edward J. [D-MA]</fullName>
        <state>MA</state>
        <lastName>MARKEY</lastName>
        <middleName>J.</middleName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>735</lisID>
          <bioguideId>M000133</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7972</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Drone Aircraft Privacy and Transparency Act of 2017</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to provide guidance and limitations regarding the integration of unmanned aircraft systems into United States airspace, and for other purposes.</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Drone Aircraft Privacy and Transparency Act of 2017</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>(Extracted from GPO) Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Drone Aircraft Privacy and Transparency Act of 2017</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

