<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <title>New Mexico Drought Preparedness Act of 2015</title>
    <updateDate>2016-11-02T23:34:01Z</updateDate>
    <relatedBills />
    <introducedDate>2015-08-04</introducedDate>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Water Resources Development</name>
    </policyArea>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <billNumber>1936</billNumber>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <amendments />
    <recordedVotes />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2015-10-08T13:30:00Z</date>
              <name>Hearings by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2015-08-04T22:45:05Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <laws />
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Agricultural conservation and pollution</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Agricultural practices and innovations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Aquatic ecology</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Climate change and greenhouse gases</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Dams and canals</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Endangered and threatened species</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Environmental technology</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Farmland</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Fishes</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Floods and storm protection</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Hydrology and hydrography</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Lakes and rivers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>New Mexico</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local government operations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water resources funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water storage</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water use and supply</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Watersheds</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Wildlife conservation and habitat protection</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Water Resources Development</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <notes />
    <committeeReports />
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-10-08</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-08-04</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2015-08-04</actionDate>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <hearingsHeld>1</hearingsHeld>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>3</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2015-10-08</actionDate>
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>New Mexico Drought Preparedness Act of 2015</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>A bill to provide for drought preparedness measures in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>New Mexico Drought Preparedness Act of 2015</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2015-08-04T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Mexico Drought Preparedness Act of 2015</strong></p> <p> Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation (Secretary), to carry out a water acquisition program in specified basins in New Mexico, under which the Secretary shall: (1) make acquisitions of water by lease or purchase of water rights or contractual entitlements from willing lessors or sellers; and (2) take other actions to enhance stream flow to benefit fish and wildlife, water quality, and river ecosystem restoration and to enhance stewardship and conservation of working land, water, and watersheds.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary, in cooperation with the Middle Rio Grande Conservancy District, to provide funding and technical assistance for the installation of metering and measurement devices and the construction of check structures on irrigation diversions, canals, laterals, ditches, and drains to: (1) ensure the conservation and efficient use of water within the District by reducing actual consumptive use or by not increasing the use of water, and (2) improve the measurement and allocation of water acquired through such water acquisition program.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to provide for development of a comprehensive plan for the San Acacia and Isleta reaches to plan, design, construct, and prioritize projects that balance river maintenance, water availability, use, and delivery, and ecosystem benefits.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of the Army to continue, for five years after enactment of this Act, the temporary deviation in the operation of Cochiti Lake and Jemez Canyon Dam that was initiated in 2009 and terminated in 2013, to evaluate the benefits of the deviation while a permanent reauthorization of the reservoirs is pursued.</p> <p>Requires the Secretaries to: (1) conduct a feasibility study to address Cochiti Dam operation limitations on the timing, magnitude, and duration of flows that support federally listed species in the Middle Rio Grande; (2) submit a feasibility report on the reauthorization of the purposes of Cochiti Dam; and (3) enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences to study water and reservoir management and operation issues along the Rio Grande.</p> <p>Authorizes financial assistance to be made available for eligible water projects to help New Mexico and other Western states address drought-related impacts to water supplies or any other immediate water-related crisis or conflict.</p> <p>Amends the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (OPLMA) to: (1) authorize the use of water management improvement grants to assist applicants in planning for or addressing the impacts of drought, (2) authorize the Commissioner of Reclamation to waive any cost-share requirements to address emergency drought situations and to prioritize projects based on drought relief benefits, and (3) authorize appropriations for such grants.</p> <p>Reauthorizes appropriations for: (1) the Reclamation States Emergency Drought Relief Act of 1991, and (2) Rio Grande Pueblos infrastructure grants under OPLMA. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to allocate certain financial assistance made available under the Food Security Act of 1985 (FSA) to establish special conservation initiatives to assist producers in implementing eligible activities on agricultural land in the western states for: (1) mitigating the effects of drought; (2) improving water quality and quantity; (3) restoring, enhancing, and preserving fish and wildlife habitat; and (4) promoting innovative and collaborative conservation tools and approaches.</p> <p>Amends the FSA to provide that areas eligible for designation as conservation priority areas shall include areas with actual and significant water quantity impacts related to agricultural production activities.</p>]]></text>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-11-24T20:06:16Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2015-08-04</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <createDate>2015-08-05T08:16:03Z</createDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <state>NM</state>
        <fullName>Sen. Udall, Tom [D-NM]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>U000039</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1567</lisID>
          <gpoId>8260</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>TOM</firstName>
        <lastName>UDALL</lastName>
        <bioguideId>U000039</bioguideId>
        <byRequestType />
        <party>D</party>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <state>NM</state>
        <fullName>Sen. Heinrich, Martin [D-NM]</fullName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-08-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <middleName />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1937</lisID>
          <bioguideId>H001046</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8056</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>Martin</firstName>
        <lastName>Heinrich</lastName>
        <bioguideId>H001046</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <party>D</party>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

