<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2015-06-15T19:22:51Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <billNumber>1575</billNumber>
    <updateDate>2016-11-02T23:30:28Z</updateDate>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2015-06-15</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Write the Laws Act</strong></p> <p>Prohibits an Act of Congress from containing any delegation of legislative powers, whether to: (1) any component within the legislative branch, (2) the President or any other member of the executive branch, (3) the judicial branch, (4) any agency, (5) any quasi-public agency, (6) any state or state instrumentality, or (7) any other organization or individual.</p> <p>Excludes from the meaning of delegation of legislative powers the issuance of presidential proclamations, the issuance of rules or regulations governing the internal operation of federal agencies, or the making of conditions upon agency grants or contracts.</p> <p>Prohibits the promulgation or putting into effect of any new presidential directive, adjudicative decision, rule, or regulation, or any change to an existing presidential directive, adjudicative decision, rule, or regulation governing, limiting, imposing a penalty on, or otherwise regulating any activity of any individual or entity, other than a federal officer or employee, unless it is authorized by an Act of Congress that complies with this Act.</p> <p>Requires the Comptroller General to identify to Congress all statutes enacted within 90 days after enactment of this Act that contain any delegation of legislative powers prohibited by it.</p> <p>Denies any force or effect to any Act of Congress, presidential directive, adjudicative decision, rule, or regulation that is noncompliant with this Act. Prohibits any legal, equitable, regulatory, civil, or criminal action from being brought under such an Act, adjudicative decision, rule, or regulation.</p> <p>Grants persons aggrieved by the action of any executive branch officer or employee the right to bring an action against the United States to seek appropriate relief, including an injunction against enforcement of any Act of Congress, presidential directive, adjudicative decision, rule, or regulation that is noncompliant with this Act.</p>]]></text>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-07-08T18:31:42Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <updateDate>2015-06-15T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <title>Write the Laws Act</title>
    <laws />
    <cosponsors />
    <billType>S</billType>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <recordedVotes />
    <relatedBills />
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-06-15</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2015-06-15</actionDate>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <notes />
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2015-06-15</actionDate>
      <links />
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <introducedDate>2015-06-15</introducedDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Paul, Rand [R-KY]</fullName>
        <firstName>Rand</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2082</lisID>
          <gpoId>8308</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>P000603</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>P000603</bioguideId>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>KY</state>
        <lastName>Paul</lastName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional-executive branch relations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Constitution and constitutional amendments</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Legislative rules and procedure</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <committeeReports />
    <amendments />
    <createDate>2015-06-16T09:28:42Z</createDate>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Write the Laws Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to end the unconstitutional delegation of legislative power which was exclusively vested in the Senate and House of Representatives by article I, section 1 of the Constitution of the United States, and to direct the Comptroller General of the United States to issue a report to Congress detailing the extent of the problem of unconstitutional delegation to the end that such delegations can be phased out, thereby restoring the constitutional principle of separation of powers set forth in the first sections of the Constitution of the United States.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Write the Laws Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

