<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <committeeReports />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2015-05-14T21:17:07Z</date>
              <name>Hearings by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2015-02-09T20:52:50Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <subcommittees />
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <createDate>2015-02-10T05:11:54Z</createDate>
    <amendments />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Energy</name>
    </policyArea>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Barrasso, John [R-WY]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <bioguideId>B001261</bioguideId>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8300</gpoId>
          <lisID>1881</lisID>
          <bioguideId>B001261</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <lastName>Barrasso</lastName>
        <middleName />
        <byRequestType />
        <party>R</party>
        <state>WY</state>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Energy</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Indian lands and resources rights</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Land use and conservation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Oil and gas</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Pipelines</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <notes />
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Heitkamp, Heidi [D-ND]</fullName>
        <lastName>Heitkamp</lastName>
        <bioguideId>H001069</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <state>ND</state>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>Heidi</firstName>
        <party>D</party>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2174</lisID>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>H001069</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-02-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
      </item>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Enzi, Michael B. [R-WY]</fullName>
        <lastName>ENZI</lastName>
        <bioguideId>E000285</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <state>WY</state>
        <middleName>B.</middleName>
        <firstName>MICHAEL</firstName>
        <party>R</party>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1542</lisID>
          <gpoId>8328</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>E000285</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-02-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
      </item>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Hoeven, John [R-ND]</fullName>
        <lastName>Hoeven</lastName>
        <bioguideId>H001061</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <state>ND</state>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <party>R</party>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2079</lisID>
          <gpoId>8331</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>H001061</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-02-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <title>Natural Gas Gathering Enhancement Act</title>
    <billNumber>411</billNumber>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <title>Natural Gas Gathering Enhancement Act</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to authorize the approval of natural gas pipelines and establish deadlines and expedite permits for certain natural gas gathering lines on Federal land and Indian land.</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Natural Gas Gathering Enhancement Act</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Natural Gas Gathering Enhancement Act</b></p> <p> Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to grant a right of way for natural gas pipelines through a unit of the National Park System for a maximum term of 30 years, and a maximum width of 50 feet. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to permit the use of rights of way for natural gas pipelines through public lands, forest, and other reservations of the United States, and specified national parks in California. </p> <p>Defines &quot;gas gathering line and associated field compression unit&quot; as: (1) a pipeline installed to transport natural gas production associated with one or more wells drilled and completed to produce oil or gas; and (2) if necessary, a compressor to raise the pressure of that transported natural gas to higher pressures suitable to enable the gas to flow into pipelines and other facilities.</p> <p>Excludes from such definition any pipeline or compression unit installed to transport natural gas from a processing plant to a common carrier pipeline or facility. </p> <p>Excludes from federal lands, for purposes of gas gathering line and associated field compression units, any unit of the National Park System, any unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System, a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System, or Indian land.</p> <p>Deems the issuance of a sundry notice or right-of-way for a gas gathering line and associated field compression unit located on federal or Indian land and servicing an oil well to be an action categorically excluded for purposes of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA), if the line and the compression unit are: (1) within a field or unit for which an approved land use plan or an environmental document prepared pursuant to NEPA analyzed transportation of natural gas produced from one or more oil wells in that field or unit as a reasonably foreseeable activity, and (2) located adjacent to or within an existing disturbed area or an existing corridor for a right-of-way.</p> <p>(A &quot;categorical exclusion&quot; is a category of actions which do not individually or cumulatively have a significant effect on the human environment and which have been found to have no such effect in procedures adopted by a federal agency in implementing environmental regulations and for which, therefore, neither an environmental assessment nor an environmental impact statement is required.) <p>Applies this categorical exclusion to Indian land if the Indian tribe with jurisdiction over the land requests in writing that the exclusion apply. </p> <p>Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to direct the Secretary to study permissible actions or proposed changes to federal law which would expedite permitting for gas gathering lines and associated field compression units located on federal land or Indian land to transport natural gas associated with oil and gas production on any land, to a processing plant or a common carrier pipeline for delivery to markets.</p> <p>Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to direct the appropriate agency head to issue a sundry notice or right-of-way for a gas gathering line and associated field compression unit located on federal land within 90 days after receiving the request for a line and compression unit described in this Act, unless the Secretary or agency head finds that the sundry notice or right-of-way would violate either the National Historic Preservation Act or the Endangered Species Act of 1973.</p>]]></text>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-03-03T16:52:24Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <updateDate>2015-02-09T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDate>2015-02-09</actionDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestTitle>Natural Gas Gathering Enhancement Act</latestTitle>
        <type>HR</type>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <number>1616</number>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
          <actionDate>2015-04-08</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <recordedVotes />
    <introducedDate>2015-02-09</introducedDate>
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2015-05-14</actionDate>
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <hearingsHeld>1</hearingsHeld>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>3</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-05-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-02-09</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-02-09</actionDate>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <laws />
    <updateDate>2016-11-02T23:20:11Z</updateDate>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

