<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to direct the Secretary of the Army to provide for modification of certain Federal water resources development projects on the Apalachicola, Chattahoochee, and Flint Rivers, and for other purposes.</title>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to direct the Secretary of the Army to provide for modification of certain Federal water resources development projects on the Apalachicola, Chattahoochee, and Flint Rivers, and for other purposes.</title>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <notes />
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <actionDate>2017-02-15</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees />
          <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
          <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2017-02-15T21:42:48Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-02-15</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
          <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-02-15</actionDate>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Water Resources Development</name>
    </policyArea>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Nelson, Bill [D-FL]</fullName>
        <party>D</party>
        <bioguideId>N000032</bioguideId>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>859</lisID>
          <gpoId>8236</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>N000032</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <lastName>NELSON</lastName>
        <byRequestType />
        <middleName>WILLIAM</middleName>
        <firstName>CLARENCE</firstName>
        <state>FL</state>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <recordedVotes />
    <updateDate>2018-08-28T20:23:54Z</updateDate>
    <billNumber>398</billNumber>
    <title>A bill to direct the Secretary of the Army to provide for modification of certain Federal water resources development projects on the Apalachicola, Chattahoochee, and Flint Rivers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <relatedBills />
    <amendments />
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <laws />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <billType>S</billType>
    <createDate>2017-02-16T08:49:56Z</createDate>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2017-02-15T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDate>2017-02-15</actionDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2017-08-18T18:52:51Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>This bill directs the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to operate the federal water resources projects on the Apalachicola, Chattahoochee, and Flint Rivers in Alabama, Florida, and Georgia in a manner that ensures the maintenance of freshwater flows.</p> <p>The term "freshwater flows" is defined as the quality, quantity, timing, and variability of freshwater flows required to: (1) support and reestablish the ecological integrity of the rivers, commercial and recreational fisheries dependent on freshwater flows into Apalachicola Bay and adjacent waters, and thriving and diverse fish, wildlife, and plant populations similar to those found prior to construction of the projects; (2) restore and recover species that are endangered, threatened, or at risk; and (3) prevent significantly harmful adverse impacts to the Chattahoochee and Apalachicola River ecosystems.</p> <p>The Corps of Engineers must enter into an arrangement for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to conduct a study that evaluates existing data related to freshwater flows and provides recommendations on how to maintain such flows. </p> <p>The Corps shall not issue a final water control manual based on the final environmental impact statement titled &quot;Update of the Water Control Manual for the Apalachicola-Chattahoochee-Flint River Basin in Alabama, Florida, and Georgia and a Water Supply Storage Assessment,&quot; dated December 2016, but shall: (1) issue revised water control manuals for such projects that ensure the maintenance of freshwater flows, considering the findings of NOAA's study; (2) ensure that operational modifications needed to maintain freshwater flows are achieved while providing system-wide balance in conservation storage through the maintenance of water levels in the same action zone for each of the project reservoirs; (3) enter into an arrangement for the National Academy of Sciences to carry out an independent peer review of each revised manual; and (4) obtain written approval from the Environmental Protection Agency, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, NOAA, and the U.S. Geological Survey of each manual developed before a final manual may be issued.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <committeeReports />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <cosponsors />
    <introducedDate>2017-02-15</introducedDate>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Alabama</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Aquatic ecology</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Endangered and threatened species</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Florida</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Georgia</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Hunting and fishing</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Lakes and rivers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water storage</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water use and supply</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Wildlife conservation and habitat protection</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Water Resources Development</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

