<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:28:53Z</updateDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>Schatz</lastName>
        <firstName>Brian</firstName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>S001194</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2173</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>S001194</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <fullName>Sen. Schatz, Brian [D-HI]</fullName>
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <createDate>2014-02-13T07:00:56Z</createDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Advisory bodies</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Commerce</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Education programs funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Higher education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Marine and inland water transportation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Research administration and funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Student aid and college costs</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <introducedDate>2014-02-12</introducedDate>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 113-279</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees />
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Reported by</name>
              <date>2014-12-01T21:34:58Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Markup by</name>
              <date>2014-07-23T18:30:00Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-02-12T22:31:22Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <title>S. 2030, National Sea Grant College Program Amendments Act of 2014</title>
        <pubDate>2014-08-08T18:52:00Z</pubDate>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/45638</url>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>S. 2030, National Sea Grant College Program Amendments Act of 2014</title>
        <pubDate>2014-08-08T18:52:00Z</pubDate>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/45638</url>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <amendments />
    <title>National Sea Grant College Program Amendments Act of 2014</title>
    <notes />
    <billNumber>2030</billNumber>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <middleName>F.</middleName>
        <firstName>ROGER</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. Wicker, Roger F. [R-MS]</fullName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-02-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>W000437</bioguideId>
        <lastName>WICKER</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1226</lisID>
          <bioguideId>W000437</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8263</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>MARIA</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. Cantwell, Maria [D-WA]</fullName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-07-21</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>C000127</bioguideId>
        <lastName>CANTWELL</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8288</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>C000127</bioguideId>
          <lisID>172</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <number>0607</number>
        <calendar>Senate Calendar of Business</calendar>
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <actionDate>2014-02-12</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2014-02-12T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-03-21T19:39:05Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>National Sea Grant College Program Amendments Act of 2014 - Reauthorizes the National Sea Grant College Program Act with specified appropriations through FY2020.</p> <p>Removes a requirement that the Secretary of Commerce report annually to Congress regarding efforts and progress made by colleges, universities, institutions, associations, and alliances to become designated as sea grant colleges or institutes.</p> <p>Requires (currently, allows) the Secretary to award marine policy fellowships to support the placement of individuals at the graduate level of education (in fields related to ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources) in positions with the executive and legislative branches of the federal government.</p> <p>Repeals a requirement under the National Sea Grant College Program Act Amendments of 2002 that the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere and the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) submit an annual report to Congress regarding the coordination of research activities by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) and NSF.</p> <p>Requires the National Sea Grant Advisory Board to report to Congress every three years (currently, every two years) on the progress made toward meeting priorities under the Secretary's strategic plan. </p> <p>Authorizes additional FY2015-FY2020 appropriations designated specifically for competitive grants relating to: (1) university research on aquatic non-native species, oyster diseases, algal blooms, and specified regional or national priority issues; and (2) fishery extension activities conducted by sea grant colleges or institutes to enhance existing core program funding.</p> <p>Requires the Director of the Program to use authority available for the temporary assignment of personnel between federal, state, and local governments and other organizations to meet any critical staffing requirement while implementing authorized activities. Exempts costs associated with the exercise of such authority from limitations on the amount that may be used for administration of programs in a fiscal year.</p>]]></text>
        </item>
        <item>
          <actionDesc>Reported to Senate amended</actionDesc>
          <actionDate>2014-12-01</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2014-12-01T12:51:30Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>01</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-03-25T21:34:02Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Reported to Senate amended</name>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>National Sea Grant College Program Amendments Act of 2014 - Reauthorizes the National Sea Grant College Program Act through FY2020.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) Removes a requirement that Department of Commerce report annually on efforts and progress made by colleges, universities, institutions, associations, and alliances to become designated as sea grant colleges or institutes.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) Changes from discretionary to mandatory the authority of Commerce to award Dean John A. Knauss Marine Policy Fellowships to support the placement of individuals at the graduate level of education (in fields related to ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources) in positions with the executive and legislative branches of the federal government.</p> <p>Grants first priority to placement of those legislative fellows in offices or committees of Congress that have jurisdiction over the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), and second priority to placement in offices of Members of Congress that have a demonstrated interest in ocean, coastal, or Great Lakes resources. Requires Commerce to ensure that placements are equitably distributed among political parties.</p> <p>Urges the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere to encourage participating federal agencies to consider opportunities for fellowship awardees at the conclusion of their fellowship for workforce positions appropriate for their education and experience<em>.</em></p> <p>(Sec. 5) Requires Commerce to establish priorities for the use of donations of money and voluntary, uncompensated services for the National Sea Grant Program. Directs the National Sea Grant Office to recommend the optimal use of the donations.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) Repeals a reporting requirement under the National Sea Grant College Program Act Amendments of 2002 regarding the coordination of research activities by NOAA and the National Science Foundation.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) Requires the National Sea Grant Advisory Board to report to Congress every three years (currently, every two years) on the progress made toward meeting priorities under the Secretary's strategic plan. </p> <p>(Sec. 9) Authorizes additional FY2015-FY2020 appropriations designated specifically for competitive grants relating to: (1) university research on aquatic non-native species, oyster diseases, oyster restoration, oyster-related human health risks, harmful algal blooms, coastal resilience and U.S. working waterfronts and other specified regional or national priority issues, and sustainable aquaculture techniques and technologies; and (2) fishery extension activities conducted by sea grant colleges or institutes to enhance existing core program funding.</p> <p>Requires the Program to use authority available for the temporary assignment of personnel between federal, state, and local governments and other organizations to meet any critical staffing requirement while implementing authorized activities. Exempts costs associated with the exercise of such authority from limitations on the amount that may be used for administration of programs in a fiscal year.</p>]]></text>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>National Sea Grant College Program Amendments Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles Senate</parentTitleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>National Sea Grant College Program Amendments Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to reauthorize and amend the National Sea Grant College Program Act, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>National Sea Grant College Program Amendments Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 607.</text>
      <actionDate>2014-12-01</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-01</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 607.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-01</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>report No. 113-279</name>
            <url>/congressional-report/113th-congress/senate-report/279</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-279.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2014-12-01</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>report No. 113-279</name>
            <url>/congressional-report/113th-congress/senate-report/279</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-279.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-07-23</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-02-12</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2014-02-12</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>6</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>1</placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <orderedReported>1</orderedReported>
        <reportedToSenate>2</reportedToSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <laws />
    <recordedVotes />
    <billType>S</billType>
    <relatedBills />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

