<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:28:41Z</updateDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>ROCKEFELLER</lastName>
        <firstName>JAY</firstName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>R000361</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1424</lisID>
          <gpoId>8273</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>R000361</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <fullName>Sen. Rockefeller, John D., IV [D-WV]</fullName>
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <createDate>2014-02-04T07:02:02Z</createDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Health</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Child health</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health care costs and insurance</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health care coverage and access</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health care quality</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Medicaid</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Performance measurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Poverty and welfare assistance</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <introducedDate>2014-02-03</introducedDate>
    <committeeReports />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <name>Finance Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-02-03T20:32:31Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <amendments />
    <title>Medicaid and CHIP Continuous Quality Act of 2014</title>
    <notes />
    <billNumber>1980</billNumber>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000944</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Brown, Sherrod [D-OH]</fullName>
        <lastName>BROWN</lastName>
        <firstName>SHERROD</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-02-27</sponsorshipDate>
        <middleName />
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>B000944</bioguideId>
          <lisID>136</lisID>
          <gpoId>8309</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <congress>113</congress>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Medicaid and CHIP Continuous Quality Act of 2014 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require a state Medicaid plan to provide 12-month continuous enrollment for an eligible individual, regardless of age.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) <ea> to: (1) identify methods that promote the retention of individuals who are enrolled under the state plan and remain eligible for medical assistance beyond the 12-month period, (2) actively promote the adoption of such enrollment retention methods by states, (3) publish the procedures that states are expected to use to provide annual enrollment and retention reports, and (4) publish annually enrollment and retention performance results for all states.</p> <p>Amends SSA title XXI (State Children's Health Insurance) (CHIP) to: (1) require a state CHIP plan also to provide 12-month continuous enrollment for an eligible individual, (2) prohibit eligibility standards from applying a waiting period for a targeted low-income child (including a child provided dental-only supplemental coverage), and (3) extend the authorization of CHIP performance bonuses through FY2015.</p> <p>Amends SSA title XIX to allow a state to qualify for performance bonuses for the enrollment and retention in Medicaid of certain low-income individuals.</p> <p>Requires a state to develop and implement a quality assessment and improvement strategy if it provides contracts with comparable primary care case management services providers as well as health care services furnished in fee-for-service settings.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to require states to use certain adult health quality measures and approaches to report on the initial core set of quality measures for Medicaid eligible adults and for the quality of pediatric health care.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) a Medicaid Quality Performance Bonus fund for awarding performance bonuses to select states for high attainment and improvement on a core set of quality measures related to the goals and purposes of the Medicaid program, as well as (2) a methodology for awarding Medicaid Quality Performance bonuses to states</p> <p>Requires a state, as a condition of receiving a bonus fund award, to designate at least 75% of the performance bonus funds for the development and operation of quality-related initiatives that will directly benefit providers. </p>]]></text>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-02-24T20:53:42Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <actionDate>2014-02-03</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2014-02-03T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Medicaid and CHIP Continuous Quality Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>A bill to amend titles XIX and XXI of the Social Security Act to provide for 12-month continuous enrollment under the Medicaid program and Children's Health Insurance Program and to promote quality care.</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Medicaid and CHIP Continuous Quality Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <actionDate>2014-02-03</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-02-03</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
          <name>Finance Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2014-02-03</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <laws />
    <recordedVotes />
    <billType>S</billType>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <number>1698</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-04-26</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>Stabilize Medicaid and CHIP Coverage Act</latestTitle>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

