<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <introducedDate>2016-12-09</introducedDate>
    <committeeReports />
    <laws />
    <createDate>2016-12-12T07:48:21Z</createDate>
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-12-09</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssbk00</systemCode>
          <name>Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <actionDate>2016-12-09</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <recordedVotes />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>2231</number>
        <latestTitle>Public Housing Tenant Protection and Reinvestment Act of 2015</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-05-01</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <type>HR</type>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <cosponsors />
    <billNumber>3537</billNumber>
    <amendments />
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects />
        <policyArea>
          <name>Housing and Community Development</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NJ</state>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>M000639</bioguideId>
        <lastName>MENENDEZ</lastName>
        <firstName>ROBERT</firstName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>M000639</bioguideId>
          <lisID>791</lisID>
          <gpoId>8239</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <fullName>Sen. Menendez, Robert [D-NJ]</fullName>
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <title>Choice Neighborhoods Initiative Act of 2016</title>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Housing and Community Development</name>
    </policyArea>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <actionDate>2016-12-09</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <actionDate>2016-12-09</actionDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2017-01-03T18:34:17Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <updateDate>2016-12-09T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Choice Neighborhoods Initiative Act of 2016</b></p> <p> This bill authorizes the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to make competitive grants to local governments, public housing agencies (PHAs), community development corporations, assisted housing owners, and other for-profit and nonprofit entities to implement transformational programs in eligible neighborhoods with a concentration of extreme poverty, severely distressed housing, and a potential for long-term viability, once certain key problems are addressed.</p> <p>The programs shall include neighborhoods with proximity to educational institutions, medical centers, central business districts, major employers, effective transportation alternatives (including public transit, walking, and bicycling), and low poverty neighborhoods.</p> <p>The bill requires grant applications to include a transformation plan that will demonstrate how a distressed neighborhood can be transformed into a mixed-income neighborhood with high-quality, safe, affordable housing, economic opportunities, access to jobs and public transportation, and effective education programs. </p> <p>Such grants: (1) may not be used for construction or rehabilitation of a K-12 school building or an institution of higher education, and (2) are limited for certain non-housing activities and supportive services. HUD may waive these limitations.</p> <p>The bill exempts from specified requirements of the United States Housing Act of 1937 the demolition and disposition of severely distressed public and assisted housing pursuant to a transformation plan.</p>]]></text>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <notes />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <name>Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Committee</name>
          <systemCode>ssbk00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2016-12-09T15:43:05Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <updateDate>2017-01-11T20:18:03Z</updateDate>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <title>Choice Neighborhoods Initiative Act of 2016</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to authorize the Department of Housing and Urban Development to transform neighborhoods of extreme poverty into sustainable, mixed-income neighborhoods with access to economic opportunities, by revitalizing severely distressed housing, and investing and leveraging investments in well-functioning services, educational opportunities, public assets, public transportation, and improved access to jobs.</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Choice Neighborhoods Initiative Act of 2016</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
    </titles>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

