<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <updateDate>2016-11-30T10:13:00Z</updateDate>
    <laws />
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Carper, Thomas R. [D-DE]</fullName>
        <bioguideId>C000174</bioguideId>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8283</gpoId>
          <lisID>179</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C000174</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <byRequestType />
        <lastName>CARPER</lastName>
        <firstName>THOMAS</firstName>
        <state>DE</state>
        <party>D</party>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <title>Federal Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2016</title>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles Senate</parentTitleType>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Federal Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>A bill to improve Federal network security and authorize and enhance an existing intrusion detection and prevention system for civilian Federal networks.</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Federal Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2016</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <updateDate>2015-07-27T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-08-24T21:36:52Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2015-07-27</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Federal Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), in coordination with the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), to implement an intrusion assessment plan to identify and remove intruders in federal agency information systems. </p> <p>Directs DHS to deploy and operate, for use by other agencies, capabilities to detect and prevent or remove cybersecurity risks in network traffic transiting or traveling to or from agency information systems. Authorizes the DHS Secretary to access, and agency heads to disclose to the Secretary, information transiting agency systems, regardless of the location from which the information is accessed, notwithstanding any laws that would otherwise restrict or prevent such disclosures. Requires agencies to utilize such capabilities and adopt subsequent improvements.</p> <p>Provides liability protections to private entities authorized to assist the Secretary with such capabilities.</p> <p> Terminates authority for such capabilities seven years after enactment of this Act. </p> <p>Requires DHS to include in the Continuous Diagnostics and Mitigation Program advanced network security tools to improve visibility of network activity to detect and mitigate intrusions and anomalous activity. Directs the OMB to implement a plan to ensure that agencies utilize such advanced tools. </p> <p>Directs DHS to collaborate with the OMB to update government information security metrics to include measures of intrusion and incident detection and response times. Requires the OMB to display additional agency metrics on federal government performance websites. </p> <p>Authorizes DHS, upon an agency's request, to operate and maintain technology that is deployed to agencies to diagnose and mitigate against cyber threats and vulnerabilities.</p> <p>Requires agencies to: (1) encrypt sensitive and mission critical data, (2) implement single sign-on trusted identity platforms for public websites, and (3) implement multifactor authentication standards for remote access to agency systems. </p> <p>Excludes the Department of Defense and the intelligence community from procedures of this Act.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Reported to Senate amended</name>
          <updateDate>2016-11-17T15:41:27Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-11-23T21:31:30Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Federal Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of </b> <b>2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to coordinate with the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to implement an intrusion assessment plan to identify and remove intruders in federal agency information systems. </p> <p>DHS must deploy and operate, for use by other agencies, capabilities to detect and prevent or remove cybersecurity risks in network traffic transiting or traveling to or from agency information systems. DHS may access, and agencies may disclose to DHS, information transiting agency systems, regardless of the location from which the information is accessed, notwithstanding any laws that would otherwise restrict or prevent such disclosures. Agencies must utilize such capabilities and adopt subsequent improvements.</p> <p>DHS must establish a pilot to test and deploy advanced technologies to improve detection and prevention. </p> <p>DHS must ensure that: (1) activities are reasonably necessary to protect agency information and systems from cybersecurity risks, (2) information accessed by DHS will be retained no longer than reasonably necessary, (3) notice has been provided to users of agency information systems concerning access to their communications, and (4) activities are implemented pursuant to policies governing the operation of the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities. </p> <p>Liability protections are provided to private entities authorized to assist DHS with such capabilities. But such liability protections shall not be construed to authorize an Internet service provider to break a user agreement with a customer.</p> <p>The Department of Justice must ensure that guidelines for such capabilities are consistent with laws governing the acquisition, interception, retention, use, and disclosure of communications.</p> <p>The OMB and DHS must update government-wide policies and brief Congress regarding the prioritization and use of network security monitoring tools within agency networks.</p> <p>The Department of Defense and the intelligence community are exempt from this bill's procedures. </p><p>(Sec. 4) DHS must include in the Continuous Diagnostics and Mitigation Program advanced network security tools to improve visibility of network activity to detect and mitigate intrusions and anomalous activity. The OMB must implement a plan to ensure that agencies utilize such advanced tools. </p> <p>DHS must collaborate with the OMB to update government information security metrics to include measures of intrusion and incident detection and response times. The OMB must display additional agency metrics on federal government performance websites. </p> <p>Upon an agency's request, DHS may operate and maintain technology that is deployed to agencies to diagnose and mitigate against cyber threats and vulnerabilities.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) DHS must require implementation of best practices for securing agency information systems against intrusion and preventing data exfiltration in the event of an intrusion. Agencies must: (1) identify their stored sensitive and mission critical data, (2) assess data access controls, (3) encrypt data consistent with federal information system standards, (4) implement a single sign-on trusted identity platform for individuals accessing each public website of the agency that requires user authentication, and (5) implement multifactor authentication for remote access to agency systems and for user accounts with elevated privileges.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) The Government Accountability Office must report on the effectiveness of the federal government's strategy to secure agency information systems. On an annual basis: (1) DHS must report on the implementation status of intrusion detection and prevention capabilities, and (2) the OMB must report on agency application of such capabilities.</p> <p>The OMB must submit updated intrusion assessment plans to Congress and report annually on intrusion assessment findings, advanced network security tools, and agency compliance.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) The authority for operating such federal intrusion detection and prevention capabilities terminates seven years after enactment of this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 8) The Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI) must submit to Congress an assessment of: (1) the risks that would result from the breach of unclassified information systems that provide access to information that, when combined with other unclassified information, may comprise classified information; and (2) the cost and impact on the mission carried out by each agency if such systems were subsequently classified.</p> <p>(Sec. 9) DHS and the ODNI must coordinate with agencies to conduct an ongoing damage and risk assessment relating to data breaches at the Office of Personnel Management (OPM). The ODNI must report on: (1) the extent to which federal data was compromised, exfiltrated, or manipulated by the same entity that caused the OPM data breach; (2) national security impacts; and (3) whether information accessed through the breach has been released or deployed.</p> <p>(Sec. 10) DHS may issue an emergency directive to an agency to take any lawful action regarding the operation of the agency's information system (including systems owned or operated by another entity on behalf of an agency) in response to a known or reasonably suspected information security threat, vulnerability, or incident that represents a substantial threat to information security. DHS must report annually to Congress regarding specific actions taken pursuant to such directives. </p> <p>If DHS determines that there is an imminent threat for which a directive is unlikely to result in a timely response, DHS may authorize the use of protective capabilities under DHS control for communications or system traffic transiting to or from, or stored on, an agency information system without prior consultation with the affected agency. But DHS must immediately notify the OMB, each affected agency, and Congress of the use of such imminent threat authority and the reasons for, and duration of, the action. </p> <p>DHS may direct or authorize such lawful action or protective capability only: (1) to protect agency information from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction; or (2) to require the remediation of, or to protect against, identified information security risks for information collected or maintained by or on behalf of an agency or that portion of an information system used or operated by an agency or other organization on an agency's behalf.</p> <p>The OMB must report annually regarding specific actions it has taken to enforce agency compliance and accountability.]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Reported to Senate amended</actionDesc>
          <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 673.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <createDate>2015-07-28T14:38:42Z</createDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Computer security and identity theft</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Performance measurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Technology assessment</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <notes />
    <title>Federal Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2016</title>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <firstName>Ron</firstName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8355</gpoId>
          <lisID>2086</lisID>
          <bioguideId>J000293</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <fullName>Sen. Johnson, Ron [R-WI]</fullName>
        <party>R</party>
        <lastName>Johnson</lastName>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>J000293</bioguideId>
        <state>WI</state>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-07-27</sponsorshipDate>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <number>754</number>
        <latestTitle>Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015</latestTitle>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-10-28</actionDate>
          <actionTime>19:13:54</actionTime>
          <text>Held at the desk.</text>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
      <item>
        <number>2029</number>
        <latestTitle>Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016</latestTitle>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-12-18</actionDate>
          <text>Became Public Law No: 114-113.</text>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <calendar>Senate Calendar of Business</calendar>
        <number>0673</number>
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <billNumber>1869</billNumber>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2016-01-15T22:25:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1869, Federal Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/51147</url>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 673.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/senate-report/378</url>
            <name>report No. 114-378</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with amendments. With written report No. 114-378.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/senate-report/378</url>
            <name>report No. 114-378</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with amendments. With written report No. 114-378.</text>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-07-29</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-07-27</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2015-07-27</actionDate>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>6</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>1</placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>
        <orderedReported>1</orderedReported>
        <reportedToSenate>2</reportedToSenate>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Reported by</name>
              <date>2016-11-17T20:46:20Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Markup by</name>
              <date>2015-07-29T15:08:34Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2015-07-27T20:06:26Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <recordedVotes />
    <introducedDate>2015-07-27</introducedDate>
    <amendments />
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 114-378</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

