<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2015-04-28</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <amendments />
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestTitle>TRACK Act</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
          <actionDate>2015-04-29</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <number>2074</number>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <type>HR</type>
        <congress>114</congress>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <billNumber>1114</billNumber>
    <updateDate>2016-11-02T23:26:21Z</updateDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Menendez, Robert [D-NJ]</fullName>
        <firstName>ROBERT</firstName>
        <lastName>MENENDEZ</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>M000639</bioguideId>
          <lisID>791</lisID>
          <gpoId>8239</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>NJ</state>
        <middleName />
        <party>D</party>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>M000639</bioguideId>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <notes />
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Accidents</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Transportation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Emergency communications systems</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Emergency planning and evacuation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Environmental health</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>First responders and emergency personnel</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Hazardous wastes and toxic substances</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Medical tests and diagnostic methods</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Railroads</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Transportation employees</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Transportation safety and security</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2015-04-28T19:31:23Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <cosponsors />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <committeeReports />
    <congress>114</congress>
    <title>TRACK Act</title>
    <introducedDate>2015-04-28</introducedDate>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-04-28</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-04-28</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2015-04-28</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-05-13T19:02:28Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2015-04-28T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Toxics by Rail Accountability and Community Knowledge Act of 2015 or the TRACK Act</b></p> <p> Requires railroad carriers found at fault for an unintended release of hazardous materials (hazmat) due to a railroad accident or incident during calendar year 2010 to: </p> <ul> <li>review periodically any post-accident public health assessments of hazmat-exposed individuals who could experience long-lasting or irreversible health effects;</li> <li>inform those individuals in a timely manner of any health information, including information on long-lasting or irreversible health consequences; and </li> <li>offer to renegotiate any legal settlements made to affected individuals in which additional information about potential for such consequences has been later disclosed in a post-accident public health assessment.</li> </ul> <p>Directs the Secretary of Transportation to prescribe regulations:</p> <ul> <li> requiring railroad carriers transporting hazmat to give first responders, emergency response officials, and law enforcement personnel accurate and current commodity flow data and assist with the development of emergency operations and hazmat response plans for railroad accidents or incidents; and</li> <li>establishing a procedure for railroad carriers to permit a train to pass a red signal at a moveable bridge.</li> </ul> <p>Requires the Secretary, in collaboration with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the American Short Line and Regional Railroad Association, to develop route safety and security risk assessment tools for short line and regional railroad carriers.</p> <p>Revises the railroad safety risk reduction program by requiring railroad carriers to develop a comprehensive program to improve safety by reducing the number and rates of accidents, incidents, injuries, and fatalities (as under current law) through the use of safety management systems and their associated key principles, analysis of operational incidents and accidents, and continuous evaluation and improvement programs.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to prescribe regulations requiring railroad carriers transporting hazmat to:</p> <ul> <li>give first responders, emergency response officials, and law enforcement personnel real-time information regarding hazmat on the train in the event of an incident, accident, or emergency; and</li> <li>develop a public education program for communities along railroad hazmat routes.</li> </ul> <p>Prescribes certain civil penalties for any railroad carrier that violates a requirement or regulation under this Act.</p>]]></text>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <laws />
    <createDate>2015-04-29T08:46:13Z</createDate>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>TRACK Act</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Toxics by Rail Accountability and Community Knowledge Act of 2015</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>A bill to enhance rail safety and provide for the safe transport of hazardous materials, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>TRACK Act</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <recordedVotes />
    <billType>S</billType>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

