<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <notes />
    <committeeReports />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>Protecting Veterans Credit Act of 2016</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>A bill to amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act and the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to delay the inclusion in consumer credit reports and to establish requirements for debt collectors with respect to medical debt information of veterans due to inappropriate or delayed billing payments or reimbursements from the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>Protecting Veterans Credit Act of 2016</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Protecting Veterans Credit Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to exclude from a consumer report: (1) for one year, information related to a veteran's medical debt resulting from hospital or medical services provided in a non-Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) facility; and (2) information related to a fully paid or settled medical debt that had been characterized as delinquent, charged off, or in collection. </p> <p> A veteran may submit a notice along with proof of VA liability for such debt to a consumer reporting agency or a reseller to dispute the debt's inclusion in a consumer report. The consumer reporting agency shall, within 30 days, delete such information from the consumer's file and notify the furnisher and the veteran.</p> <p> The Consumer Credit Protection Act is amended to provide a mechanism for veterans to dispute the inclusion of program debt already on a credit report. A consumer reporting agency shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of such dispute, delete such information from the veteran's file and notify the furnisher and the veteran. </strong></h3> </p> <p>Within five days after the initial communication with a veteran, a debt collector shall, unless the appropriate information is contained in the initial communication or the veteran has paid the debt, send the veteran a written notice containing specified debt-related information, including information concerning the debt amount, creditors, the insurance company involved, and the hospital or medical care provider.</p> <p>If a veteran notifies the debt collector within such one-year period that the program debt is disputed or that the veteran requests the name and address of the original creditor, the debt collector shall cease collection until debt verification or the name and address of the original creditor is obtained.</p>]]></text>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-11-09T20:45:20Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <updateDate>2016-07-14T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <createDate>2016-07-15T07:14:53Z</createDate>
    <recordedVotes />
    <billNumber>3258</billNumber>
    <introducedDate>2016-07-14</introducedDate>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-06-28</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <number>5593</number>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestTitle>Protecting Veterans Credit Act of 2016</latestTitle>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <updateDate>2016-11-15T09:52:15Z</updateDate>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2016-07-14T20:28:44Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <subcommittees />
          <systemCode>ssbk00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <laws />
    <title>Protecting Veterans Credit Act of 2016</title>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>D000607</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7941</gpoId>
          <lisID>1850</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <byRequestType />
        <fullName>Sen. Donnelly, Joe [D-IN]</fullName>
        <firstName>Joe</firstName>
        <state>IN</state>
        <bioguideId>D000607</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <party>D</party>
        <lastName>Donnelly</lastName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Committee</name>
          <systemCode>ssbk00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <amendments />
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects />
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <state>SD</state>
        <fullName>Sen. Rounds, Mike  [R-SD]</fullName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-14</sponsorshipDate>
        <middleName />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2288</lisID>
          <bioguideId>R000605</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>Mike</firstName>
        <lastName>Rounds</lastName>
        <bioguideId>R000605</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <party>R</party>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <billType>S</billType>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

