<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <updateDate>2017-01-20T09:52:43Z</updateDate>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <number>579</number>
        <latestTitle>Inspector General Empowerment Act of 2015</latestTitle>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 68.</text>
          <actionDate>2015-05-05</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
      <item>
        <number>3011</number>
        <latestTitle>Bolster Accountability to Drive Government Efficiency and Reform Washington Act of 2016</latestTitle>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 505.</text>
          <actionDate>2016-06-06</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
      <item>
        <number>6450</number>
        <latestTitle>Inspector General Empowerment Act of 2016</latestTitle>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Became Public Law No: 114-317.</text>
          <actionDate>2016-12-16</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <calendar>U00158</calendar>
        <number />
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/50304</url>
        <pubDate>2015-06-12T20:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>H.R. 2395, Inspector General Empowerment Act of 2015</title>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>H. Rept. 114-210</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001076</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <party>R</party>
        <firstName>Jason</firstName>
        <lastName>Chaffetz</lastName>
        <district>3</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Chaffetz, Jason [R-UT-3]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1956</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C001076</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8191</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>UT</state>
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-06-22</actionDate>
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2015-05-18T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Inspector General Empowerment Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to: (1) grant Inspectors General additional subpoena authority to compel the attendance and testimony of certain witnesses, including federal contractors and former federal employees necessary in the performance of the functions assigned by such Act; (2) assign the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency additional responsibilities for receiving, reviewing, and mediating any disputes involving the jurisdiction of more than one federal agency or entity; (3) set forth procedures for considering allegations of wrongdoing against the Special Counsel or Deputy Special Counsel (officials appointed to investigate prohibited personnel practices and government waste and abuse); and (4) require each Inspector General to make publicly available any administrative investigation that confirms misconduct by any member of the Senior Executive Service, an employee in an excepted position, or a commissioned officer in the Armed Forces in pay grades 0-6 and above and to include in semiannual reports a list and summary of any administrative investigation that confirms such misconduct.</p> <p>Exempts from requirements relating to the authority of federal agencies to collect information for investigations: (1) information collected during any evaluation by the Federal Accountability and Spending Transparency Board; and (2) information collected during any audit, investigation, inspection, evaluation, or other review conducted by the Council or any Office of the Inspector General, including any Office of Special Inspector General. </p> <p>Requires: (1) the Government Accountability Office to study and report on prolonged vacancies in the offices of Inspector General, and (2) the Council to conduct and report on an analysis of critical issues that involve the jurisdiction of more than one Office of Inspector General.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2015-05-18</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-07-08T14:01:18Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        </item>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2015-07-16T13:26:50Z</updateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>Inspector General Empowerment Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to enhance the investigatory powers of Inspectors General.</p> <p>(Sec. 2) This section grants Inspectors General subpoena authority to compel the attendance and testimony of certain witnesses, including federal contractors and former federal employees, in investigations of fraud or waste in excess of $100,000. However, if there is reasonable cause to believe a crime has been committed, the $100,000 threshold&nbsp;shall not apply. </p> <p>Prior to issuing a subpoena, an Inspector General must submit a request for approval of a subpoena to a Subpoena Panel comprised of three Inspectors General of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency and then notify the Department of Justice (DOJ) of intent to issue&nbsp;the subpoena. DOJ retains the power to approve or deny the issuance of a subpoena.</p> <p>Inspectors General may compare, through a matching program, federal records with other federal or non-federal records, while conducting an audit or other review to identify weaknesses that may lead to waste, fraud, or abuse and to detect improper payments and fraud. This authority is not restricted by privacy protections in the Computer Matching and Privacy Protection Act of 1988. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency is charged with receiving, reviewing, and mediating any disputes involving the jurisdiction of more than one federal agency or entity. </p> <p>The Integrity Committee of the Council must make an expedited determination of whether to initiate an investigation of allegations of wrongdoing&nbsp; and must complete an investigation within six months after making such determination. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) This section exempts from Paperwork Reduction Act requirements: (1) information collected during any evaluation by the Federal Accountability and Spending Transparency Board; and (2) information collected during any audit, investigation, inspection, evaluation, or other review conducted by the Council or any Office of the Inspector General, including any Office of Special Inspector General. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) The Integrity Committee is granted the authority to investigate an allegation of wrongdoing against the Special Counsel or the Deputy Special Counsel (officials appointed to investigate prohibited personnel practices and government waste and abuse) on the same basis as an investigation of an allegation against an Inspector General. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) This section requires: (1) the Government Accountability Office to study and report on prolonged vacancies in the offices of Inspector General, and (2) the Council to conduct and report on an analysis of critical issues that involve the jurisdiction of more than one Office of Inspector General.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) This section requires the public disclosure of any finding of misconduct, including any violation of federal law or agency policy, by any member of the Senior Executive Service, an employee excepted from the competitive service, or certain commissioned officers in the U.S. Army.&nbsp;</p> <p><br /></p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2015-07-16</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Reported to House without amendment</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-09-22T19:30:43Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Reported to House without amendment</name>
          <versionCode>79</versionCode>
        </item>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2016-06-21T14:14:02Z</updateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Inspector General Empowerment Act of</strong> <b>2016</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to expand the investigatory powers of federal inspectors general.</p> <p>(Sec. 2) Inspectors general are authorized to request access to federal grand jury materials that are protected from disclosure under the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure. An inspector general must submit such a request to the head of its establishment, who then must transmit the request to the Department of Justice (DOJ). </p> <p>DOJ must grant such a request unless access to the grand jury materials would: (1) interfere with an ongoing criminal investigation, prosecution, or undercover operation; (2) identify a confidential source or protected witness; (3) pose a serious threat to national security; or (4) significantly impair the trade or economic interests of the United States. If DOJ denies such a request, it must submit a statement to Congress explaining the reason for the denial. </p> <p>The DOJ Inspector General is exempt from these request procedures and shall automatically have access to information available to DOJ regarding grand jury materials. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill grants inspectors general subpoena authority to compel the attendance and testimony of witnesses as necessary, but they may not require by subpoena the attendance and testimony of any current federal employees, though they may use other authorized procedures. </p> <p>Prior to issuing a subpoena, an inspector general must submit a request for approval of a subpoena to a Subpoena Panel comprised of three inspectors general of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency and then notify DOJ of intent to issue&nbsp;the subpoena. </p> <p>If the subpoena will interfere with an ongoing investigation, DOJ may object within 10 days after being notified of the Subpoena Panel's approval and the subpoena may not be issued. But if DOJ does not object within those 10 days, the inspector general may issue the subpoena. </p> <p>Inspectors general collecting information or performing computerized comparisons of automated federal records systems with other federal or nonfederal records while conducting an authorized audit, investigation, inspection, evaluation, or review are exempt from: (1) privacy protections that require agreements between agencies for the use of computerized matching programs to compare records under the Computer Matching and Privacy Protection Act of 1988, and (2) procedural requirements for information collections under the Paperwork Reduction Act.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency is charged with receiving, reviewing, and mediating any disputes regarding inspector general activities involving the jurisdiction of more than one federal agency or entity, except with regard to the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community. </p> <p>The Integrity Committee of the Council must make an expedited determination of whether to initiate an investigation of allegations of wrongdoing and must complete an investigation within six months after making such determination. Agencies and entities represented on the committee must provide assistance at the chairperson's request. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) The Integrity Committee is granted the authority to investigate an allegation of wrongdoing against the Special Counsel or the Deputy Special Counsel (officials appointed to investigate prohibited personnel practices and government waste and abuse) on the same basis as an investigation of an allegation against an inspector general. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) The bill requires: (1) the Government Accountability Office to study and report on prolonged vacancies in the offices of inspector general, and (2) the Council to conduct and report on an analysis of critical issues that involve the jurisdiction of more than one office of inspector general.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) The bill requires the public disclosure of any finding of misconduct, including any violation of federal law or any significant violation of agency policy, by any senior government employee.&nbsp;Inspectors general must include in their semiannual reports: (1) statistical tables showing the total numbers of issued investigative reports, persons referred to DOJ for criminal prosecution, persons referred to state or local prosecutors, and indictments resulting from such referrals; and (2) descriptions of investigations involving senior government employees where allegations of misconduct were substantiated. <br /> </p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2016-06-21</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Passed House amended</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-06-27T20:18:56Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Passed House amended</name>
          <versionCode>36</versionCode>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. CHAFFETZ:H.R. 2395.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8.[Page H3309]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <createDate>2015-05-19T09:18:40Z</createDate>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <introducedDate>2015-05-18</introducedDate>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House</titleType>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
        <title>Inspector General Empowerment Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to House</titleType>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
        <title>Inspector General Empowerment Act of 2015</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Inspector General Empowerment Act of 2015</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>To amend the Inspector General Act of 1978 to strengthen the independence of the Inspectors General, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Inspector General Empowerment Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2016-06-22T18:50:25Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2015-07-16T18:06:06Z</date>
              <name>Reported by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2015-05-19T20:18:06Z</date>
              <name>Markup by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2015-05-18T16:02:50Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <state>MD</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>7</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Cummings, Elijah E. [D-MD-7]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7982</gpoId>
          <lisID>256</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C000984</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>ELIJAH</firstName>
        <lastName>CUMMINGS</lastName>
        <bioguideId>C000984</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-05-18</sponsorshipDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <state>NC</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <district>11</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Rep. Meadows, Mark [R-NC-11]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2142</lisID>
          <bioguideId>M001187</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <lastName>Meadows</lastName>
        <bioguideId>M001187</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <middleName />
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-05-18</sponsorshipDate>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <notes />
    <amendments />
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-06-22</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-06-21</actionDate>
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <actionTime>16:58:38</actionTime>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H37300</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-06-21</actionDate>
        <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR H4002-4005)</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-162/house-section/page/H4002-4005</url>
            <name>H4002-4005</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionTime>16:58:37</actionTime>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-06-21</actionDate>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.(text: CR H4002-4005)</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-162/house-section/page/H4002-4005</url>
            <name>H4002-4005</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionTime>16:58:37</actionTime>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-06-21</actionDate>
        <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2395.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/114th-congress/house-bill/2395</url>
            <name>H.R. 2395</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionTime>16:50:19</actionTime>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-06-21</actionDate>
        <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR H4002-4006)</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-162/house-section/page/H4002-4006</url>
            <name>H4002-4006</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionTime>16:50:13</actionTime>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H30300</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-06-21</actionDate>
        <text>Mr. Meadows moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <actionTime>16:50:02</actionTime>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H12410</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-07-16</actionDate>
        <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 158.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H12200</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-07-16</actionDate>
        <text>Reported by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-210.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/house-report/210</url>
            <name>H. Rept. 114-210</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>5000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-07-16</actionDate>
        <text>Reported by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-210.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/house-report/210</url>
            <name>H. Rept. 114-210</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-05-19</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-05-19</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-05-18</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-05-18</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-05-18</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <actionStageOverride>1</actionStageOverride>
        <generalDebate>1</generalDebate>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <committeeReportOfABill>1</committeeReportOfABill>
        <reportedToHouse>1</reportedToHouse>
        <motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>1</motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>
        <considerationByHouse>1</considerationByHouse>
        <finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>1</finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <passedAgreedToInHouse>1</passedAgreedToInHouse>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <motionToReconsiderResults>1</motionToReconsiderResults>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <unionCalendarAssignment>1</unionCalendarAssignment>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>14</houseOfRepresentatives>
        <senate>1</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Evidence and witnesses</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Federal officials</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government ethics and transparency, public corruption</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <billNumber>2395</billNumber>
    <recordedVotes />
    <title>Inspector General Empowerment Act of 2016</title>
    <laws />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

