<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. MORAN:H.R. 289.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 4 of the Constitution of the UnitedStates grants Congress the authority to enact thislegislation.[Page H172]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>MORAN</lastName>
        <firstName>JAMES</firstName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>832</lisID>
          <gpoId>8199</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>M000933</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>M000933</bioguideId>
        <middleName>P.</middleName>
        <fullName>Rep. Moran, James P. [D-VA-8]</fullName>
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <createDate>2013-01-16T07:02:11Z</createDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Computer security and identity theft</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional elections</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Election Assistance Commission</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Elections, voting, political campaign regulation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Internet and video services</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Right of privacy</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local government operations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Telephone and wireless communication</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Voting rights</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <committeeReports />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <systemCode>hsha00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>House Administration Committee</name>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2013-01-15T15:00:30Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <amendments />
    <title>VOTE Act</title>
    <laws />
    <notes />
    <billNumber>289</billNumber>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <cosponsors />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <congress>113</congress>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p> Value Our Time Elections Act or VOTE Act - Amends the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (NVRA) to require each state to make available official public websites for online voter registration.</p> <p>Authorizes automated voter registration of certain individuals and establishes other initiatives to promote voter registration, such as same day registration and voter registration of individuals under 18 years of age.</p> <p>Sets forth requirements for maintenance, privacy, and security of voter registration lists, including establishing deadlines for transmittal of change of address or other identifying information.</p> <p>Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (HAVA) to direct each state to provide, according to standards issued by the Election Assistance Commission, for the minimum required number of voting systems, poll workers, and other election resources (including all other physical resources) for each voting site on the day of any federal election and on any days during which such state allows early voting for a federal election. </p> <p>Require each state to submit a written plan to the Commission describing the measures it is implementing to ensure, to the greatest extent possible, an equitable waiting time for all voters in the state and a waiting time of less than one hour at any polling place in the election. </p> <p>Requires each jurisdiction for which the Commission determines that a substantial number of voters waited more than 90 minutes to cast a vote in a federal election, or in which there were substantial violations of certain established standards, to comply with a state remedial plan established by the Commission to provide for the effective allocation of resources to administer elections in the state and to reduce voter waiting times.</p> <p>Requires provision of an emergency paper ballot to any requesting voter in the event of a failure of voting equipment or other circumstances at a polling place that causes an unreasonable delay.</p> <p>Requires each state to allow individuals to vote during the seven day period (or, at state option, a longer period) before a federal election in the same manner as voting is allowed on election day.</p> <p>Establishes minimum early voting requirements.</p> <p>Directs the Commission to issue standards for the administration of early voting.</p>]]></text>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2013-01-15</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-02-12T18:45:24Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <updateDate>2013-01-15T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>VOTE Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Value Our Time Elections Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to modernize State voting systems by allowing for increased use of the internet in voter registration, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>VOTE Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
      <actionDate>2013-01-15</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsha00</systemCode>
          <name>House Administration Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2013-01-15</actionDate>
        <links />
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2013-01-15</actionDate>
        <links />
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2013-01-15</actionDate>
        <links />
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>3</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T15:57:49Z</updateDate>
    <recordedVotes />
    <introducedDate>2013-01-15</introducedDate>
    <relatedBills />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

