<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2017-11-06T21:44:32Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-11-06</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2017-11-06</actionDate>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <recordedVotes />
    <laws />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Airline Accountability Act</title>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to promote economic security and workplace accountability for the workers of air carriers, and their subcontractors, and for other purposes.</title>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Airline Accountability Act</title>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>(Extracted from GPO) Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Airline Accountability Act</title>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>BROWN</lastName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-11-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <party>D</party>
        <fullName>Sen. Brown, Sherrod [D-OH]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>B000944</bioguideId>
          <lisID>136</lisID>
          <gpoId>8309</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>SHERROD</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <state>OH</state>
        <middleName />
        <bioguideId>B000944</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <latestAction>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2017-11-06</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <updateDate>2018-08-28T20:30:33Z</updateDate>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <billNumber>2079</billNumber>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <relatedBills />
    <title>Airline Accountability Act</title>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2018-03-23T19:05:16Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2017-11-06</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Airline Accountability Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the General Services Administration (GSA) to require an air carrier, as a condition of eligibility for a contract under the City Pair Program, to: (1) disclose to the Department of Labor, annually, whether within the preceding three-year period any administrative merits determination, arbitral award or decision, or civil judgment has been issued against the carrier or any of its subcontractors for violations of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, the National Labor Relations Act, the Davis-Bacon Act, the Service Contract Act, the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993, the Civil Rights Act of 1964, the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967, or other specified labor laws and executive orders; and (2) incorporate into each subcontract a requirement that the subcontractor disclose to the carrier any such determination, award, decision, or judgment rendered against the subcontractor within the preceding three-year period for violations of any of such laws.</p> <p>Labor shall provide an air carrier that makes such a disclosure an opportunity, annually, to report any steps taken by the carrier or any of its subcontractors to correct the violations or improve compliance. may negotiate corrective measures that the carrier or any of its subcontractors may take in order to avoid having the carrier placed on the list.</p> <p>For each year that a contract is solicited under the program, Labor shall prepare and submit to the GSA a list of air carriers that shall be ineligible for such solicitation based on serious, repeated, willful, or pervasive violations of the labor laws and the failure of such carriers or any of its subcontractors to complete a corrective measure negotiated. The GSA shall not solicit a contract under the program from any carrier on the list that applies to the year of the solicitation.</p> <p>Labor may negotiate corrective measures that a carrier or any of its subcontractors may take in order to avoid having the carrier placed on the list.</p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2017-11-06T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects />
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <committeeReports />
    <introducedDate>2017-11-06</introducedDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001288</bioguideId>
        <middleName>A.</middleName>
        <byRequestType />
        <fullName>Sen. Booker, Cory A. [D-NJ]</fullName>
        <lastName>Booker</lastName>
        <state>NJ</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2194</lisID>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>B001288</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>Cory</firstName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <notes />
    <createDate>2017-11-07T00:26:17Z</createDate>
    <amendments />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

