<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <title>Success Act</title>
    <updateDate>2016-11-02T23:20:12Z</updateDate>
    <relatedBills />
    <introducedDate>2015-02-09</introducedDate>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Education</name>
    </policyArea>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <billNumber>412</billNumber>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <amendments />
    <recordedVotes />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2015-02-09T21:25:58Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <laws />
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Academic performance and assessments</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Child care and development</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Child health</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Community life and organization</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Education of the disadvantaged</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Education programs funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Elementary and secondary education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Family relationships</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Family services</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Homelessness and emergency shelter</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Teaching, teachers, curricula</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Education</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <notes />
    <committeeReports />
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-02-09</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-02-09</actionDate>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2015-02-09</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Success Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Schools Utilizing Comprehensive and Community Engagement for Success Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to encourage and support parent, family, and community involvement in schools, to provide needed integrated services and comprehensive supports to children for the ultimate goal of assisting students to stay in school, become successful learners, improve their academic achievement, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Success Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2015-02-09</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Schools Utilizing Comprehensive and Community Engagement for Success Act or the Success Act</strong></p> <p>Amends part A of title I (Improving the Academic Achievement of the Disadvantaged) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to require local educational agencies (LEAs) to work with public and private state and local entities to provide children and families with services that are integrated with services from specialized instructional support personnel and LEA homeless liaisons to address the academic and nonacademic factors that affect student achievement.</p> <p>Amends title V (Promoting Informed Parental Choice and Innovation Programs) of the ESEA to establish a Parent and Community Outreach and Engagement program. Directs the Secretary of Education to award formula grants to states and, through them, competitive subgrants to: (1) LEAs to assist their public elementary and secondary schools to hire and maintain Parent and Community Outreach Coordinators; and (2) community-based organizations or institutions of higher education that work in partnership with public schools to connect integrated services and comprehensive supports to students and families to enhance students' social, emotional, intellectual, and physical development.</p> <p>Requires Parent and Community Outreach Coordinators to: (1) build relationships, bridge gaps, and create partnerships among school staff, families, and community members; and (2) provide support and resources to increase family and community engagement in schools.</p> <p>Requires Coordinators to be supervised and evaluated by the principal or headmaster of the school and evaluated annually by a committee composed of school personnel, parents, and at least one community partner.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to contract with a nonprofit organization that has effective and extensive experience in providing integrated student supports to: (1) provide technical assistance and training to this Act's grantees and subgrantees; and (2) establish a national clearinghouse for the collection and dissemination of information on effective parent, family, and community engagement practices and programs.</p>]]></text>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-03-04T15:47:29Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <updateDate>2015-02-09T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <createDate>2015-02-10T05:11:54Z</createDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <state>MD</state>
        <fullName>Sen. Mikulski, Barbara A. [D-MD]</fullName>
        <middleName>ANN</middleName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>M000702</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8240</gpoId>
          <lisID>802</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>BARBARA</firstName>
        <lastName>MIKULSKI</lastName>
        <bioguideId>M000702</bioguideId>
        <byRequestType />
        <party>D</party>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <state>RI</state>
        <fullName>Sen. Whitehouse, Sheldon [D-RI]</fullName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-02-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <middleName />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1823</lisID>
          <bioguideId>W000802</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8264</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>Sheldon</firstName>
        <lastName>Whitehouse</lastName>
        <bioguideId>W000802</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <party>D</party>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

