<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. SERRANO:H.R. 5377.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto Article I, Section 8, Clause 7 of the Constitution, whichstates that that ``The Congress shall have Power . . . . . Toestablish Post Offices and post roads.'' In addition, thislegislation is introduced pursuant to Article I, Section 8,Clause 18 of the Constitution, which states that Congressshall have the power ``to make all laws which shall benecessary and proper for carrying into execution theforegoing powers, and all other powers vested by thisConstitution in the government of the United States, or inany department or officer thereof''.[Page H7188]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2014-07-31</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-10-17T12:22:47Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Postal Facilities Preservation and Sales Reform Act - Revises requirements for making a determination as to the necessity for&nbsp;closing or consolidating any postal facility to require that the U.S. Postal Service (USPS): (1) hold at least three public meetings, located in the area affected by the closing or consolidation, at least 120 days prior to the determination; and (2) provide adequate notice of the closing or consolidation to persons served by such facility&nbsp;at least 180 days prior to the proposed date of such closing or consolidation. </p> <p>Prohibits USPS from entering into any contract or agreement to sell or relocate a historic postal facility until the proposed decision to sell or relocate is reviewed in accordance with requirements of the National Historic Preservation Act. </p> <p>Requires USPS to use the Historic Surplus Property Program to dispose of a historic postal facility that has been determined by the State Historic Preservation Officer or the Keeper of the National Register of Historic Places to be of national significance. Requires: (1) the Postmaster General to maintain a list of historic postal facilities and to publish such list on the USPS website, (2) the Postmaster General to maintain a separate preservation budget for such facilities, and (3) the USPS Federal Preservation Officer to notify the National Museum of American Art when New Deal art (art located at a postal facility that was commissioned by the federal government between 1933 and 1937)&nbsp;owned by USPS is loaned or relocated.</p> <p>Requires the Postmaster General to develop a model covenant to be used and applied to any historic postal facility offered for sale that: (1) requires the purchaser of such a facility to allow public access to any historic artwork located within such facility, (2) requires USPS&nbsp;to contribute sufficient funds to the maintenance of such artwork, and (3) prohibits the purchaser of the historic postal facility from demolishing or altering&nbsp;it in any way that is incompatible with its historic character. </p> <p>Nullifies the proposed rule published&nbsp;by USPS in&nbsp;the Federal Register on January 13, 2014, relating to a categorical exclusion under the National Environmental Policy Act for disposal of USPS facilities. </p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2014-07-31T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2014-07-31</actionDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-07-31T13:10:05Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <introducedDate>2014-07-31</introducedDate>
    <recordedVotes />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Postal Facilities Preservation and Sales Reform Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>To provide for certain safeguards with respect to the sale of historic postal facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Postal Facilities Preservation and Sales Reform Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000248</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Serrano, Jose E. [D-NY-15]</fullName>
        <byRequestType />
        <lastName>SERRANO</lastName>
        <firstName>JOSE</firstName>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>S000248</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1042</lisID>
          <gpoId>8077</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <laws />
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <createDate>2014-08-01T04:46:07Z</createDate>
    <notes />
    <title>Postal Facilities Preservation and Sales Reform Act</title>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <billNumber>5377</billNumber>
    <committeeReports />
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Art, artists, authorship</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government buildings, facilities, and property</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Historic sites and heritage areas</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Historical and cultural resources</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Land transfers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Postal service</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public participation and lobbying</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>U.S. Postal Service</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <relatedBills />
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:16:06Z</updateDate>
    <amendments />
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>3</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <committee>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
        <actionDate>2014-07-31</actionDate>
        <links />
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <actionDate>2014-07-31</actionDate>
        <links />
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <actionDate>2014-07-31</actionDate>
        <links />
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000551</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Lee, Barbara [D-CA-13]</fullName>
        <lastName>LEE</lastName>
        <firstName>BARBARA</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-07-31</sponsorshipDate>
        <middleName />
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>L000551</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1501</lisID>
          <gpoId>7814</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

